<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='2'>Chapter 11A DISCRIMINATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. HOUSING</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>11A-18.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Required notices in connection with application to purchase or rent a dwelling.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002420</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>Within fifteen (15) days after receipt of any incomplete or incorrectly completed application (or amended application) to purchase or rent a dwelling, the condominium association, homeowners' association, or cooperative association shall provide the applicant with written notice specifically identifying any and all items in the application that need to be completed or corrected.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Within forty-five (45) days after receipt of a correctly completed application, the condominium association, homeowners' association, or cooperative association shall either reject or approve the application and shall provide the applicant with written notice of same. If the application is rejected, the written notice must state with specificity each reason for the rejection.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the condominium association, homeowners' association, or cooperative association fails to comply with the provisions of Section 11A-18.1 (a) and (b), of this article, the Director or the Commission may send a demand letter requesting that the condominium association, homeowners' association, or cooperative association, within ten (10) days after the date of the demand letter, provide to the applicant and the Director or the Commission a written acknowledgement of application receipt, notice of approval or rejection of the application, and notice specifying each reason for the rejection (if applicable). The failure of the condominium association, homeowners' association, or cooperative association to timely comply with this provision may be considered in determining whether reasonable cause exists to believe the association's decision or action was discriminatory.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-63, ยง 1, 7-1-14)</history></law>