<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='2'>Chapter 17 HOUSING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='3'>ARTICLE XI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY AFFORDABLE HOUSING SET ASIDE INCENTIVE FOR DISABLED HOUSEHOLDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>17-157</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002805</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>Disabled Household means any moderate, low, very low (as these terms are defined in Section 420.9071 of the Florida Statutes) or extremely low income household (as this term is defined in [Section] 17-131 of the Code of Miami-Dade County) that has one or more persons who (a) have a physical impairment or mental impairment that substantially limits one or more major life; (b) have a record of such impairment; or (c) are regarded as having such an impairment in accordance with the Federal Fair Housing Act (42 U.S.C. ยง 3601 et seq., State of Florida Fair Housing Act (ยง 760.20, et seq.) and Chapter 11A of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Rental Housing Project or Homeownership Project means a housing development that has been funded through the County's Surtax, State Housing Initiatives Partnership (SHIP), Home Investment Partnerships Program (HOME), Community Development Block Grant (CDBG), or other affordable housing program.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Set aside unit means a rental housing unit or homeownership unit which meets or exceeds the accessibility requirements of the Fair Housing Act and other applicable laws and regulations and which is affordable to a Disabled Household. A set aside unit also includes those rental housing units or homeownership units which are rented or sold to a Disabled Household, which includes one or more persons with a mental impairment or other non-mobility disability.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-56, ยง 1, 6-3-14)</history></law>