<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00097' order_by='00097' level='3'>ARTICLE LXXIX. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY ASIAN-AMERICAN ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1088</section_number>
<catch_line>Membership; officers; meetings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000791</order_by>
<text><section>The members of the board shall elect a chairperson, vice-chairperson, and such other additional offices as the Asian-American Advisory Board shall deem necessary. All officers shall serve one-year terms at the will of the board. No member shall remain in the same office for more than two (2) consecutive years. After one (1) year of not holding the office, a member may be elected to the same office that was previously held for up to two (2) consecutive years. Officer elections shall take place each November, with newly elected officers installed the following January.</section><section>A majority of members duly appointed to the board shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. Members shall serve without compensation. The chairperson or vice-chairperson may call meetings of the board. Meetings may also be called by written notice and signed by fourteen (14) members. The board at any duly noticed public meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. All meetings shall be public.</section><section>Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, a board member shall be automatically removed if, in a given County fiscal year; the member is absent from two (2) consecutive meetings without an acceptable excuse or the member is absent from three (3) of the board's meetings without an acceptable excuse. An 'acceptable excuse' is defined as an absence for medical reasons, business reasons, personal reasons, or any other reason which the board, by a two-thirds () vote of its membership, deems appropriate. If a member is absent with an acceptable excuse from three (3) or more meetings, the board may vote to remove the member from the board.</section><section>A member shall be considered absent from a meeting if the member is not physically present for at least seventy-five (75) percent of the meeting's duration. A member shall also be considered absent from a meeting if the member refrains from voting on any matter for which voting is conducted at the meeting, unless the member is prevented from voting by a conflict of interest. The provisions of the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, as may be amended, are applicable to this board.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-128, ยง 3, 7-22-97; Ord. No. 14-112, ยง 2, 11-5-14)</history></law>