<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-11.17</section_number>
<catch_line>Residents First Training and Employment Program.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000096</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>Title. This section shall be referred to as the Miami-Dade County Residents First Training and Employment Program.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Definitions. For purposes of this section the following definitions shall be effective:<section prefix='(a)'>County Construction Contracts means (i) a County contract valued in excess of $1,000,000 for the construction, demolition, alteration and/or repair of public buildings or public works, or (ii) a contract or lease valued in excess of $1,000,000 which provides for privately funded construction, demolition, alteration or repair of buildings or improvements located on County-owned land.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Department means the department, agency or other party responsible for awarding a County Construction Contract as designated by the County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Implementing Order ("IO") means the implementing order developed by the Mayor or Mayor's designee and approved by this Board of County Commissioners (the "Board") to give effect to the provisions of this section.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Program Scope.<section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this ordinance shall apply to County Construction Contracts which are subject to Section 2-11.16 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida (the "Code"), entered into after the effective date of the ordinance by the County, and its Departments.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The provisions of this Section shall be applied to reinforce and complement the provisions of Sections 2-11.16 and 2-1701 of the Code.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>General Program Requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Except where state or federal laws or regulations mandate to the contrary, all contractors and subcontractors of any tier performing on a County Construction Contract shall satisfy the requirements of this Section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>As a condition of submitting a bid or proposal for a County Construction Contract, a general contractor, construction manager or other contractor seeking award of a contract shall submit a Responsible Contractor Affidavit with its bid or proposal.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Responsible Contractor Affidavit shall be completed on a standard form prepared by the County and shall reference the County Construction Contract for which a bid or proposal is being submitted by name and contract or project number. Any agency, department, or other party responsible for awarding a County Construction Contract shall require contractors to use the standard form prepared by the County.</section><section prefix='(d)'>A County Construction Contract shall not be executed until all requirements of this Section have been fulfilled.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Prior to awarding or approving future County Construction Contracts, the County shall review prior work performed by proposed contractors and subcontractors, including their compliance with the terms of the Responsible Contractor Affidavit.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The County shall provide notice to any contractor who fails to submit a Responsible Contractor Affidavit, that said contractor has forty-eight (48) hours from the time of notification to submit a Responsible Contractor Affidavit or its bid or proposal will be deemed nonresponsive and disqualified.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Responsible Contractor Affidavit.<section prefix='(a)'>Required Affidavit. A construction manager, general contractor or other contractor submitting a bid or proposal for a County Construction Contract shall verify the following information on its Responsible Contractor Affidavit form:<section prefix='(i)'>Prior to working on the project, all persons employed by the contractor to perform construction shall have completed, the OSHA 10 Hour safety training course established by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration of the United States Department of Labor. Such training does not need to be completed at the time of bidding but shall be completed prior to the date persons are employed on the project.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The contractor will make its best reasonable efforts to promote employment opportunities for local residents and seek to achieve a project goal of having fifty-one percent (51%) of all Construction Labor hours performed by Miami-Dade County residents. To verify workers' residency, firms shall require each worker to produce a valid driver's license or other form of government-issued identification. County residents employed in furtherance of the goal set forth in the County's Community Workforce Program shall be counted towards the fifty-one percent (51%) goal.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Subcontractor Affidavits. After the contractor has received the Notice of Award of the contract but prior to the issuance by the County of the Notice to Proceed, the contractor shall also submit (i) a list of all subcontractors that will be used on the project, and (ii) provide Responsible Subcontractor Affidavits for all such subcontractors to the County. Responsible Subcontractor Affidavits shall be executed by the respective subcontractors on forms prepared by the County and shall contain the same information required in Responsible Contractor Affidavits.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Construction Workforce Plan. Documentation regarding a contractor's construction workforce plan (the "Plan") shall be provided. The Plan shall specify the total number of persons that will be used by the contractor (as well as by all subcontractors) to perform all of the construction trades and labor work of the contract, broken down by trade and labor category, minimum qualifications for each category, and the number of persons to be utilized in each category. The Plan shall identify by name, address and trade category of all persons proposed to perform work under the contract currently on the contractor's (or on any proposed subcontractor's) payroll who reside in Miami-Dade County. The Plan shall also indicate the number of positions shown on the work, trade categories and minimum qualifications therefore of the positions to be hired by the contractor (or by any proposed subcontractors) to perform the construction trades and labor work under the contract.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Workforce Performance Reports.<section prefix='(a)'>Within thirty (30) days of completion of a County Construction Contract, the contractor responsible for the project shall submit a Workforce Performance Report to the County, which shall include the following information on the workforce employed in the execution of the contract:<section prefix='(i)'>the total number of Construction Labor work hours performed on the project, and the number and percentage of such work hours performed by Miami-Dade County residents;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>supporting documentation verifying Construction Labor work hours performed by Miami-Dade County Residents;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>the total amount of funds the contractor expended during the course of the project on other related skill and safety training programs; and</section><section prefix='(iv)'>supporting documentation verifying reasonable efforts to promote employment opportunities for local residents.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>No contractor shall receive final payment for completion of a County Construction Contract until the County receives a completed workforce performance report submitted pursuant to this Section.</section><section prefix='(c)'>When evaluating a prospective contractor's bids or proposals for future County Construction Contracts, the Department shall review past Contractor's Workforce Reports, as well as other performance evaluations and reports on the contractor's work, to ensure it meets appropriate qualification and contractor responsibility standards.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Implementation. The Mayor or Mayor's designee shall prepare and submit to the Board for approval, an Implementing Order within ninety (90) days of the effective date of this ordinance, which shall at a minimum:<section prefix='(a)'>Set forth procedures to determine contractor compliance with the requirement to make its best reasonable efforts to promote employment opportunities for local residents and seek to achieve a project goal of having fifty-one percent (51%) of all Construction Labor hours performed by Miami-Dade County residents.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Establish a procedure for review and investigation of allegations of noncompliance with the provisions of this ordinance and IO.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Establish a procedure to determine appropriate sanctions for failure to comply with the terms of this ordinance and IO.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Require that all solicitations for County Construction Contracts and the resulting contracts, include the requirements of the Residents First Training and Employment Program.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-26, ยง 1, 3-4-14)</history></law>