<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00110' order_by='00110' level='3'>ARTICLE XCII. NEAT STREETS MIAMI</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-1335</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization of the Board for Neat Streets Miami.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000877</order_by>
<text><section prefix='1.'>Membership. The Board for Neat Streets Miami shall be made up of the following members:<section prefix='a.'>A representative from Florida Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix='b.'>Two representatives from the Miami-Dade County Public Works and Waste Management Department;</section><section prefix='c.'>A representative from seven municipalities located within Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='d.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade Transit Department;</section><section prefix='e.'>Two representatives from the Miami-Dade County Parks, Recreation, and Open Spaces Department;</section><section prefix='f.'>A representative from the County Mayor's Office;</section><section prefix='g.'>A Miami-Dade County Commissioner from each Commission District or his or her designee;</section><section prefix='h.'>A representative from Miami-Dade Expressway Authority;</section><section prefix='i.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade County Aviation Department;</section><section prefix='j.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade County Seaport;</section><section prefix='k.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade Regulatory and Economic Resources Department;</section><section prefix='l.'>A representative from the Metropolitan Planning Organization ("MPO");</section><section prefix='m.'>A representative from Miami-Dade County Public Schools;</section><section prefix='n.'>A representative from Transportation Aesthetics Review Committee ("TARC");</section><section prefix='o.'>A representative from the Citizen's Transportation Advisory Committee ("CTAC");</section><section prefix='p.'>A representative from one chamber of commerce in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='q.'>A representative from the Greater Miami Convention and Visitors Bureau;</section><section prefix='r.'>A representative from the Downtown Development Authority;</section><section prefix='s.'>A representative from the Miami-Dade League of Cities;</section><section prefix='t.'>A representative from the train/railroad industry;</section><section prefix='u.'>A representative from the Miami Herald;</section><section prefix='v.'>A representative from the University of Florida's Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences (UF/IFAS)/Miami-Dade County Cooperative Extension;</section><section prefix='w.'>A representative from two institutes of higher education;</section><section prefix='x.'>Two members at large; and</section><section prefix='y.'>A representative from two non-profit organizations within Miami-Dade County.</section></section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Board for Neat Streets Miami shall be permitted, by majority vote, to alter the composition of the Board for Neat Streets Miami without further amendment of this Ordinance. To the extent the Board for Neat Streets Miami creates new membership categories under this paragraph, the Board for Neat Streets Miami shall notify the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners of the new membership category created. Persons selected to fill new membership categories created by the Board for Neat Streets Miami shall be appointed in accordance with Section (2), below.</section><section prefix='2.'>Appointment of Chairperson and Members of Neat Streets Miami. The Chairperson of the Board for Neat Streets Miami shall be appointed by the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners. A person designated by the Board for Neat Streets Miami shall contact each of the organizations, companies, and municipalities referenced in Section (1) above, and shall request that each of these organizations, companies, and municipalities submit the names of at least one (1) interested and eligible nominee. The membership slots for municipalities created under Section (1)(c) shall be filled on a first-come, first-served basis. These nominees shall be submitted to the Board for Neat Streets Miami in the form of a report for approval and appointment to the Board for Neat Streets Miami.</section><section prefix='3.'>Unfilled Membership Vacancies. If any membership slot created under Section (1) remains unfilled for a period of three (3) months from the date the vacancy occurs, then the Board for Neat Streets Miami may fill said vacant membership slot as if that slot were designated for an at-large member under Section (1).</section><section prefix='4.'>Meetings. The Board for Neat Streets Miami shall hold regular meetings, no less than six times per year, and such other meetings as it deems necessary. Ten (10) of the duly appointed and sitting members of the Board for Neat Streets Miami shall constitute a quorum. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Board for Neat Streets Miami and all meetings shall be duly noticed to the public.</section><section prefix='5.'>Applicability of County Rules and Procedures. The Board for Neat Streets Miami shall at all times operate under the Florida Open Government laws, including the "Sunshine Law," public meeting laws and public records laws and shall be governed by all State and County conflict of interest laws, as applicable, including the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, Section 2-11.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='6.'>Attendance Requirement. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, any Neat Streets Miami Board member shall be automatically removed if, in a given fiscal year he or she is absent from more than 50% of the year's meetings. A member shall be deemed absent from a meeting when he or she is not present at the meeting at least seventy-five percent of the time. By a one-third () vote of the members present, the provisions of this section may be waived.</section><section prefix='7.'>Compensation. Members of the Board for Neat Streets Miami shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their duties.</section><section prefix='8.'>Staff and Facility Support. The County Mayor and County Attorney shall provide such staff support to the Board for Neat Streets Miami as may be necessary to accomplish its purpose. The County Mayor will provide such facilities as the Board for Neat Streets Miami may deem necessary to accomplish its purposes.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 01-164, § 2, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 02-31, § 1, 2-26-02; Ord. No. 03-215, § 1, 10-7-03; Ord. No. 14-46, § 1, 5-6-14; Ord. No. 15-04, § 2, 2-3-15)</history></law>