<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='3'>ARTICLE XXIII. COMMUNITY RELATIONS BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-206</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization; quorum; voting; rules of procedure; records of meetings.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000418</order_by>
<text><section>The members of the Board shall select and designate from its members a Chairperson, Vice-Chairperson, Secretary, and such other officers as may be deemed necessary, who shall serve for a two-year term at the pleasure of the Board. No member shall remain in the same office for more than four (4) consecutive years. After one (1) year of not holding the office, a member may be elected to the same office that was previously held for up to four (4) consecutive years. Officer elections shall take place each November, with newly elected officers installed the following January.</section><section>A majority of members duly appointed to the Board shall constitute a quorum, notwithstanding. No action shall be taken except by a majority vote of those present at a duly constituted meeting of the Board; provided, however, an executive committee consisting of all officers and such other persons as the Chairperson may appoint from time to time is authorized to exercise all powers, duties and functions of the Board between Board meetings, any such action to be reported to the Board at its next meeting and the Board shall either ratify or rescind the action of the executive committee. The Board may adopt rules of procedure governing its meetings and actions on matters within its jurisdiction, not inconsistent with the provisions of this article, which rules of procedure shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission.</section><section>Copies of the minutes of all Board meetings shall be furnished to the Chairperson of the County Commission and the County Mayor. The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners ("Clerk of the Board") shall maintain a current roster of the board's members and record the board's meetings and maintain minutes of the board's meetings.</section><section>The Office of Community Advocacy's duties shall include working with the Clerk of the Board to ensure the board's membership roster is current and posting minutes from the board's meetings online. In addition, the executive director of the Office of Community Advocacy shall provide a report on the board every twelve months to the Board of County Commissioners.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-22, § 3, 6-11-63; Ord. No. 64-10, § 1, 3-24-64; Ord. No. 67-38, § 2, 5-16-67; Ord. No. 68-2, § 1, 2-6-68; Ord. No. 00-115, § 1, 9-19-00; Ord. No. 03-86, § 2, 4-10-02; Ord. No. 14-108, § 2, 11-5-14)</history></law>