<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00168' order_by='00168' level='3'>ARTICLE CXLIX. DADE-MIAMI CRIMINAL JUSTICE COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2169</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001313</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>The Council shall establish, adopt, and amend bylaws for its own governance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Officers. Members of the Council shall elect one (1) of its members as chairperson, one (1) of its members as vice-chairperson, and any such other officers as the Council determines to be necessary and appropriate. Notwithstanding any provision herein, the Chairperson and Vice-Chairperson in office at the time this ordinance becomes effective shall complete their term as Chairperson and Vice-Chairperson and may be elected for successive terms, subject to compliance with the provisions of this ordinance and any applicable provisions of the bylaws.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Meetings. The Council shall convene at least four regular meetings per year.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Quorum. In order to transact business, a quorum shall consist of a majority of those persons duly appointed to the board, provided that at least one-half (1/2) of the full Council membership has been appointed. If the persons appointed to the board do not constitute at least one-half (1/2) of the full Council membership, the Chairperson shall take all necessary steps to fill, or cause vacancies to the Council to be filled, in accordance with the provisions of this ordinance.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Special or Emergency Meeting. Special Meetings of the Council may be called by the Chairperson, or upon the written request of three (3) or more Council members made to Council staff, or upon the request of Council staff.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Committees. The Chairperson, independently or upon recommendation of the Council, shall establish committees to assist in accomplishing its tasks and shall appoint members thereto and a Chairperson and Vice-Chairperson of committees established, except for the Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee. Only Council members may be appointed to serve as Chairperson or Vice-Chairperson of committees. The Chairperson shall be a voting member of all Committees. Results of all committee action(s) will be made known to all Council members at the next scheduled full Council meeting. The following committees shall be established:<section prefix='(1)'>Executive Committee. The Dade-Miami Criminal Justice Council shall have an Executive Committee that will be comprised of the Council Chairperson, the Council Vice-Chairperson, and the Chairpersons of the Council's Standing Committees. The Executive Committee shall act on behalf of the Council between meetings on any urgent matters which would normally come before the Council for a decision.<section>No designees may be authorized to vote at an Executive Committee meeting, except as otherwise permitted under this ordinance. The Executive Committee shall be entitled to propose changes to the bylaws as needed.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee. The Council shall have a Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee, which shall carry out duties required by Florida Statute Section 951.26. The members of the committee shall be members of the Council that meet the requirements of Florida Statute Section 951.26, as may be amended. This committee's actions shall be independent from, and shall not be subject to modifications by the Council. The Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee shall act in accordance with Florida Statute Section 951.26 and shall be comprised of members as stated therein.<section>The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chairperson for the purpose of assessing the population status of all detention or correctional facilities owned or contracted by the county, and will formulate recommendations to ensure that the capacities of such facilities are not exceeded. Such recommendations shall include an assessment of the availability of pretrial intervention or probation programs, work-release programs, substance abuse programs, gain-time schedules, applicable bail bond schedules, and the confinement status of the inmates housed within each facility owned or contracted by the county. Results of Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee action will be made known to all Council members at the next scheduled full Council meeting.</section><section>Pursuant to section 951.26, Florida Statutes, the Chairperson of the Board of County Commissioners, or another County Commissioner as designee, shall serve as the chairperson of the Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee until the Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee elects a committee chairperson from the committee's membership.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Legislative and Policy Committee. The Legislative and Policy Committee shall develop a comprehensive approach for the prevention of serious and violent crime through legislative strategies that fill the gaps in the continuum of practices that impact the community. This committee shall review and analyze proposed and current federal, state, and local legislation, and provide recommendations to the Council on legislative development.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Juvenile Justice and Prevention Committee. The Juvenile Justice and Prevention Committee shall strengthen the continuum of care for youth at risk of criminal behavior and for young offenders at all stages of involvement in the juvenile and criminal justice systems through the replication and adaptation of proven initiatives that incorporate research, practical experience, and broad-based community partnerships.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Nominating Committee. The Nominating Committee shall be comprised of Institutional Members. The Nominating committee shall identify, review, and make recommendations to the Council for candidates to fill Community Representative vacancies on the Council.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Mental Health Diversion Committee. The Mental Health Diversion Committee shall review the current mental health and jail system/processes and shall make recommendations for system improvements to more effectively divert, treat and monitor persons with mental illness who become involved in the criminal justice system.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Ad Hoc Committees. The Council Chairperson may appoint an "ad hoc" Committee for special purposes.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Public Meetings. All meetings of the Council and its committees shall take place in accordance with applicable Sunshine law requirements. The Council shall supply copies of the notice of its regular meetings, special, rescheduled and reconvened meetings to any media that have filed a request for such notice.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Staff Support. The Council shall have assistance as designated by Miami-Dade County.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-17, ยง 4, 2-4-14)</history></law>