<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00168' order_by='00168' level='3'>ARTICLE CXLIX. DADE-MIAMI CRIMINAL JUSTICE COUNCIL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2167</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and Duties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001305</order_by>
<text><section>The Council shall have the following powers, duties, functions, and responsibilities:<section prefix='(a)'>To advise and make recommendations to the Miami-Dade County Mayor, Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners, the City of Miami Mayor, and the City of Miami Board of City Commissioners on Criminal Justice and Juvenile Justice issues;</section><section prefix='(b)'>To encourage and facilitate coordination and cooperation between and amongst the various agencies of the criminal justice systems of Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(c)'>To provide for coordination through the efficient and effective use of funds from various sources to improve the criminal justice system;</section><section prefix='(d)'>To provide advice to local officials on City and County criminal justice-related programming and funding needs as requested;</section><section prefix='(e)'>To provide legislative analysis and recommendations at the local, state, and federal levels;</section><section prefix='(f)'>To review local criminal justice issues as they arise and are brought to the attention of the Council, or its staff, thus encouraging appropriate, cooperative criminal justice agency response;</section><section prefix='(g)'>To serve in advisory role in comprehensive planning for all segments of the criminal justice system in Miami-Dade County;</section><section prefix='(h)'>To serve in an advisory capacity, as needed, to any private or public agency whose activities are related to criminal justice;</section><section prefix='(i)'>Through its Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee, pursuant to section 951.26, Florida Statutes, the Public Safety Coordinating Council Committee:<section prefix='(1)'>may develop a local public safety plan for future jail construction needs, in accordance with the steps described in section 951.26, Florida Statutes. The plan, if developed, must cover at least a 5-year period;</section><section prefix='(2)'>shall develop a comprehensive public safety plan as described in section 948.51, Florida Statutes, which includes the future public safety construction needs as described in Miami-Dade County's local public safety plan, if Miami-Dade County contracts to receive community corrections funds for its community corrections programs under section 948.51, Florida Statutes; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>may develop a comprehensive local reentry plan that is designed to assist offenders released from incarceration to successfully reenter the community. The plan should cover at least a 5-year period. In developing the plan, the council shall coordinate with public safety officials and local community organizations that can provide offenders with reentry services, such as assistance with housing, health care, education, substance abuse treatment, and employment.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-17, ยง 2, 2-4-14)</history></law>