<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00169' order_by='00169' level='3'>ARTICLE CL. JACKSON HEALTH SYSTEM'S GENERAL OBLIGATION BOND PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2182</section_number>
<catch_line>Powers and Duties of Advisory Committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001369</order_by>
<text><section>The Advisory Committee shall have the following powers, duties, responsibilities and functions:<section prefix='(a)'>To review and monitor performance and program achievements related to the Bond Program; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>To periodically advise the County Commission, the Public Health Trust and the Mayor, and assist in informing the community, of the Bond Program's accomplishments regarding completion of Jackson Health System capital projects funded in whole or in part by the Bond Program; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>To review recommendations of the Public Health Trust on the use of any Bond Program funds to fund Jackson Health System capital projects, including those set forth in informational pamphlets and media releases distributed by the County and/or the Public Health Trust to the public prior to said November 5, 2013 election; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>To participate, along with Public Health Trust staff, in citizen outreach efforts relating to the development of Jackson Health System capital projects funded in whole or in part with Bond Program funds; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>To assist in the preparation of quarterly reports to the County Commission and Mayor describing the progress of the Bond Program and to periodically provide advice, by either written resolution or oral presentation, as may be requested by the County Commission, the Public Health Trust or the Mayor in accordance with the terms of this section; and</section><section prefix='(f)'>To appoint an Advisory Committee member to participate in monthly meetings of the Public Health Trust governing board committee with jurisdiction over facilities and construction; and</section><section prefix='(g)'>To promulgate rules consistent with this article for the conduct of its meetings and the discharge of its responsibilities; provided, however, the Advisory Committee shall not create or establish any subcommittees to address the work of the Advisory Committee; and</section><section prefix='(h)'>To comply with the laws and regulations of the United States, the State of Florida, and Miami-Dade County, including, but not limited to, the laws relating to the keeping of records including the preservation of all audit rights.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-44, ยง 1, 5-6-14)</history></law>