<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00172' order_by='00172' level='3'>ARTICLE CLIII. KEYS CROSSING APARTMENTS MULTIPURPOSE MAINTENANCE AND STREET LIGHTING SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2242</section_number>
<catch_line>[Boundaries.]</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001331</order_by>
<text><section>The area or boundaries of this proposed special taxing district are as follows:</section><section>A portion of, Township 56 South, Range 39 East in Miami-Dade County, Florida; being more particularly described as follows:<section>Commence at the southwest corner of the E ½ of the NE ¼ of the SW ¼ of said; thence N 00° 35′ 28″ W along the west line of the E ½ of the NE ¼ of the SW ¼ of said for 494.92 feet to the Point-of-Beginning; thence N 00° 35′ 28″ W along the west line of the E ½ of the NE ¼ of the SW ¼ of said for 433.00 feet; thence S 89° 22′ 22″ W along the centerline of the proposed right-of-way for SW 257 Terrace for 448.20 feet; thence S 00° 37′ 09″ E for 433.00 feet; thence N 89° 22′ 22″ E along the westerly prolongation of the north line of the dedicated right-of-way for SW 258 Lane, as shown on the plat of "Magnolia Landing," according to the Plat thereof, as recorded in Plat Book 168 at Page 73, of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for 53.53 feet; thence S 00° 37′ 07″ E along the westerly boundary line of a 27.75 foot wide easement as described in that certain "temporary grant of easement, "Recorded in Official Records Book 27062, at Page 4196, of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for 144.88 feet; thence N 89° 22′ 22″ E for 27.75 feet; thence N 00° 37′ 07″ W for 144.88 feet; thence N 89° 22′ 22″ E for 366.71 feet to the Point-of-Beginning (a.k.a. Keys Crossing Apartments, Tentative Plat # T-23569).</section></section><section>The area and geographical location of this proposed special taxing district are shown on the Exhibit map or sketch, and made a part herein by reference.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 15-51, § 2, 6-30-15)</history></law>