<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00170' order_by='00170' level='3'>ARTICLE CLI. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY MARKETING PARTNERSHIPS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2201</section_number>
<catch_line>Marketing Partnerships Program.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001319</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Marketing Partnerships Program—The Marketing Partnerships Program is a countywide sponsorship program whereby a third party will provide a financial benefit to the County in the form of non-tax revenue and/or in-kind fees (products or services) in exchange for the access to the marketing commercial potential associated with select County assets for the use in strategies to promote, sell, or distribute a product or service. Marketing partnerships will vary depending on County assets and corporate goals, but can incorporate certain marketing privileges such as naming and sales rights, facility and event signage, program advertising, and an exclusive proud product/services provider to the County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Marketing Partnership Agreement—A Marketing Partnership Agreement is an agreement with a third party to provide a financial benefit to the County in the form of non-tax revenue and/or in-kind fees (products or services) in exchange for the access to the marketing commercial potential associated with select County assets for the use in strategies to promote, sell, or distribute a product or service. Marketing Partnership Agreements may incorporate but not be limited to certain marketing privileges such as advertising, exclusivity rights, naming rights, and other revenue-generating methodologies.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The Marketing Partnerships Program is hereby created to generate revenue for the County by using the commercial marketable value of county assets.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The Board of County Commissioners retains the authority for the allocation of any revenue generated by this Program.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The County Mayor or his designee is hereby delegated the following authority:<section prefix='(a)'>to develop, implement, and manage the Marketing Partnerships Program;</section><section prefix='(b)'>to enter into Marketing Partnership Agreements with an aggregate estimated value of less than $1 million. Agreements with an aggregate estimated value of $1 million or more and non-event naming rights require Board of County Commissioners approval;</section><section prefix='(c)'>to provide guidance to County departments regarding the proper application of the criterion of the program;</section><section prefix='(d)'>to provide assistance and consultation to departments regarding prospective marketing partnership activities and opportunities; and</section><section prefix='(e)'>to review and assist in the creation and negotiation of Marketing Partnership Agreements.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-99, § 1, 10-7-14)</history></law>