<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00176' order_by='00176' level='3'>ARTICLE CLVII. ATLANTIC VILLAS AT KENDALL MULTIPURPOSE MAINTENANCE SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2322</section_number>
<catch_line>[Boundaries.]</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001365</order_by>
<text><section>The area or boundaries of this proposed special taxing district are as follows:</section><section>A portion of, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, and a portion of Section 34, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, both lying in Miami-Dade County, Florida (a.k.a. Atlantic Villas at Kendall, Tentative Plat # T-23489); being more particularly described as follows:<section>The S ½ of the S ½ of the SE ¼ of the SE ¼, less the west 410.00 feet thereof, in, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, all lying and being in Miami-Dade County, Florida. Subject to right-of-way dedication along SW 137 Avenue.</section><section>AND</section><section>The N ½ of the N ½ of the NE ¼ of the NE ¼ of Section 34, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, less the west 410.00 feet thereof, and less the north 200.00 feet of the east 200.00 feet, lying and being in Miami-Dade County, Florida, a.k.a. lot 1 less the west 410.00 feet thereof, and less the north 200.00 feet of the east 200.00 feet, in the NE ¼ of Section 34 of "Tropico", according to the Plat thereof, as recorded in Plat Book 2, Page 57 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section>AND</section><section>The north 200.00 feet of the east 200.00 feet of the N ½ of the N ½ of the NE ¼ of the NE ¼ of Section 34 lying and being in Miami-Dade County, Florida, a.k.a. the north 200.00 feet of the east 200.00 feet of Lot 1, in the NE ¼ of Section 34, Township 55 South, Range 39 East, of "Tropico", according to the Plat thereof, as recorded in Plat Book 2, Page 57 of the Public Records of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>The area and geographical location of this proposed special taxing district are shown on the exhibit map or sketch, and made a part herein by reference.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 15-55, § 2, 6-30-15)</history></law>