<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00175' order_by='00175' level='3'>ARTICLE CLVI. DORAL COMMONS RESIDENTIAL AND DORAL COMMONS COMMERCIAL MULTIPURPOSE MAINTENANCE AND STREET LIGHTING SPECIAL TAXING DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-2304</section_number>
<catch_line>[Maintenance and service—Costs.]</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001414</order_by>
<text><section prefix='A)'>Multipurpose Maintenance—The combined costs of the multipurpose maintenance project and operation of the proposed district's improvements and/or services including engineering, administration, billing, collecting and processing for the first year are provided by petitioner, and are $121,544.27 for the second year. It is estimated that the cost per assessable square foot of real property within the proposed district for the initial multipurpose maintenance program shall be provided by petitioners for the first year, and are $0.0500 for the second year. The second and succeeding years' assessments will be adjusted from actual experience.</section><section prefix='B)'>Street Lighting Services—The installation of the street lighting project will be accomplished pursuant to an agreement between Miami-Dade County and the Florida Power and Light Company. The expected costs of the street lighting project and operation of the proposed district's improvements including service, maintenance, electricity, engineering, administration, billing, collection and processing for the first year are provided by petitioner and estimated to be $32,386.92. The expected costs of the street lighting project and operation of the district's improvements including service, maintenance, electricity, engineering, administration, billing, collection and processing for the second year are estimated to be $12,848.96. The expected estimated cost per assessable front foot of real property within the proposed district for the second year is $2.2982. The second and succeeding years' assessments will be adjusted from actual experience.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 15-54, § 4, 6-30-15)</history></law>