<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='3'>ARTICLE XXX. COMMISSION FOR WOMEN</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-268</section_number>
<catch_line>Organization of the commission.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000529</order_by>
<text><section>The members of the Commission shall elect such officers other than a Chairman as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve one-year terms at the will of the Commission. No member shall remain in the same office for more than two (2) consecutive years. After one (1) year of not holding the office, a member may be elected to the same office that was previously held for up to two (2) consecutive years. Officer elections shall take place each November, with newly elected officers installed the following January.</section><section>A majority of members duly appointed to the Commission shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, upon approval by the County Commission. The Chairman may call meetings of the Commission, and meetings may be called by written notice signed by fourteen (14) members and the Commission at any meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. Minutes shall be kept of all meetings of the Commission. All meetings shall be public.</section><section>The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners ("Clerk of the Board") shall maintain a current roster of the Commission for Women's members and maintain minutes of the Commission's meetings.</section><section>The Office of Community Advocacy's duties shall include working with the Clerk of the Board to ensure the Commission's membership roster is current and posting minutes from the Commission's meetings online. In addition, the executive director of the Office of Community Advocacy shall provide a report on the Commission every twelve months to the Board of County Commissioners.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-11, ยง 5, 1-19-71; Ord. No. 71-51, ยง 1, 6-15-71; Ord. No. 14-111, ยง 4, 11-5-14)</history></law>