<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='4'>DIVISION 1. PERSONNEL DEPARTMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-30</section_number>
<catch_line>Criminal history record checks for certain county employees, appointees, and contractors.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000155</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-30. Criminal history record checks for certain county employees, appointees, and contractors.<section>Pursuant to Section 125.5801, Florida Statutes, as such may be amended from time to time, state and national criminal history background checks shall be required for:<section prefix='(a)'>Any position of county employment or appointment, whether paid, unpaid, or contractual, which is identified as critical to security or public safety pursuant to Implementing Order 7-41, as such may be amended from time to time; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any private contractor or employee of a private contractor who has direct contact with individual members of the public or access to any public facility or publicly-operated facility to such an extent that the legislative body of the County finds that such contact or access is critical to security or public safety, as set forth in Implementing Order 7-41, as such may be amended from time to time.</section></section><section>Each such person shall be fingerprinted who is applying for any such position, continuing employment or appointment in any such position, or having such contact or access. The Miami-Dade County Human Resources Department, its successor department, and other applicable departments shall conduct such state and national criminal history background checks.</section><section>Fingerprints obtained pursuant to the authority of this section shall be submitted to the Florida Department of Law Enforcement for a state criminal history records check and also to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check. The information obtained from each respective criminal history record check conducted pursuant to this ordinance shall be used to determine a person's eligibility for employment, appointment, or access and to determine a person's eligibility for continued employment, appointment, or access.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 15-20, ยง 1, 3-17-15)</history></law>