<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='4'>DIVISION 2. CIVIL SERVICE FOR COUNTY EMPLOYEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-41</section_number>
<catch_line>Classified service; exceptions therefrom.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000211</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-41. Classified service; exceptions therefrom.<section>The classified service shall comprise all full-time positions in the County service existing on January 1, 1956, or thereafter established, except positions held by employees of the Public Health Trust of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and except the following:<section prefix='(1)'>The Mayor, County Commissioners and other officers elected by popular vote or appointed by the governor, and persons appointed to fill vacancies in elective offices, and all administrative assistants and secretaries to the foregoing.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Members of Boards and Commissions, appointed by the County Commissioners or by elected official or by the Manager; and all administrative assistants and all secretaries to the foregoing.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The County Manager, all Senior Assistants to the County Manager, all administrative assistants, all secretaries and all other employees of the County Manager's Office or its offices.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The County Attorney, all Assistant County Attorneys, law Clerks, secretarial, clerical and all other employees of the County Attorney's office.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All members of the staff of the Eleventh Circuit and the employees of the Administrative Office of the Court.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Department directors, deputy department directors, assistant department directors, division directors, agency heads, board of directors, consumer advocates, program directors and all immediate assistants and all immediate assistants and all secretaries to the foregoing.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Persons employed in a professional or scientific capacity to make or conduct a temporary and specific inquiry, investigation or examination on behalf of the County Commissioners or a committee thereof, and other elected officials, or by the authority thereof, or persons employed in a highly specialized professional scientific or technical capacity needed to implement a mass transit system.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Physicians, attorneys and other professional medical employees, and licensed practical nurses.</section><section prefix='(9)'>All employees of the Office of Management and Budget.</section><section prefix='(10)'>All employees of the Cooperative Extension Division of the Department of Consumer Services.</section><section prefix='(11)'>All administrative interns.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Persons who are jointly employed by the County and any institute of higher learning.</section><section prefix='(13)'>Director of art museums.</section><section prefix='(14)'>All independent contractors.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Medical examiners and their professional personnel.</section><section prefix='(16)'>The Clerk of Circuit and County courts, Chief Deputy Clerk, Senior Deputy Clerk, division chiefs, assistant division chiefs, court operations officers, Deputy Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners, all administrative assistants and secretaries to the foregoing, and ex-parte clerks.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Employees who are hired and occupy positions that must be filled under guidelines inconsistent with merit employment principles.</section><section prefix='(18)'>The following employees of the Miami-Dade Police Department and the Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation: commanders of all bureaus and all police ranks above captain. It is the intention of the Board of County Commissioners that those positions shall be filled from the ranks of lieutenant or higher from within the departments whenever possible, in the judgment of the directors.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Employees of the Miami-Dade police department with the rank of police commander.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Employees of the fire department with the classifications of fire department special assistant 1 and 2.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Non-bargaining unit professional or managerial positions whose duties are determined to be inconsistent with the County's classified service rules, as recommended by the concerned department director and approved by the personnel director and County Manager.</section><section prefix='(22)'>All employees of the audit and management services department.</section><section prefix='(23)'>All non-bargaining unit professional and managerial employees of the Department of Business Development.</section><section prefix='(24)'>All employees of the Communications Department.</section><section prefix='(25)'>All non-bargaining unit professional and managerial employees of the Office of Building Code Compliance.</section><section prefix='(26)'>All employees of the Housing Finance Authority.</section><section prefix='(27)'>All employees of the Labor Management and Employee Appeals Division of the Employee Relations Department.</section><section prefix='(28)'>All employees of the Community Action Agency.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ch. 30255, § 2, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, § 1, 10-7-57; Ord. No. 58-31, § 1, 8-5-58; Ord. No. 64-35, §§ 2, 3, 7-21-64; Ord. No. 65-8, § 1, 1-25-65; Ord. No. 66-38, § 1, 7-26-66; Ord. No. 67-46, § 1, 7-11-67; Ord. No. 68-82, § 1, 12-17-68; Ord. No. 69-43, § 1, 7-16-69; Ord. No. 70-50, § 1, 6-16-70; Ord. No. 71-77, § 1, 9-22-71; Ord. No. 75-71, §§ 1, 2, 9-17-75; Ord. No. 75-102, § 1, 11-4-75; Ord. No. 76-26, §§ 1, 2, 3-2-76; Ord. No. 77-86, § 2, 12-6-77; Ord. No. 80-16, § 1, 3-4-80; Ord. No. 82-60, § 1, 7-6-82; Ord. No. 86-23, § 1, 3-18-86; Ord. No. 90-18, § 1, 3-6-90; Ord. No. 92-30, § 1, 4-21-92; Ord. No. 99-112, § 2, 9-9-99)</history></law>