<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='4'>DIVISION 2. CIVIL SERVICE FOR COUNTY EMPLOYEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-52</section_number>
<catch_line>Political activities, prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000223</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-52. Political activities, prohibited.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall be appointed or promoted to, or demoted or dismissed from, any position in the classified service or in any way favored or discriminated against with respect to employment in the classified service because of his political or religious opinions or affiliations; but nothing herein shall be construed as precluding the dismissal of any employee who may be engaged in subversive activities or found disloyal to the nation.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No person shall seek or attempt to use any political endorsement in connection with any appointment to a position in the classified service.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No person shall use or promise to use, directly or indirectly, any official authority or influence, whether possessed or anticipated, to secure or attempt to secure for any person an appointment or advantage in appointment to a position in the classified service, or an increase in pay or other advantage in employment in any such position, for the purpose of influencing the vote or political action of any person, or for any consideration.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No employee in the classified service or member of the Board or the Director shall, directly or indirectly, coerce or attempt to coerce, command or advise any other employee in the classified service or member of the Board or officer to pay, lend or contribute any part of his salary, kickback any sum of money, or anything else of value to any party, committee, organization, agency or person for political purposes.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Any person in the classified service of the County who violates any of the foregoing provisions of this section shall forfeit his office or position, and for one (1) year shall be ineligible for any office or position in the County classified service.</section></section></text><history>(Ch. 30255, § 18, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 74-64, § 1, 7-30-74; Ord. No. 75-15, §§ 1, 2, 3-4-75)</history></law>