<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00066' order_by='00066' level='3'>ARTICLE L. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HISPANIC AFFAIRS ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-533</section_number>
<catch_line>Officers; quorum; compensation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000630</order_by>
<text><section>The members of the Board shall elect a chairperson and vice chairperson, who shall serve one-year terms at the will of the Board. No member shall remain in the same office for more than two (2) consecutive years. After one (1) year of not holding the office, a member may be elected to the same office that was previously held for up to two (2) consecutive years. Officer elections shall take place each November, with newly elected officers installed the following January.</section><section>A majority of members duly appointed to the Board shall constitute a quorum necessary to hold a meeting and take any action. A majority vote of the quorum of the Board shall be necessary to take any action. Members shall serve without compensation. The chairperson or vice chairperson may call meetings of the Board. Meetings may also be called by written notice signed by nine (9) members. The Board at any duly noticed meeting may fix and call a meeting on a future date. All meetings shall be public.</section><section>The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners ("Clerk of the Board") shall maintain a current roster of the board's members and maintain minutes of the board's meetings.</section><section>The Office of Community Advocacy's duties shall include working with the Clerk of the Board to ensure the board's membership roster is current and posting minutes from the board's meetings online. In addition, the executive director of the Office of Community Advocacy shall provide a report on the board every twelve months to the Board of County Commissioners.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 92-41, ยง 3, 5-19-92; Ord. No. 93-44, ยง 1, 5-18-93; Ord. No. 14-110, ยง 2, 11-5-14)</history></law>