<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='4'>DIVISION 2. CIVIL SERVICE FOR COUNTY EMPLOYEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-53</section_number>
<catch_line>Misrepresentations on examinations, etc.; employees of Department unlawfully aiding or obstructing applicants.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000224</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-53. Misrepresentations on examinations, etc.; employees of Department unlawfully aiding or obstructing applicants.<section prefix='(a)'>No person shall make any false statement, certificate, mark, rating or report with regard to any test, certification or appointment made under any provision of this law or in any manner commit or attempt to commit any fraud preventing the impartial execution of this law and the rules.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No employee of the Department, examiner, or other person shall defeat, deceive or obstruct any person in his right to examination, eligibility, certification or appointment under this law, or furnish to any person any special or secret information for the purpose of affecting the rights or prospects of any person with respect to employment in the classified service.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any person who is convicted of a violation of any provision of subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall, for a period of five (5) years, be ineligible for appointment to or employment in a classified position in the County service and if he is an employee in the classified County service, shall forfeit his employment.</section></section></text><history>(Ch. 30255, ยง 19, Laws 1955; Ord. No. 57-16, ยง 1, 10-7-57)</history></law>