<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='4'>DIVISION 6. PROTECTION OF EMPLOYEES DISCLOSING SPECIFIED INFORMATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-56.28.19</section_number>
<catch_line>Reporting employee's award program.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000267</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-56.28.19. Reporting employee's award program.<section>Employees who report information pursuant to this division which results in the County's recovery of public funds shall be eligible to apply for an award of up to ten (10) percent of the net amount recovered or one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00), whichever is less. The precise amount of any such award shall be set by the County Mayor or Mayor's designee in accordance with the following procedure: The Mayor or Mayor's designee shall select for each application a panel of three (3) County administrators who shall conduct an informal hearing for the purpose of recommending to the County Mayor or Mayor's designee whether an award should be granted and the amount of any such award. The panel's recommendation shall include consideration of:<section prefix='(1)'>The significance of the information revealed to improving the efficiency of the County;</section><section prefix='(2)'>The likelihood that the County would have learned of the information if the employee had not reported it; and</section><section prefix='(3)'>If the information was reported by more than one employee, whether and how it should be apportioned.</section></section><section>The panel's written recommendation shall be submitted to the Mayor or Mayor's designee whose decision as to whether an award should be granted and the amount thereof shall be final.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-107, ยง 1, 6-9-94; Ord. No. 10-75, ยง 1, 11-4-10)</history></law>