<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='4'>DIVISION 6. PROTECTION OF EMPLOYEES DISCLOSING SPECIFIED INFORMATION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-56.28.17</section_number>
<catch_line>Remedies.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000259</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-56.28.17. Remedies.<section prefix='(1)'>Any employee protected by this division who has the right to file an appeal of an adverse personnel action under Section 2-47 shall also have the right to have the hearing examiner appointed under that section consider the issue of whether the adverse action was in violation of this division. The hearing examiner shall include in his findings of fact and conclusions a determination of whether the adverse action was in violation of this section and shall recommend an appropriate remedy.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any employee protected by this division who does not have the right to file an appeal under Section 2-47 may file a written complaint within sixty (60) days after the action prohibited by this division with the Miami-Dade County Personnel Director. The Director shall refer the complaint to a panel of impartial persons from whom a hearing examiner shall be selected. The panel shall be comprised of all persons available to serve as a hearing examiner under Section 2-47. Such hearing examiners may be paid a fee for their services, but shall not be deemed County officials or employees within the purview of Sections 2-10.2, 2-11.1 or otherwise. The hearing examiner shall conduct a hearing after notice to the complainant and the County department, political subdivision or special district involved. The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the procedures applicable to hearings under Section 2-47, except as may be provided herein. Any interested party may procure the attendance of witnesses and the production of records at such hearing in the manner provided by Section 2-50. All hearings requested pursuant to this paragraph shall be commenced insofar as is practicable within sixty (60) days of the Personnel Director's receipt of the complaint, except that the Director shall have the authority to extend such time for reasonable cause.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The hearing examiner shall transmit his findings of facts, conclusions of law and any recommendations together with a transcript of all evidence taken before him and all exhibits received by him to the County Mayor or Mayor's designee for a final decision. The Mayor or Mayor's designee may sustain, reverse or modify the adverse personnel action. In any case in which the hearing examiner finds that the employee filed a frivolous complaint in bad faith, the hearing examiner may recommend and the Mayor or Mayor's designee may direct the employee to pay the costs of the hearing, including the employer's attorney's fees.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Investigation by Ethics Commission. In addition to the remedies set forth above.<section prefix='(a)'>Any employee protected under this division who alleges retaliation may, in lieu of or in addition to seeking the relief set forth above, file a written complaint with the Miami-Dade County Ethics Commission alleging a prohibited personnel action, no later than 60 days after the prohibited personnel action.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Within ten working days after receiving a complaint under this section, the Ethics Commission shall acknowledge receipt of the complaint and provide copies of the complaint and any other preliminary information available concerning the disclosure of information under this Section to the department or employee accused of retaliation.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Fact finding. Upon the filing of a complaint with the Ethics Commission under this section, the Ethics Commission shall:<section prefix='(i)'>Conduct a preliminary investigation and a fact finding hearing within 60 days regarding the allegation of retaliation, to the extent necessary, to determine whether there is probable cause to believe that a prohibited personnel action under this Section has occurred, is occurring, or is to be taken.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Within 90 days after receiving the complaint, provide the accused department or employee and the complainant with a fact-finding report. The fact-finding report shall be presumed admissible in any subsequent or related administrative or judicial review.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Based on its fact-finding report, recommend to the County Manager an appropriate course of action. The Manager shall thereafter take appropriate remedial action in accordance with Section 2-56.28.18</section></section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Any employee found by the Ethics Commission to have retaliated against another County employee in violation of this section shall be considered to have committed a violation of the County's Code of Ethics and shall be subject to disciplinary action up to and including dismissal from County employment.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-107, ยง 1, 6-9-94; Ord. No. 07-63, ยง 1, 5-8-07; Ord. No. 10-75, ยง 1, 11-4-10)</history></law>