<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='4'>DIVISION 4. SERVICE-CONNECTED DISABILITY PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-56.27.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Short-term disability leave and benefits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000246</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-56.27.1. Short-term disability leave and benefits.<section>Unless otherwise provided by agreement with a County employee or bargaining representative of a County employee, any employee who sustains a service-connected disability may be entitled to the following benefits, only after the injury has been investigated by the Insurance Management Division and approval has been given by the Division and Personnel Division of the Employee Relations Department.<section prefix='(a)'>Career employees occupying permanently budgeted full time positions and who have competed nine (9) pay periods (four (4) months) of service, may be entitled to receive their normal salary, reduced by the Workmen's Compensation benefits due them, for a period not to exceed four (4) months.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Career employees occupying permanently budgeted full time positions, and who have not completed nine (9) pay periods (four (4) months) of service, shall be entitled to normal Workmen's Compensation benefits for the first fifteen (15) calendar days of disability. If at the end of this period, the employee is not able to return to duty, the employee may receive additional compensation, representing the difference between workmen's compensation and the usual salary, up to an inclusive period of four (4) months.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the employee is not able to return to work at the end of his period of entitlement, the case shall be reviewed by the Personnel Department and the Insurance Management Division. Upon the recommendation of these agencies and the approval of the County Manager, the employee may receive an extended period of entitlement up to another four (4) months. If the individual is a special risk employee as defined by Chapter 121, Florida Statutes, who has been disabled as a result of an assault and battery on his period in the performance of his duties, the employee may receive an additional period of entitlement up to one month. In no case will the total extended period of entitlement exceed five (5) months. If it is decided not to extend the employee beyond his initial period of entitlement, he shall, after using his accrued annual and sick leave, revert to Workmen's Compensation benefits. If the medical prognosis shows that the employee will continue to be disabled, he may apply for, or application may be made for him, for benefits of the extended disability program provided in Sections 2-56.21 through 2-56.27 of the Code.</section></section><section>When it has been determined by medical examination that an employee is able to resume his duties and the employee does not do so, all benefits under this section shall be immediately terminated.</section><section>Disability leave shall not be approved when it is determined by the Insurance and Safety Division and the Personnel Department that the disability occurred through the employee's negligence or willful misconduct. If the employee brings litigation against the County, while receiving Workmen's Compensation, supplemented by disability leave providing full salary, disability leave shall be terminated. The employee may then draw upon accrued vacation and sick leave.</section><section>Effective April 1, 1972, the Finance Department will make provision to pay Workmen's Compensation payments and the disability leave supplement on a single check, which will indicate the amounts attributable to each.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-76, ยง 1, 9-22-71; Ord. No. 75-2, ยง 1, 1-7-75; Ord. No. 79-86, ยง 1, 10-16-79)</history></law>