<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='4'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-56.23</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000241</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>Employee shall mean anyone engaged full time by the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County and who is paid a salary or wage for services rendered provided he has attained permanent status in the classified service or, if exempt, has completed six (6) months' full-time employment prior to the onset of disability.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Long-term disability shall mean a disability of at least eight (8) months' duration, which disability incapacitates an employee from performing the duties of his job classification, and is the proximate result of an accident occurring at some definite time and place while in the actual performance of duty.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Disability leave shall be as defined in the personnel rules of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Disability-date salary shall mean an employees' gross monthly County salary at the time of incurring a disability.</section><section prefix='(e)'>County physician shall mean any physician designated by the Disability Panel.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Disability Panel shall mean a committee composed of the Director of Risk Management, the Director of the Employee Relations Department, a representative of the County Manager's office, a representative of the disabled employee's department, and a representative of the disabled employee's collective bargaining unit, if any.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Disability payments shall mean the payments by the County to an employee with a long-term disability.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Secondary employment shall mean a disabled individual's employment by the County, or other employer, or self-employment.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 69-49, ยง 3, 7-23-69; Ord. No. 05-184, ยง 1, 10-18-05)</history></law>