<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. PERSONNEL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='4'>DIVISION 3. SPECIAL OFF-DUTY POLICE AND FIRE SERVICES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-56.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000179</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 2-56.1. Definitions.<section>When the terms defined in this section are used in this division, they shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section, unless the context of this division expressly provides to the contrary:<section prefix='(a)'>Department shall mean the authorized permit issuing agent(s) of the Miami-Dade Police Department, Fire Department, Corrections and Rehabilitation Department, and the Office of County Manger, respectively, of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Law Enforcement Officer shall mean a certified Law Enforcement Officer of any rank who is a duly appointed employee of the Miami-Dade Police Department.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Correctional Officer shall mean a certified Correctional Officer of any rank who is a duly appointed employee of the Miami-Dade Corrections and Rehabilitation Department.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Off-regular-duty police services shall mean and include any police services rendered by a Law Enforcement Officer or Correctional Officer during a period or periods of time not within the regularly assigned hours of duty except for those police services performed by Correctional Officers on behalf of a state, county or municipal law enforcement agency other than Miami-Dade County pursuant to that agency's supervision and authority and otherwise in accordance with applicable state law. Correctional Officers shall not be considered to be acting within the course and scope of their official duties for Miami Dade County whenever they are performing police work on behalf of any state, county or municipal law enforcement agency other than Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Firefighter shall mean a Fire Officer of any rank who is an employee of the Fire Department.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Off-regular-duty fire prevention and fire inspection services shall mean and include any such services rendered by a Firefighter during a period or periods of time not within his regularly assigned hours of duty.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Permit shall mean a permit issued pursuant to this division.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Permittee shall mean and include any person and/or business concern receiving a permit.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Permit assignment shall mean and include any assignment made by the appropriate department to a Law Enforcement Officer or Correctional Officer to provide any off-regular-duty police services, and shall also be deemed to include any assignment made by or to a Firefighter to provide any off-regular-duty fire prevention or fire inspection services.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 65-56, § 1, 7-27-65; Ord. No. 75-4, § 1, 1-7-75; Ord. No. 76-92, § 1, 10-5-76; Ord. No. 76-112, § 1, 12-21-76; Ord. No. 04-74, § 1, 4-13-04)</history></law>