<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.2.13</section_number>
<catch_line>Mental Health Diversion Facility Capital Expedite Program.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000103</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>Policy. It is the policy of Miami-Dade County and the Eleventh Judicial Circuit in and for Miami-Dade County, Florida, through its Criminal Mental Health Project (referred to in this Section as the "Court") to expedite the delivery of mental health services through the expedited design and construction of the mental health diversion facility located at 2200 NW 7th Avenue, Miami, Florida 33127 (the "Facility"). Expediting the design, construction and improvement of the Facility will also allow for the reduction of the County's jail population by providing for an alternative setting to treat those persons who suffer from serious mental illnesses. For these reasons, the design and construction of the Facility is hereby declared to be a County priority. To advance these policies, Miami-Dade County hereby enacts this Section creating the "Mental Health Diversion Facility Capital Expedite Program". The provisions of this Section shall be liberally construed to accomplish this policy.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Construction Manager. The County shall designate a construction manager (the "Construction Manager"), who shall be principally responsible for overseeing the design and construction of the Facility. The Construction Manager shall be a person experienced in design and construction of major capital facilities, who shall be designated by the Mayor or the Mayor's designee and subject to the approval of the Court. Work related to the Facility shall be the priority of the Construction Manager and he or she may be employed in other projects subject to this limitation. The Construction Manager shall provide a report of the status of the design and construction of the Facility to the Court on a monthly basis.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Construction Team. In the design and construction of the Facility, the Mayor or the Mayor's designee, in consultation with the Construction Manager and the Court, shall designate a team of construction professionals as necessary to supervise the design and construction of the Facility. Work related to the Facility shall be the priority of each member of the team and such members may be employed in other projects subject to this limitation.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Delegation of authority. The Facility shall be subject to the Economic Stimulus Ordinance, codified under Section 2-8.2.7 of this Code, except that there shall be no bid protest as provided in Section 2-8.4 of this Code in connection with the construction of the Facility or the award of any contract for the acquisition of goods or services for the Facility. Accordingly, Section 2-8.2.7(4)(d)(4), providing that the Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall award bids or contracts only where none of the bidders have filed a timely bid protest, shall be inapplicable to the Facility. The appointment of all selection and negotiation committees for the Facility shall contain at least one representative from the Court.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Implementation. The Mayor or the Mayor's designee shall include the provisions necessary to implement this Section in the contract documents related to the Facility.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-93, ยง 1, 10-7-14)</history></law>