<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.2.14</section_number>
<catch_line>Jackson Health System Capital Expedite Program.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000049</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>Policy. It is the policy of Miami-Dade County and the Public Health Trust of Miami-Dade County, Florida (referred to herein as the "Trust") to expedite the delivery of health care throughout Miami-Dade County through the design, construction and improvement of the capital facilities of the Jackson Health System. Expediting the design, construction and improvement of those facilities, through open, competitive and transparent processes will also promote the local economy by creating employment opportunities for Miami-Dade County. To advance these policies, Miami-Dade County hereby enacts this ordinance creating the "Jackson Health System Capital Expedite Program."</section><section prefix='(2)'>Professional Services. The Trust is hereby authorized to create specifications for, advertise, negotiate and award contracts for architecture, professional engineering, landscape architecture, and registered surveying and mapping, and other professional services as defined in Section 287.055 of the Florida Statutes, all in accordance with the procurement policy duly enacted by the Public Health Trust, as the same may be amended from time to time (the "Procurement Policy") and the provisions of law. In particular, and without limitation to the grant of authority in the preceding sentence, the Trust shall be authorized to create within its Procurement Policy provisions for the award of continuing contracts as defined under state law to providers who specialize in health care facilities. The Procurement Policy shall be consistent with the County's policy contained in Section 2-10.4 of this Code except where the Trust determines in its discretion that simplification is in the best interest of the Jackson Health System Capital Expedite Program.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Construction and Design-Build Services. The Trust is hereby authorized to create specifications for, advertise, negotiate and award contracts for construction, construction management, and design-build services, all in accordance with the Procurement Policy and the provisions of law.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Procurement Policy. The Trust is hereby authorized and directed to amend the Procurement Policy as necessary to give effect to this Section. The Procurement Policy shall, at a minimum, contain provisions:<section prefix='(a)'>establishing processes for the award of design, construction and design build contracts, including without limitation, applicable thresholds for the award by the Trust or its executive staff,</section><section prefix='(b)'>governing bid protests where applicable,</section><section prefix='(c)'>establishing the appointment of selection committees, including where appropriate, standing committees,</section><section prefix='(d)'>governing the establishment and disbursement of contract contingency accounts, and</section><section prefix='(e)'>governing the issuance of change orders.</section></section><section>The Procurement Policy and all contract awards pursuant thereto shall at all times comply with all applicable provisions of this Code including, without limitation, the provisions governing Community Business Enterprises and Community Small Business Enterprises or successor programs, which include the requirements that all design and construction contracts be submitted to Small Business Development ("SBD") prior to advertisement for review and assignment of small business measures and that all subsequent amendments and/or change orders must include SBD determination of compliance with applicable goals and responsible wages.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Implementation. The Trust's adoption of the Procurement Policy in its discretion in accordance with this Section shall satisfy any requirement contained in Section 2-10.4 that the Trust adopt rules and procedures to implement that section. Any administrative or implementing order, or part thereof, which is inconsistent with this Section is hereby repealed.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-106, ยง 1, 11-5-14)</history></law>