<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-8.2.12</section_number>
<catch_line>Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department Consent Decree and Capital Improvement Programs Acceleration Ordinance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000102</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>This Section of the Miami-Dade County Code shall be referred to as the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department Consent Decree and Capital Improvement Programs Acceleration Ordinance.<section prefix='(a)'>The Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department Consent Decree Work consists all those projects needed to comply with the Consent Decree approved on April 9, 2014 by the United States District Court for the Southern District of Florida.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department Capital Improvement Program consists of only those projects approved by the Board of County Commissioners as part of the Multi-Year Capital Plan.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The County Mayor or Mayor's designee shall, subject to the funding limitations set forth in the Multi-Year Capital Plan approved by the Board of County Commissioners, be authorized to accelerate the processing, procurement, and award of any contract and agreement of the County for Consent Decree Work and other required Capital Improvements contracts to maintain the operational effectiveness and capacity of the water and sewer systems, including any contracts related to the purchase of goods and services, construction and professional services.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All actions taken under this Ordinance shall be subject to review by the Office of Management and Budget to ensure adequate funding for each project and that appropriate operational and maintenance funding is in place for the foreseeable future and to ensure compliance with contract documents and all applicable resolutions, ordinances, and statutes.</section><section prefix='(4)'>With respect to any Consent Decree Work or other required Capital Improvement Contract, the County Mayor or Mayor's designee is authorized to:<section prefix='(a)'>Draft, Issue or Advertise Invitations to Bid, Requests for Proposals, Requests for Qualifications, Notices to Professional Consultants, or any other competitive procurement document.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Award and reject bids, proposals, or other offers received in connection with any competitive procurement. However, in the event that any proposed award of a contract is protested, the Board of County Commissioners shall award such contract as provided for in Section 2-8.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County and Implementing Order 3-21 governing the bid protest process. Unless previously authorized and delegated, the County Mayor or Mayor's designee may not waive competitive bids in the award of a contract without the approval of the Board of County Commissioners. The authority to award or reject is granted where:<section prefix='i.'>the base value of a recommended award does not exceed the base estimate by more than ten percent (10%); and</section><section prefix='ii.'>the contractor or consulting firm receiving the award has a rating of 2.5 or higher in the Capital Improvement Information System (CIIS) database and has no outstanding debts, no goal deficits, and has submitted required insurance, bonds, affidavits and documentation provided for by the time of award; and</section><section prefix='iii.'>none of the bidders have filed a timely bid protest.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Appoint selection evaluation committees to obtain professional services in accordance with Section 2-10.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County and Section 287.055 of the Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Amend contracts and extend the time for completion of any contract for construction, materials or professional services, including waivers of liquidated damages and other compensable and/or non-compensable time extensions.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Negotiate and settle claims, and issue settlement agreement(s) or change orders for additional work under contracts and amendments where:<section prefix='i.'>the change order or claim does not exceed ten percent (10%) of the base contract amount; and</section><section prefix='ii.'>the contingency allowance shall be utilized to ensure minimal disruption in work flow and shall be documented on the appropriate contingency authorization draw. Change orders shall be submitted to replenish the contingency account in a timely manner; and</section><section prefix='iii.'>the limitations provided in (4)(e)(i) above shall not apply to any change order or amendment related to emergency actions impacting remediation, public safety, health requirements or recovery from natural disaster.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Re-allocate unspent monies among projects within the approved Multi-Year Capital Plan.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Apply for, execute, and receive any federal or state grant in connection with any project, and execute any ancillary documents required to effectuate such grant.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Apply for, execute and enter into joint participation agreements with any local, state or federal government entity for the completion of a project.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Issue and evaluate Requests for Qualifications for Professional Services, if the RFQ and evaluation process is otherwise consistent with Section 2-10.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. In the event that the County Mayor or Mayor's designee is unable to negotiate a contract with the most qualified firm, the County Mayor or Mayor's designee is authorized to negotiate, sequentially, with the remaining firms in order of qualifications. Alternately, the County Mayor or Mayor's designee may at any time reject all qualifications received. Except as noted herein, nothing contained in this Section shall otherwise modify the substantive or procedural requirements of Section 2-10.4 of the Code of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(j)'>All procurement activities advertised or placed for public notice under the authority of this Ordinance shall be reported to the Infrastructure and Capital Improvements Committee (or the applicable committee to which the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department matters are assigned) at the next available meeting for Committee review and approval. The Committee shall have the authority to require that specific projects be removed from the authority granted under this Ordinance and that the award of such projects be subject to future Committee and Board approval. After being reported to the applicable Committee, all procurement activities advertised or placed for public notice under the authority of this Ordinance shall be reported to the Board at the next Board meeting following the report to the Committee.</section><section prefix='(k)'>In addition to the reporting requirement set forth in Section (4)(j) above, the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department shall also request that, at the Chair of the Board's discretion, a discussion item pertaining to the overall procurement activities of the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Department be placed on the agenda of the full Board on a quarterly basis.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>The Mayor or Mayor's designee shall provide a report to the Board of County Commissioners on the status of Consent Decree Work and other required Capital Improvement projects at least every thirty (30) days. The report shall at a minimum identify upcoming advertisement for contracts, their estimated contract value, qualifications for award beyond requisite licensing, and the proposed methodology for award. With respect to each contract award, the report shall also provide proposed contract measures, including Small Business Enterprise (SBE) goals and Community Business Enterprise (CBE) goals. Upon review of the report, the Board may by resolution duly adopted limit or condition the advertisement, award or other rights conferred upon the Mayor or Mayor's designee under this Section for specific projects.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Any act undertaken pursuant to the authority set forth in this Ordinance is subject to ratification by the Board of County Commissioners and shall be brought directly to the Board at the next available meeting and will not be subject to the 4-Day Rule. Any resolution ratifying an act undertaken pursuant to the authority set forth in this Ordinance shall include an effective date provision that provides that it will become effective upon approval by the County Mayor of the resolution and the filing of the Mayor's approval with the Clerk of the Board, which approval may be provided before the expiration of the ten (10) day mayoral veto period. Any contract, change order, settlement, modification, adjustment, or extension granted pursuant to any authority herein shall contain a termination for convenience clause or such other provision as necessary to specify that the action is revocable if not ratified by the Board of County Commissioners. The specification shall also include a sufficient release such that, in the event that the Board of County Commissioners does not ratify such item, the contractor is not entitled to lost profits or other consequential or indirect damages; however, the contractor is eligible for payment for any work done prior to failure of the ratification.</section><section prefix='(7)'>The powers conferred in this Ordinance shall be supplemental to, and not in derogation of, any other powers or authority granted elsewhere in any ordinance, statute or resolution.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-77, ยง 1, 9-3-14)</history></law>