<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='2'>Chapter 2 ADMINISTRATION</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00079' order_by='00079' level='3'>ARTICLE LXIII. MIAMI-DADE COUNTY BLACK AFFAIRS ADVISORY BOARD</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>2-832</section_number>
<catch_line>Composition.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000000740</order_by>
<text><section>The Miami-Dade County Black Affairs Advisory Board ("the board"), in accordance with the provisions of of the Code of Miami-Dade County as may be amended, shall be composed of twenty-six (26) members who shall be permanent residents and electors of the County and who shall have a knowledge and interest in the County's Black community. Each County Commissioner shall appoint one member of the board. The other thirteen (13) members shall be nominated by a nominating committee.</section><section>The nominating committee shall be comprised of existing members of the board. The board shall develop procedures for the creation of the nominating committee in its bylaws. The nominating committee shall recommend potential members for appointment by the Black Affairs Advisory Board, subject to compliance with the requirements of(b) of the Code of Miami-Dade County, as may be amended, including the requirement relating to criminal history background checks on potential advisory board members performed by the Office of the Inspector General and compliance with the requirements of Resolution No. R-636-14, as may be amended, pertaining to background research on potential advisory board members performed by the Office of the Commission Auditor. The board shall work with the Office of Community Advocacy or successor department to advertise vacancies occurring on the Black Affairs Advisory Board in publications of general circulation and maintain an online application to generate a pool of potential members for the nominating committee's consideration.</section><section>Notwithstanding any other provision of the Code of Miami-Dade County, a board member shall be automatically removed if, in a given County fiscal year: the member is absent from two (2) consecutive meetings without an acceptable excuse or the member is absent from three (3) of the board's meetings without an acceptable excuse. An 'acceptable excuse' is defined as an absence for medical reasons, business reasons, personal reasons, or any other reason which the board, by a two-thirds () vote of its membership, deems appropriate. If a member is absent with an acceptable excuse from three (3) or more meetings, the board may vote to remove the member from the board.</section><section>A member shall be considered absent from a meeting if the member is not physically present for at least seventy-five (75) percent of the meeting's duration. A member shall also be considered absent from a meeting if the member refrains from voting on any matter for which voting is conducted at the meeting, unless the member is prevented from voting by a conflict of interest. The provisions of the Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance, as may be amended, are applicable to this board.</section><section>All appointments shall be made for a term of four (4) years. This section shall apply to all board members, except that current board members shall be allowed to complete their current terms.</section><section>Notwithstanding(b) of the Miami-Dade County Code, a Commissioner may reappoint an existing member to serve in excess of the eight (8) year term limit, provided that said member has demonstrated exceptional dedication and service to the board and that the reappointment is presented to the Board of County Commissioners in the form of a resolution and approved by a two-thirds () vote of the full membership of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-137, ยง 2, 7-12-94; Ord. No. 09-54, ยง 1, 6-30-09; Ord. No. 14-109, ยง 1, 11-5-14)</history></law>