<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. MINORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-13.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Possession or purchase by minors of electronic cigarettes and other nicotine dispensing devices prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003073</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>For the purpose of this section, "Nicotine dispensing devices" shall mean any product that can be used to deliver nicotine to an individual by inhaling vaporized nicotine from the product, whether or not such vapor actually includes nicotine, including, but not limited to, an electronic cigarette, electronic cigar, electronic cigarillo, electronic pipe, or other similar device or product and any replacement nicotine cartridge for the device or product.</section><section prefix='(b)'>It is unlawful for any person under 18 years of age to knowingly purchase or possess an electronic cigarette or other nicotine dispensing device.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any person violating this section shall be punished by a fine of twenty-five dollars ($25.00) for the first offense; fifty dollars ($50.00) for the second offense and one hundred dollars ($100.00) for each subsequent offense. In addition to any other penalties provided by law, a violation of any provision of this section shall constitute a civil offense punishable by the applicable civil penalty provided in the schedule of civil penalties pursuant to Chapter 8CC of the Code and the remedies contained in Article III of Chapter 8A of the Code.</section><section prefix='(d)'>This section shall be applicable in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, with the enforcement of the provision of this section in the unincorporated area being the responsibility of Miami-Dade County and in the incorporated area being the responsibility of the respective municipalities.</section><section prefix='(e)'>If the Florida Legislature amends state law to prohibit minors from knowingly purchasing or possessing electronic cigarettes or other nicotine dispensing devices, then upon the effective date of such enactment, the provisions of this ordinance addressed shall no longer be deemed effective.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-55, ยง 2, 6-3-14)</history></law>