<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. WEAPONS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='4'>DIVISION 3. ELECTRONIC CONTROL DEVICES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-20.22</section_number>
<catch_line>Unlawful to sell electronic control devices to persons who have not had mandatory training on the proper use of electronic control devices.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003039</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-20.22. Unlawful to sell electronic control devices to persons who have not had mandatory training on the proper use of electronic control devices.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to acquire an electronic control device in Miami-Dade County unless such person has received safety instruction and is otherwise qualified, pursuant to this section, or unless he is specifically exempted from the operation of this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In order to qualify under this section the purchaser must complete the training course offered by the manufacturer of the electronic control device or any other instructor certified by the manufacturer. Persons who have successfully completed the training course offered by the manufacturer in the course of purchasing an electronic control device shall not be required to repeat the training in any given year in order to purchase another electronic control device.</section><section prefix='(c)'>This section shall not apply to:<section prefix='(1)'>Law enforcement officers or agents of any state of the United States, or any political subdivision, municipal corporation, department or agency of either, members of the organized militia of any state for the armed forces of the United States, or law enforcement officers of any political subdivision, municipal corporation, department or agency of either, while engaged in the discharge of their official duties.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Wholesale dealers in their business intercourse with retail dealers or retail dealers in their business intercourse with other retail dealers or to wholesale or retail dealers in the regular or ordinary transportation of electronic control devices by mail, express or other mode of shipment to points outside the country.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Nonresidents of the United States having proper authorization from his or her consulate, acting consulate, commercial attache, or such other authorized representative.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-201, ยง 1, 11-3-05)</history></law>