<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. WEAPONS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='4'>DIVISION 3. ELECTRONIC CONTROL DEVICES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-20.21</section_number>
<catch_line>Five-day Waiting Period and Criminal History Records Check on Electronic Control Device Sales.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000002983</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-20.21. Five-day Waiting Period and Criminal History Records Check on Electronic Control Device Sales.<section prefix='(a)'>Application and enforcement of section. Law enforcement officers shall have the right to enforce the provisions of this section against any person found violating these provisions within their jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Sale and delivery of electronic control devices; mandatory five-day waiting period. There shall be a mandatory five-day waiting period, which shall be five full days, excluding weekends and legal holidays, between the hour of the sale and the hour of the delivery of any electronic control device when any part of the transaction is conducted within Miami-Dade County on property to which the public has the right of access.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Sale and delivery of electronic control devices; mandatory criminal records check. No person, whether licensed or unlicensed, shall sell, offer for sale, transfer or deliver any electronic control device to another person when any part of the transaction is conducted on property to which the public has the right of access within Miami-Dade County unless the buyer or the transferee has undergone the criminal history and background check procedures specified under section 790.065, Florida Statutes (2005) and has been provided with a unique approval number.</section><section>In the case of a seller who is not a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer, compliance with section 790.065 or its state or federal successor shall be achieved by the seller requesting that a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer complete all the requirements of section 790.065 or its state or federal successor. Licensed importers, manufacturers and dealers may charge a reasonable fee of an unlicensed seller to cover costs associated with completing the requirements of section 790.065.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Records available for inspection. Records of electronic control device sales must be available for inspection by any law enforcement officer as defined in section 934.02(6), Florida Statutes (2005).</section><section prefix='(e)'>Exemptions. Holders of a concealed weapons permit as prescribed by state law and holders of an active certification from the Criminal Justice Standards and Training officer, or a correctional probation officer as set forth in state law shall not be subject to the provisions of this section.</section><section>Sales to a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer shall not be subject to the provisions of this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-201, ยง 1, 11-3-05)</history></law>