<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00020' order_by='00020' level='3'>ARTICLE XIX. BOATING SAFETY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-287</section_number>
<catch_line>Rafting.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003286</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>The intent and purpose of this section is to establish rafting restrictions on any waters lying within the boundaries of Miami-Dade County to improve public safety. This section shall not apply to vessels on the Florida Intracoastal Waterway.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Definitions.<section prefix='(1)'>Florida Intracoastal Waterway shall have the meaning ascribed to it in section 327.02, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Rafting shall mean vessels that are tied together or otherwise attached to other vessels when the proximity between each tied or otherwise attached vessel is five feet or less.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Vessel shall have the meaning ascribed to it in section 327.02, Florida Statutes.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Prohibited. It is unlawful for the operator of any vessel to participate in the rafting of vessels on any waters lying within the boundaries of Miami-Dade County, other than the Florida Intracoastal Waterway, as restricted in this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>No more than five vessels may engage in rafting with each other. Such groups of rafting vessels must maintain separation of no less than 30 feet from other groups of rafting vessels.</section><section prefix='(e)'>To the extent regulation of anchoring is permitted by Florida law, when three or more vessels engage in rafting with each other, the outer vessels shall not be permitted to anchor.</section><section>Violations of this section may be punished by:<section prefix='(1)'>A fine not to exceed $250.00;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Repeat offenders may be imprisoned in the County jail for a period not to exceed 30 days;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Both such fine and imprisonment in the discretion of the court having jurisdiction over the cause;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Fines in accordance with Chapter 8CC of the Code of Miami-Dade County; or</section><section prefix='(5)'>Completion of the Miami-Dade County Diversion Program, pursuant to the County's Implementing Order No. 2-12.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 15-36, ยง 1, 5-5-15)</history></law>