<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. WEAPONS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00019' order_by='00019' level='4'>DIVISION 2. LICENSE TO SELL FIREARMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-20.18</section_number>
<catch_line>Five-day waiting period and criminal history records check on firearms sales.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003090</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 21-20.18. Five-day waiting period and criminal history records check on firearms sales.<section prefix='(a)'>Definitions. For purposes of this section, the following terms shall be defined as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>Any part of the transaction means any part of the sales transaction, including but not limited to, the offer of sale, negotiations, the agreement to sell, the transfer of consideration, or the transfer of the firearm.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Antique firearms means any firearm (including any firearm with a matchlock, flintlock, percussion cap, or similar type of ignition system) manufactured in or before 1898; and any replica of any such firearm if such replica (i) is not designed or redesigned for using rimfire or conventional centerfire fixed ammunition, or (ii) uses rimfire or conventional centerfire fixed ammunition which is no longer manufactured in the United States and which is not readily available in the ordinary channels of commercial trade.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Firearm means any weapon which will, is designed to, or may readily be converted to expel a projectile by the action of an explosive; the frame or receiver of any such weapon; and firearm muffler or firearm silencer; any destructive device; or any machine gun. Such term does not include an antique firearm.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Property to which the public has the right of access means any real or personal property to which the public has a right of access, including property owned by either public or private individuals, firms and entities and expressly includes, but is not limited to, flea markets, gun shows and firearms exhibitions.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Sale means the transfer of money or other valuable consideration.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Application and enforcement of section. Law enforcement officers shall have the right to enforce the provisions of this section against any person found violating these provisions within their jurisdiction.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Sale and delivery of firearms; mandatory five-day waiting period. There shall be a mandatory five-day waiting period, which shall be five full days, excluding weekends and legal holidays, between the hour of the sale and the hour of the delivery of any firearm when any part of the transaction is conducted within Miami-Dade County on property to which the public has the right of access.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Sale and delivery of firearms; mandatory criminal records check. No person, whether licensed or unlicensed, shall sell, offer for sale, transfer or deliver any firearm to another person when any part of the transaction is conducted on property to which the public has the right of access within Miami-Dade County until all procedures specified under section 790.065, Florida Statutes, have been complied with by a person authorized by that section to conduct a criminal history check of background information as specified in that section, and the approval number set forth by that section has been obtained and documented. Upon the repeal of section 790.065, Florida Statutes, no person, whether licensed or unlicensed, shall sell, offer for sale, transfer or deliver any firearm to another person when any part of the transaction is conducted on property to which the public has the right of access until all procedures specified under any other state or federal law which requires a national criminal history information or national criminal history check on potential buyer or transferee of firearms have been complied with by any person authorized by law to conduct the required national criminal history or background records check and any required approval under such state or federal law or rule has been obtained. "Person" for purposes of this subsection shall include any person, including, but not limited to a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer and any unlicensed person.</section><section>In the case of a seller who is not a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer, compliance with section 790.065 or its state or federal successor shall be achieved by the seller requesting that a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer complete all the requirements of section 790.065 or its state or federal successor. Licensed importers, manufacturers and dealers may charge a reasonable fee of an unlicensed seller to cover costs associated with completing the requirements of section 790.065.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Exemptions. Holders of a concealed weapons permit as prescribed by state law and holders of an active certification from the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission as a law enforcement officer, a correctional officer, or a correctional probation officer as set forth in state law shall not be subject to the provisions of this section.</section><section>Sales to a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer shall not be subject to the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Penalties. Any person violating any provision of this section shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) or by imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days in the County Jail, or by both such fine and imprisonment. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to preempt the imposition of any higher penalties imposed by state or federal law.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Reporting of information. To the fullest extent permissible by law, all information acquired in relation to a violation of this section shall be reported to appropriate federal and state officials.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 98-169, ยง 1, 12-1-98)</history></law>