<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='2'>Chapter 21 OFFENSES AND MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. MISCELLANEOUS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>21-36.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Roadway solicitation by minors; applicable area; adult supervision required; permissible hours; prohibition at enumerated roadways; penalty for section violation.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003084</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>Minor solicitor or collector shall mean any person under the age of eighteen (18) years who sells or offers for sale any thing or any service of any kind, or who seeks to solicit or collect any donation of any kind, or who personally hands to or seeks to transmit by hand or receive by hand any thing or service of any kind, whether or not payment in exchange is required or requested, to any person or organization who operates or occupies a motor vehicle of any kind, which vehicle is engaged in travel on or within any portion of any of the streets or roadways in the County, whether or not such vehicle is temporarily stopped in the travel lanes of the road. The term shall not apply to any person who merely holds or displays a sign lawfully permitted to be displayed by a person, as long as there is no entry by such person or sign into any portion of the roadway or its median. Further, this term shall not apply to official citations or notices provided pursuant to governmental authority.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Applicable area. This section shall be applicable only in the unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Accompaniment by adult. Any minor solicitor or collector must be accompanied by an adult at all times on any public right-of-way or roadway.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Permissible hours. It shall be unlawful for a minor solicitor or collector to operate between the hours of 9:00 p.m. and 9:00 a.m.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Prohibited roadways. No accompanying adult, minor solicitor, or minor collector may stand or walk within any public right-of-way, including sidewalks, bike paths, and medians within two hundred and fifty (250) feet of the following intersections for any of the purposes listed in Section 21-36.2(a). Two-hundred and fifty (250) feet is measured from the lateral curb or boundary line of the below listed intersections:<section prefix='(1)'>SW 137th Avenue&amp;SW 152nd Street</section><section prefix='(2)'>SW 107th Avenue&amp;SW 16th Street</section><section prefix='(3)'>NW 27th Avenue&amp;NW 79th Street</section><section prefix='(4)'>SW 117th Avenue&amp;SW 104th Street</section><section prefix='(5)'>SW 117th Avenue&amp;SW 72nd Street</section><section prefix='(6)'>SW 137th Avenue&amp;SW 56th Street</section><section prefix='(7)'>NW 7th Avenue&amp;NW 103rd Street</section><section prefix='(8)'>SW 117th Avenue&amp;SW 152nd Street</section><section prefix='(9)'>NW 67th Avenue&amp;NW 169th Street</section><section prefix='(10)'>NW 72nd Avenue&amp;NW 12th Street</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Revisions. The Board of County Commissioners shall have the continuing authority to update, amend, or revise the list of ten intersections enumerated in subsection (e) by resolution as often as needed, but must update the list every ten (10) years at a minimum from the effective date of this Section.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Chapter 316, Florida Statutes. The enforcement of this section shall not, in any way, preclude the enforcement of Fla. Stat. § 316.130(3)—(5), as applicable.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Enforcement. It shall be the duty of all County officers to enforce the provisions of this section. Any person who violates this section shall be prosecuted before a court of competent jurisdiction and subject, upon conviction, to the penalties listed in Section 21-36.2(i) and within the discretion of the county judge.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Penalties. Any person convicted of a violation of the provisions of this section may be punished by:<section prefix='(1)'>A first violation of this section: a verbal warning or reprimand.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Subsequent violations of this section: a fine of not more than thirty dollars ($30.00) and/or imposition of community service hours or required participation in after-school programs.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-78, § 1, 9-3-14)</history></law>