<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='4'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-16</section_number>
<catch_line>Construction of waste water facility or air pollution abatement facility, or potable water facility.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003265</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>After approval of an application, the person causing the installation or construction of the project or facility shall furnish the Director or the Director's designee with monthly reports of a registered engineer certifying that the work to date has been accomplished in strict compliance with the approved plans, drawings and specifications and that there has been no major or substantial deviation therefrom. If during construction, changes are proposed which would materially alter the quality characteristics of the effluent of a waste water facility, or which would materially alter the emission of air pollutants of an air pollution abatement facility or would materially alter the quality characteristics of the effluent of a potable water facility, then plans and specifications for such changes prepared by a registered engineer shall be submitted to the Director or the Director's designee for approval before making such changes. The Director shall have the right at any reasonable time to enter upon the project for the purpose of making inspections of the work, and may require reports and additional information at any stage of construction.</section><section prefix='(2)'>It shall be unlawful for any person causing the installation or construction of the project or facility to deviate from the conditions of the approval of the Director or the Director's designee without the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>