<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-13</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure governing variances and extensions of time.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003258</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-13. Procedure governing variances and extensions of time.<section>Applications for variances or extensions of time for compliance with this chapter shall be filed with the Director in substantially the form prescribed therefor. The Director shall make written recommendations concerning such applications and promptly file the records with the Environmental Quality Control Board. Upon request by any applicant for a variance from the regulations of, the Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee shall also make written recommendations concerning such applications and promptly file the recommendations with the Environmental Quality Control Board. The Director may initiate and file with the Board an application for variance or extension. Upon receipt of an application and the recommendations of the Director and upon receipt of the recommendations of the Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee, where applicable, the Board shall promptly hold a public hearing upon the application, after publication of notice of the hearing. All interested persons shall be entitled to be heard before the Board. The Board shall promptly hear and pass upon all such applications, and shall set forth the grounds and reasons for granting or denying the application. Any person aggrieved by any decision of the Environmental Quality Control Board shall be entitled to judicial review in accordance with the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure. The Board shall prescribe rules of procedure governing applications for variances or extensions of time, which shall conform to and be commensurate with the applicable and controlling provisions of this chapter. For purposes of this section, the County Manager may constitute a person aggrieved whenever the Environmental Quality Control Board renders a decision adverse to the recommendation of the Director.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>