<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Plan approval required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003356</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-15. Plan approval required.<section prefix='(1)'>Intent. It is the intent and purpose of this section to require that all new facilities, equipment and processes constructed or operated after the effective date of this chapter shall comply with the requirements herein contained, and that any major or substantial enlargement, expansion or addition to existing facilities also shall comply with the requirements herein contained. Any building permit issued by the County or a municipality in violation of the provisions of this chapter is hereby determined to be void.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Waste water facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to enter into or let a contract for or to commence the installation, extension, or operation of any sewerage system or waste treatment facility or any industrial waste disposal facility without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. It shall be unlawful for any person to make any enlargement, alteration or addition to any facility, or commence the construction of any facility, that will reasonably be expected to be a source of water pollution without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. No building permit involving the generation or discharge of effluents shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application for a building permit has been approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>The provisions of this section shall not apply to facilities discharging only domestic wastes to a public sewer system approved by the Director or the Director's designee. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the provisions of this section shall apply to facilities discharging only domestic wastes to a public sewer system approved by the Director or the Director's designee if the facilities provide any form of pretreatment in conjunction with a grease trap.</section><section>Provided that after January 25, 1974, the Director shall not approve an application for an interim package sewage treatment plant unless directed to do so by the Environmental Quality Control Board after a public hearing pursuant to notice.</section><section>For the purpose of this subsection, an interim package sewage treatment plant shall include all domestic waste water treatment facilities that are not included in the regional treatment system as described in the approved 1973 Water Quality Management Plan.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Air facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to make any major or substantial alteration, enlargement or addition to any existing facility, equipment or operation, or to commence the construction or operation of any new facility, that may be a source of air pollution as herein defined, without first obtaining the prior written approval of the plans, equipment or processes thereof by the Director or the Director's designee. No building permit shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application therefor or the plans for construction of the proposed facility have been approved by the Director or the Director's designee. The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to individual family dwellings or multiple-family dwellings of not more than four (4) units in respect to heating equipment or comfort space heating.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Potable water facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to enter into or let a contract for or to commence the installation, extension, alteration or operation of any public water supply facility without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director. No building permit involving a demand on a public water supply shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application for a building permit or plans for construction thereof have been approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Aboveground storage facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to install, repair, modify, expand, replace or permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the installation, repair, modification, expansion or replacement of any aboveground storage facility, without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. No building permit shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application therefor or the plans for construction of the proposed aboveground storage facility show the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Underground storage facilities. It shall be unlawful for any person to install, repair, modify, expand, replace or permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the installation, repair, modification, expansion or replacement of any underground storage facility, without first obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. No building permit shall be issued by the County or any municipality unless the application or the plans for construction of the proposed underground storage facility have been approved in writing by the Director or the Director's designee. The Director, or the Director's designee, shall issue such written approval only upon receipt of formal engineering plans, which are signed and sealed by a professional engineer registered in the State of Florida and which plans detail that the underground storage facilities specified in said plans shall be constructed in compliance with the requirements of this Chapter, Chapter 62-761 of the Florida Administrative Code and the referenced standards contained therein. After receipt of written approval from the Director, or the Director's designee, the owner or operator of the underground storage facility shall notify the Department a minimum of two (2) working days prior to the commencement of installation, repair, modification, expansion or replacement of any underground storage facility. The installation, repair, modification, expansion or replacement shall be subject to inspection by the Department to determine compliance with the approved plans and applicable laws and ordinances.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 05-196, § 2, 11-3-05; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>