<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Statements of approved water or sewer service; Emergency water and/or sewer rate requests.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003355</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-14. Statements of approved water or sewer service; Emergency water and/or sewer rate requests.<section prefix='(1)'>Any public utility holding a valid certificate pursuant to Sections 32-33 and 32-39 of the Code that desires to apply for a change of rate or to change any rule or regulation as provided by Section 32-64 shall file with the Board or the Department a request for a statement of approved water quality or approved sewage service.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Department shall within ten (10) days from the date of such request set a hearing date for consideration by the Board of such request in all cases not exempted under subsection (3), below.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A municipal public utility is exempted from the herein described public hearing process before the Board if both of the following conditions are met:<section prefix='(a)'>The utility holds a valid County operating permit pursuant to Section 24-18, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Not more than twenty (20) percent of the utility's gross revenues are generated from customers located outside of the municipality.</section></section><section>If the utility obtains an exemption by having met the above two (2) conditions, said utility must obtain a statement of approval from the Department.</section><section prefix='(4)'>In determining whether or not a public utility is entitled to a statement of approved water quality or approved sewer service, the Board shall consider the water and effluent quality requirements of Chapter 24 and other evidence including public comments regarding the overall quality of service. If the Board finds that the utility has provided reasonable and satisfactory water quality and sewage service to the public, it shall issue its statement of approved water quality or approved sewage service which shall be valid for one (1) year from the date of issuance. The validity of the statement may be extended by the Board for a period not to exceed six (6) months beyond the original expiration date. Such a statement shall also indicate "excellent," "good" or "fair" quality of service depending on which, in the opinion of the Board, is most appropriate.</section><section prefix='(5)'>The public utility shall send a written notice to each customer informing:<section prefix='(a)'>That the utility plans to file for a rate increase;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The date, time and place of public hearing as set by the Department;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The name, address and phone number of the Department; and</section><section prefix='(d)'>The name, address and phone number of the consumer advocate.</section></section><section>The notice shall be reviewed and approved by the Department and shall be mailed at least twenty (20) days prior to the hearing. In the event that the hearing on the matter is continued, mailed notices of the continuation may be disposed with by the Board.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Board may issue a conditional certificate pursuant to this section if it determines that certain improvements of said water and/or sewer utility are necessary or desirable to increase the quality of service provided to the consumers, and said conditions and improvements shall be specifically set out within said Board order granting the conditional certificate. In no event, however, shall the Water and Sewer Board grant any rate increase to said utility without requiring that the amounts collected from such rate increase be placed in escrow account under Water and Sewer Board control and not released until the conditions set forth in said conditional approval have been complied with by the utility. However, the Board or the Department may not issue its approval of the water or sewer service provided by a water and/or sewer utility if it does not meet the minimum requirements of Chapter 24.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Notwithstanding the requirements of this Section the Board may grant a qualified statement of approval of water or sewer service which shall be sufficient to permit the utility to apply to the Water and Sewer Board for an emergency rate increase solely for the purpose of permitting immediate repairs and improvements necessary to bring water or sewer service and quality to minimum standards. Said qualified approval will authorize the filing of an application for a change in rates as required by Section 32-64 of the Code, but qualified approvals received pursuant to this section will only support a temporary rate increase for such time as is necessary to finance the approved or authorized improvements required to achieve minimum water and/or sewage service quality, as noted above. In no event, however, shall the rate increase be imposed in excess of the life expectancy of the particular improvement or improvements so constructed. In addition, any rate increase granted pursuant to a statement issued under this section shall be used solely and exclusively by the utility for the purpose of improving its water or sewer service to the minimum standards required under the Miami-Dade County Code. Said repairs and improvements shall be specifically set out within said order granting the qualified statement of approval. Any approved rate increase pursuant to this section shall terminate when sufficient funds to finance the repairs and improvements have been collected from the rate increase. Statements of qualified approval may be granted by the Board only when the Board finds that:<section prefix='(a)'>Water service and/or sewage service is below minimum acceptable standards either as to the quality of water and/or sewage treatment or the quality of service for same.</section><section prefix='(b)'>That an emergency exists as to the quality of water or water service available to the public or quality of sewage treatment or sewer service available to the public.</section><section prefix='(c)'>That a temporary rate increase may be required to remedy the immediate problem of inadequate quality or service or treatment.</section><section prefix='(d)'>That no other reasonable adequate means exists for improving the quality of service or the quality of water and/or sewage treatment.</section></section><section>The provisions of this Section requiring notice of hearing shall also be required for any utility applying under this emergency section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>