<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-19</section_number>
<catch_line>Operation of facility; competent supervision.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003252</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-19. Operation of facility; competent supervision.<section prefix='(1)'>The owners or operators of each facility or project installed or constructed under the provisions of this chapter shall provide competent and responsible personnel for the operation thereof in order that the requirements of this chapter shall be observed and complied with in respect to the operation of such facility or project. Competent personnel shall be construed to mean a person or persons who have experience or knowledge concerning the proper operation of the particular facility involved, and a knowledge of the basic scientific principles relating to the proper operation of waste treatment plants and collection systems, or a knowledge of the basic scientific principles relating to the proper operation of facilities causing emissions of air contaminants from incineration, salvage, heat transfer, general combustion, or other operations of a similar nature, as the case may be. The names and qualifications of the supervisory personnel responsible for the proper operation of such facilities shall be furnished to the Director or the Director's designee upon request.</section><section prefix='(2)'>All sewage treatment plants shall be operated under the direct supervision of a qualified sewage treatment plant operator who must hold a minimum of a class "C" operator's license issued by the State of Florida and/or any higher level of certification as required by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection. All operation reports submitted pursuant to this chapter shall be signed by the licensed operator, which signature shall be a verification by said operator of the authenticity of said report.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All potable water treatment plants shall be operated under the direct supervision of a qualified water treatment plant operator who must hold a minimum of a class "C" operator's license issued by the State of Florida. In addition, all public water supplies which provide adequate protection by treatment for an effluent which exceeds ten (10) MGD shall be operated under the direct supervision of a qualified water treatment plant operator who must hold a minimum of a class "A" operator's license issued by the State of Florida. All operation reports submitted pursuant to this chapter shall be signed by the licensed operator, which signature shall be a verification by said operator of the authenticity of said report.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>