<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-15.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure for approval of plans.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003245</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-15.1. Procedure for approval of plans.<section prefix='(1)'>APPLICATION FOR APPROVAL. Application for approval of plans required hereunder shall be made on forms prescribed for such purpose and filed with the Director. Such application shall be signed by the person seeking to install, extend or alter the facility involved or a duly authorized representative vested with lawful power to bind the applicant. Upon receipt of such application and supporting data, the Director shall review all data and render a decision on the acceptability of the facility.</section><section prefix='(2)'>REQUIRED INFORMATION. Each such application shall be accompanied by the following data and information:<section prefix='(a)'>Report of engineer. A comprehensive engineer's report describing the project, the basis of design including design data, and all other pertinent data necessary to give an accurate understanding of the work to be undertaken and the reason therefor. Such report shall contain a certificate of a registered engineer certifying that in the professional opinion of such registered engineer the facility or project will fully comply with the requirements of this chapter and the rules and regulations promulgated hereunder, and will not cause or tend to cause any pollution as herein defined.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Blueprints. Blueprints or white prints of the drawings of the work to be done in sufficient detail necessary to make it clear to the contractor constructing the facility or project exactly what work is to be accomplished.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Specifications. Complete specifications in sufficient detail necessary to supplement the drawings and specify the work and the methods by which it is to be accomplished.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Processes. A description of all processes proposed to be utilized in connection with the operation of the facility or project sufficient to indicate whether or not such processes will reasonably comply with the requirements of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Additional data. Such additional data and information as may be reasonably required by the Director or the Director's designee, including, but not limited to, Baseline Monitoring Reports, Compliance Reports, or any report required for compliance pursuant to the Federal Pretreatment Regulations.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>