<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Operating permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003306</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-18. Operating permits.<section prefix='(A)'>Permit Required No person shall operate, maintain or permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the operation or maintenance of a public water system, public sewerage system, location at which a site rehabilitation action has been completed in accordance with the provisions set forth in Section 24-44(2)(k)(ii) or any of the following facilities, all of which will reasonably be expected to be a source of air pollution, ground pollution or water pollution, without a valid operating permit issued by the Director or the Director's designee or in violation of any condition, limitation or restriction which is part of an operating permit:<section prefix='(1)'>Interim package sewage treatment plants;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Interim package water treatment plants;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Private sewage pumping station;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Facilities which generate, dispose of, store, use, discharge, handle or reclaim any liquid waste other than domestic sewage, any hazardous waste or any hazardous material (except factory prepackaged products intended primarily for domestic use or consumption), including, but not limited to, the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Industrial and agricultural waste reclaim systems; waste or product holding tanks; or waste or product spill prevention control systems;</section><section prefix='(b)'>Industrial and agricultural waste pretreatment facilities;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Industrial and agricultural waste treatment facilities;</section><section prefix='(d)'>The following industrial and agricultural liquid waste facilities:<section prefix='(i)'>Aircraft, vehicle, construction equipment, and boat mechanical maintenance or repair facilities including, but not limited to, engine and electric motor maintenance and repair, and facilities which perform maintenance or repair of any component parts of aircraft, vehicles, boats, or construction equipment;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Chemical manufacturing, packaging, repackaging, storage, or distribution facilities;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Pest control facilities;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Photographic processing facilities or laboratories;</section><section prefix='(v)'>Printing facilities;</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Paint manufacturing, distribution, and product testing; paint research laboratory facilities;</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Battery manufacturing; battery reclaiming facilities; battery refurbishing facilities;</section><section prefix='(viii)'>Hospitals;</section><section prefix='(ix)'>Medical, research or chemical laboratories;</section><section prefix='(x)'>Animal hospitals; animal clinics, and animal grooming facilities;</section><section prefix='(xi)'>Plastics manufacturing facilities;</section><section prefix='(xii)'>Anodizing facilities;</section><section prefix='(xiii)'>Silk screening and silk printing facilities;</section><section prefix='(xiv)'>Junk yards;</section><section prefix='(xv)'>Jewelry manufacturing and repair facilities;</section><section prefix='(xvi)'>Machine shops;</section><section prefix='(xvii)'>Construction contractor's facilities handling hazardous materials;</section><section prefix='(xviii)'>Funeral homes;</section><section prefix='(xix)'>Agricultural field packing facilities;</section><section prefix='(xx)'>Stationary agricultural packinghouses;</section><section prefix='(xxi)'>Aerial pesticide applicators (crop-dusters);</section><section prefix='(xxii)'>Dry cleaning facilities;</section><section prefix='(xxiii)'>Textile dyeing facilities;</section><section prefix='(xxiv)'>Vehicle paint and body shops;</section><section prefix='(xxv)'>Metal recycling facilities;</section></section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, nonresidential land uses which are served or will be served by a liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method or those nonresidential land uses which use, generate, handle, dispose of, discharge or store hazardous materials, on any portion of the property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, nonresidential land uses which are served or will be served by any liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method (other than public sanitary sewers) or those nonresidential land uses which use, generate, handle, dispose of, discharge or store hazardous materials, on any portion of the property within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, Hialeah Wellfield or within the outer protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Resource recovery and management facilities;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Facilities that will reasonably be expected to be a source of air pollution; provided, however, the operation of heating equipment or comfort space heating within individual facility dwellings or multiple family dwellings of not more than four (4) units is exempt from the requirement of obtaining a permit pursuant to this section;</section><section prefix='(9)'>All commercial boat docking facilities. Operating permits shall be required for all such facilities no later than May 17, 1990;</section><section prefix='(10)'>All boat storage facilities contiguous to the tidal waters of Miami-Dade County with a total of ten (10) or more dry storage spaces. Operating permits shall be required for all such facilities no later than May 17, 1990;</section><section prefix='(11)'>All recreational boat docking facilities with a total of ten (10) or more boat slips, moorings, davit spaces, and vessel tieup spaces. Operating permits shall be required for all such facilities no later than May 17, 1990;</section><section prefix='(12)'>Underground storage facilities;</section><section prefix='(13)'>Aboveground storage facilities;</section><section prefix='(14)'>Loading facilities;</section><section prefix='(15)'>Balanced systems utilized by motor vehicle fuel service stations;</section><section prefix='(16)'>Vacuum assist systems utilized by motor vehicle fuel service stations;</section><section prefix='(17)'>Any facility which sells or distributes or which offers to sell or distribute any refrigerant or which recharges or causes, lets, allows, permits, or suffers the recharging of refrigerant into any refrigeration system;</section><section prefix='(18)'>Any nonresidential facility, including, but not limited to, restaurants, bakeries, hotel and cafeteria kitchens, processing plants or such other nonresidential facilities discharging into a publicly or privately-owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system, if oil and grease can be introduced into a sewer by such nonresidential facility in quantities which have the potential to affect or hinder the operation of sewage collecting, transmission or treatment facilities.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems, except sanitary sewers which are less than six (6) inches in diameter.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Locations at which a site rehabilitation action has been completed in accordance with the provisions set forth in Section 24-44 (2)(k)(ii).</section></section><section>The criterion for issuance of an operating permit pursuant to this section is compliance with, Miami-Dade County Code. Additionally, no resource recovery and management facility permit shall be granted without the written recommendation of approval of the Director of the Department of Solid Waste Management issued pursuant to the provisions of, Miami-Dade County Code. At the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee, conditions, limitations or restrictions may be required as part of the operating permit if said conditions, limitations and restrictions are consistent with the requirements of this chapter.</section><section>The Director or the Director's designee may deny the issuance of an operating permit if the public water system, public sewerage system or pollution source does not comply with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section>The Director or the Director's designee may suspend or revoke an operating permit if the public water system, public sewerage system or pollution source does not comply with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section>Such operating permits shall not be required for the aforesaid facilities, systems, and plants existing on the effective date of this section until one hundred twenty (120) days from the effective date of this section.</section><section>This section shall not be immediately applicable to air pollution sources with valid air pollution control operating permits on the effective date of this section. However, said air pollution sources shall comply with this section by obtaining the operating permit required by this section no later than one hundred eighty (180) days from the effective date of this section.</section><section>Notwithstanding anything in this chapter to the contrary, such operating permits shall not be required for underground storage facilities until ninety (90) days from the effective date of this paragraph.</section><section>All applications for permits issued pursuant to this section shall be on a form prescribed by the Director and accompanied by a fee which shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Disposition of Fees The permit fee payable hereunder shall be deposited in a separate County fund and shall be used exclusively by the Department to pay for the costs of the following environmental services to, and environmental regulation of, the aforesaid facilities, systems and plants:<section prefix='(1)'>Monitoring and evaluating purification and disposal systems of said sources.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Responding to and attempting to resolve citizen complaints against said sources.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Investigation, preparation, and prosecution of enforcement actions, pursuant to Chapter 24 of this Code, to protect the groundwater, surface water, drinking water, and air quality.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Ambient monitoring of groundwater, surface water, and air quality.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Special studies of groundwater, drinking water, surface water, and air quality when deemed necessary by the Director to protect the groundwater, surface water, drinking water, and air quality.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Air quality and water supply protection, planning, and programming.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Laboratory analyses of groundwater, surface water, drinking water, waste water, ambient air, air emissions, and other effluents affecting air or water quality.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Restoration of the air, water, property, animal life, aquatic life, and plant life to their condition prior to any violation of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Prevention of any imminent threat of any violation of this chapter.</section></section><section>No part of said fund shall be used for purposes other than the aforesaid.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 06-125, § 2, 9-12-06; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>