<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00022' order_by='00022' level='4'>DIVISION 2. STATE AND FEDERAL ADOPTIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-25</section_number>
<catch_line>Violations of rules and regulations of the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection, Florida Department of Health, and the United States Environmental Protection Agency.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003370</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-25. Violations of rules and regulations of the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection, Florida Department of Health, and the United States Environmental Protection Agency.<section prefix='(1)'>All of the following rules and regulations are hereby adopted and are incorporated herein by reference hereto as same may be amended from time to time:<section prefix='(a)'>Chapter 62-160 of the Florida Administrative Code</section><section prefix='(b)'>Chapter 62-550 of the Florida Administrative Code</section><section prefix='(c)'>Chapter 62-713 of the Florida Administrative Code</section><section prefix='(d)'>Chapter 62-761 of the Florida Administrative Code</section><section prefix='(e)'>Chapter 64E-8 of the Florida Administrative Code</section><section prefix='(f)'>Chapter 62-770 of the Florida Administrative Code</section><section prefix='(g)'>Chapter 62-777 of the Florida Administrative Code</section><section prefix='(h)'>Chapter 62-782 of the Florida Administrative Code</section><section prefix='(i)'>Chapter 62-785 of the Florida Administrative Code</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The regulations of the United States Environmental Protection Agency as set forth in 40 C.F.R. Part 403, as of January 1, 2011, are hereby adopted and incorporated herein by reference hereto, with the exception of 40 C.F.R. § 403.6(c)(5), 40 C.F.R. § 403.8(f)(2)(v), and 40 C.F.R. § 403.12(e). The regulations of the United States Environmental Protection Agency set forth in 40 C.F.R. § 403.6(c)(5), 40 C.F.R. § 403.8(f)(2)(v), and 40 C.F.R. § 403.12(e) as published in 40 C.F.R. Part 403 as of July 1, 2005 are hereby adopted and incorporated herein by reference hereto.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All rules and regulations promulgated by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection pursuant to provisions of Chapters 373, 403 and 253, Florida Statutes, as they may be amended from time to time, are hereby adopted and are made a part of this chapter by reference.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Any person who commits a violation of any rules and regulations adopted pursuant to this section shall be deemed guilty of committing a violation of this chapter. Violations of such rules and regulations shall constitute violations of this chapter triable in the court of appropriate jurisdiction.</section><section>Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit Miami-Dade County from enacting ordinances stricter than the rules and regulations incorporated herein or to invalidate or supersede ordinances heretofore enacted by Miami-Dade County which are stricter than the rules and regulations incorporated herein. Notwithstanding the foregoing provision, nothing in Sections(2) and (4),(2), and(9) of this Code shall supersede Sections(1)(c), (f), (g), (h), and (i) with respect to cleanup target levels for contaminants found in groundwater, surface water, and soil for sites contaminated in whole or part with petroleum substances subject to Chapter 62-770, F.A.C., for sites contaminated in whole or in part with dry cleaning solvent substances subject to Chapter 62-782, F.A.C., and for sites governed in whole or in part by the terms of a brownfields site rehabilitation agreement pursuant to Chapter 62-785, F.A.C.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 11-91, § 1, 11-15-11)</history></law>