<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-2</section_number>
<catch_line>Declaration of legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003247</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-2. Declaration of legislative intent.<section>The Board finds and determines that the reasonable control and regulation of activities which are causing or may cause pollution or contamination of air, water, soil and property is required for the protection and preservation of the public health, safety and welfare. It is the intent and purpose of this chapter to provide and maintain for the citizens and visitors of Miami-Dade County standards which will insure the purity of all waters consistent with public health and public enjoyment thereof, the propagation and protection of wildlife, birds, game, fish and other aquatic life, and atmospheric purity and freedom of the air from contaminants of synergistic agents injurious to human, plant or animal life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business. The Board finds it necessary to establish, within the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County, Countywide water control, coastal engineering, and coastal wetlands management programs for the purpose of maintaining adequate water levels, flood control, drainage, water conservation, and prevention of saltwater intrusion; for preserving beaches and shorelines; for managing coastal wetland resources; for acquisition of lands by gift, donation, purchase, condemnation or otherwise, as necessary for such programs; and providing for cooperation with federal, State and local agencies and authorities.</section><section>The Board further finds it necessary to maintain within Miami-Dade County a freshwater wetlands management program for the purposes of providing adequate water levels, flood control, water conservation, protection of water quality and recharge to the Biscayne Aquifer, and prevention of saltwater intrusion; for the maintenance of the biological integrity of freshwater wetlands in Miami-Dade County; for the protection of the interrelated natural functions between Miami-Dade County's wetlands and the natural systems in Everglades National Park; for managing freshwater wetland resources in accordance with environmental standards and management criteria as recommended by the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan and of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time; and providing for cooperation with federal, State, and local agencies and authorities.</section><section>The Board finds it necessary to establish for Miami-Dade County a Tree and Forest Resources Program for the purpose of protecting, preserving and replacing tree canopy, preserving natural forest communities including associated understory, providing protection for specimen-size trees and environmentally-sensitive tree resources, conserving rare, endangered, threatened and endemic species, protecting historically-significant tree resources, promoting the preservation of subtropical vegetation and unique or unusual species, providing for wildlife habitat, maintaining the natural character of neighborhoods, preserving the natural diversity of species, promoting environmentally-sound aesthetics, and providing for improved environmental quality by recognizing the numerous beneficial effects of trees (including improvements to air quality, maintenance of land areas essential to surface water management and aquifer recharge, reduction of heat and noise pollution, water and energy conservation and provision of shade and physical and psychological benefits to the people of Miami-Dade County by enhancing urban development). This program shall be a minimum standard and shall apply to both the incorporated and unincorporated areas, and in the unincorporated areas shall be enforced by the Department of Environmental Resources Management, and in the incorporated areas shall be enforced by the municipalities, unless the County is notified by a municipality, in the form of a letter from an official of the municipality or by resolution, that the municipality desires the County to enforce the Miami-Dade County Tree and Forest Program within the municipality. Any municipality may establish and enforce its own ordinance provided such ordinance is equivalent to or more stringent than the provisions of Ordinance Number 89-8.</section><section>The provisions of this chapter are not intended and shall not be construed as superseding or conflicting with any statutory provisions relating to, or rules and regulations promulgated by, the Florida State Department of Environmental Protection, but shall be construed as implementing and assisting the enforcement thereof. It is not the intent of this Board to hereby preempt the authority of any municipality in the exercise of its authority to issue coastal construction permits or to restrict it from adopting more stringent standards, the purpose of this chapter being to establish minimum standards for the issuance of coastal construction permits within all of Miami-Dade County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>