<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='4'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-28</section_number>
<catch_line>Nuisances injurious to health (sanitary nuisances).</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003277</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>The following conditions existing, permitted, maintained, kept or caused by any individual, municipal organization or corporation, governmental or private, shall constitute a sanitary nuisance:<section prefix='(a)'>Untreated or improperly treated or disposed of human waste, garbage, offal, dead animals or dangerous waste materials.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Improperly built or maintained septic tanks, water closets or privies.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Discharging, or allowing the discharge of septic tank pump-out wastes into streams, or surface waters or underground aquifers or into ditches, drainage structures or on the ground surface.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Supplying potable water without providing disinfection by a public water supply system.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Air pollution which is harmful to human beings, animal life, or plant life.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Water pollution which is harmful to human beings, animal life, or plant life.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Ground pollution which is harmful to human beings, animal life, or plant life.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Objectionable odors which are harmful to human beings or animal life.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The Director or the Director's designee is authorized to investigate any condition or alleged nuisance in any place within the geographical limits of Miami-Dade County, and if such condition is determined to constitute a sanitary nuisance, the Director or the Director's designee shall serve notice upon the proper party or parties to remove, abate, or correct the said nuisance within twenty-four (24) hours or such other reasonable time as the Director or the Director's designee may determine.</section><section>It shall be the duty of said Director, Environmental Resources Management, to institute proceedings in the appropriate court against all persons failing to comply with notices to remove, abate or correct said nuisance conditions.</section><section prefix='(3)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to cause, maintain or allow to be caused or maintained any sanitary nuisance as defined in Section 24-5 herein.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>