<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00024' order_by='00024' level='4'>DIVISION 4. TRUSTS AND FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-39</section_number>
<catch_line>Tree Trust Fund and Tree Forest Resources Advisory Committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003329</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-39. Tree Trust Fund and Tree Forest Resources Advisory Committee.<section prefix='(1)'>Creation of the Tree Trust Fund. There is hereby created a Tree Trust Fund, the purpose of which is to acquire, protect and maintain natural forest communities in Miami-Dade County and to plant trees on public property.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Creation of the Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee. The Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee is hereby established for the purpose of providing the Board of County Commissioners with recommendations regarding the Tree Trust Fund, and recommendations to the Director regarding the establishment of Departmental policies relating to Ordinance Number 89-8.<section prefix='(a)'>Composition and qualifications of members. The Committee shall be composed of thirteen (13) members which shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners. The Director or the Director's designee shall submit recommendations for appointments to the Miami-Dade County Manager. Members of the Committee shall be residents of Miami-Dade County who possess outstanding reputations for civic pride, interest, integrity, responsibility, and business or professional ability. Appointments shall be made by the County Commission on the basis of experience or interest in the fields of conservation, botany, horticulture, landscape architecture, agriculture, land use, land planning, or land development. The Director or the Director's designee shall serve as executive secretary to the Committee. The process of appointment and other requirements of Ordinance 80-136 (Chapter 2, Article I B, Sections 2-11.36 through 2-11.40 of this Code) shall be followed.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Terms of office and organization. In order that the terms of office of all appointed members of the Committee shall not expire at the same time, the initial appointments to the Committee shall be as follows: seven (7) members shall be appointed for a term of one (1) year, and six (6) members shall be appointed for a term of two (2) years. Thereafter, all members shall be appointed for a term of two (2) years. Appointments to fill any vacancy on the Committee shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term of office. The members of the Committee shall elect a chairman and such other officers as may be deemed necessary or desirable, who shall serve at the will of the Committee. Appointed members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, in accordance with County policy, upon approval of the County Manager. A majority vote of a quorum shall be necessary to take any action. Seven (7) members shall constitute a quorum.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Meetings and authority. The Committee shall hold a minimum of one (1) publicly-advertised meeting per year. The Committee shall have the authority to make recommendations to the Board of County Commissioners concerning any matter relating to the tree trust fund. The Committee shall also have the authority to make recommendations to the Director regarding Departmental policies relating to Ordinance Number 89-8, and shall review and approve the quantitative evaluation form which the Department shall use for evaluating natural forest communities. In addition, upon request, the Committee shall have the authority to make recommendations to the Environmental Quality Control Board concerning variance requests made pursuant to this Ordinance Number 89-8, natural forest community site additions or deletions, and natural forest community boundary line modifications being proposed by the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Disbursement and maintenance of the Tree Trust Fund. Monies obtained for the Tree Trust Fund shall be disbursed for the acquisition, maintenance, management and protection of natural forest communities, or for planting trees on public property. Such monies may be used as a matching fund contribution towards the acquisition of natural forest communities in Miami-Dade County in association with other public land acquisition programs, such as, but not limited to, the State of Florida Conservation and Recreational Lands Trust Fund. Said trust fund shall be kept and maintained in trust by the Board of County Commissioners solely for the purposes set forth in this section in a separate and segregated fund of the County which shall not be commingled with other County funds until disbursed for an authorized purpose pursuant to this section. Disbursement from the tree trust fund shall require approval by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners, provided, however, that any funds received pursuant to the conditions of any tree removal permit shall be used as required by the permit conditions without the necessity of approval, appropriation, or action of any kind by the Board of County Commissioners. Prior to approving disbursements, the Board of County Commissioners shall consider the recommendations of the County Manager and the Tree and Forest Resources Advisory Committee. The County Manager, prior to making any such recommendations, shall consider the recommendations of the Department pertaining to the proposed disbursement(s) for the acquisition of natural forest communities or planting of trees on public property. The Finance Director is hereby authorized to establish the Tree Trust Fund and to receive and disburse monies in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Source of monies for the Tree Trust Fund. Said Tree Trust Fund shall consist of the following monies:<section prefix='(a)'>All monies collected by the Department for environmental damages to tree or forest resources and environmental mitigation for the loss of tree or forest resources which are obtained through civil lawsuits, consent agreements or after-the-fact tree removal permits, except penalties and administrative costs.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All monies offered to and accepted by Miami-Dade County for the Tree Trust Fund in the form of federal, State, or other governmental grants, allocations or appropriations, as well as foundation or private grants and donations, shall be disbursed strictly in accordance with terms and conditions of the grant, allocation, appropriation or donation and shall be earmarked accordingly.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Contributions in lieu of, or in conjunction with, the replacement planting provisions of Section 24-49.4(2). The Department shall collect funds designated for the Tree Trust Fund when the replacement planting requirements of Section 24-49.4(2) cannot be met, and in accordance with Section 24-49.2(II)(5).</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Interest. Unless otherwise restricted by the terms and conditions of a particular grant, gift, appropriation or allocation, all interest earned by the investment of all monies in the Tree Trust Fund shall be disbursed by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners for any project authorized consistent with Section 24-39. Trust fund monies shall be invested only in accordance with the laws pertaining to the investment of County funds.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Decisions to grant or deny tree removal permits shall be made without consideration of the existence of this fund or offers of donations of monies thereto.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>