<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00023' order_by='00023' level='4'>DIVISION 3. ENFORCEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-31</section_number>
<catch_line>Civil liability; joint and several liability; attorneys' fees.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003319</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-31. Civil liability; joint and several liability; attorneys' fees.<section prefix='(1)'>Whoever commits a violation of this chapter or any lawful rule or regulation promulgated under this chapter is liable to Miami-Dade County for any damage caused to the air, ground, waters, or property, including animal, plant, or aquatic life, within the geographical limits of Miami-Dade County and for reasonable costs and expenses of Miami-Dade County in tracing the source of the discharge, in controlling and abating the source and the pollutants, and in restoring the air, waters, and property, including animal, plant, and aquatic life, within the geographical limits of Miami-Dade County in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, and furthermore is subject to the judicial imposition of a civil penalty for each offense in an amount of not more than twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) per offense. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense. Nothing herein shall give the Director the right to bring an action on behalf of any private person.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whenever two (2) or more persons pollute the air, ground or waters of the County in violation of this chapter or any lawful rule or regulation promulgated under this chapter or any order of the Director so that the damage is indivisible, each violator shall be jointly and severally liable for such damage and for the reasonable cost and expenses of the County incurred in tracing the source of the discharge, in controlling and abating the source and the pollutants, and in restoring the air, waters, ground and property, including the animal, plant and aquatic life of the County in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. However, if said damage is divisible and may be attributed to a particular violator or violators, each violator is liable only for that damage attributable to his violation.</section><section prefix='(3)'>In assessing damages for fish killed, the value of the fish is to be determined in accordance with a table of values for individual categories of fish which has been promulgated by the Florida Department of Environmental Protection.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All the judicial remedies in this chapter are independent and cumulative.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Each mangrove tree unlawfully trimmed, cut or altered shall constitute a separate violation of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Whenever a violation of this chapter occurs or exists, or has occurred or existed, any person, individually or otherwise, who has a legal, beneficial, or equitable interest in the facility or instrumentality causing or contributing to the violation, or who has a legal, beneficial, or equitable interest in the real property upon which such violation occurs or exists, or has occurred or existed, shall be jointly and severally liable for said violation regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation. This provision shall be construed to impose joint and severable liability, regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation, upon all persons, individually or otherwise, who, although said persons may no longer have any such legal, beneficial or equitable interest in said facility or instrumentality or real property, did have such an interest at any time during which such violation existed or occurred or continued to exist or to occur. This provision shall be liberally construed and shall be retroactively applied to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and to accomplish the purposes of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Any person violating any provision of this chapter shall immediately correct the violation and restore the air, water, ground and property, including but not limited to animal, plant, and aquatic life, affected by said violation in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Owners of real property shall be liable for the sums expended by the County pursuant to Section 24-7(27) when the violation of this chapter occurred or continued to exist or appeared imminent upon the real property aforesaid, regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the aforesaid violation. All sums expended by the County pursuant to Section 24-7(27) of this Code shall constitute and are hereby imposed as special assessments against the real property aforesaid, and until fully paid and discharged or barred by law, shall remain liens equal in rank and dignity with the lien of County ad valorem taxes and superior in rank and dignity to all other liens, encumbrances, titles and claims in, to or against the real property involved. All such sums shall become immediately due and owing to the County upon expenditure by the County and shall become delinquent if not fully paid within sixty (60) days after the due date. All such delinquent sums shall bear a penalty of fifteen (15) percent per annum. Unpaid and delinquent sums, together with all penalties imposed thereon, shall remain and constitute special assessment liens against the real property involved for the period of five (5) years from due date thereof. Said special assessment liens may be enforced by the Director by any of the methods provided in Chapter 85, Florida Statutes, or, in the alternative, foreclosure proceedings may be instituted and prosecuted by the Director pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 173, Florida Statutes, or the collection and enforcement of payment thereof may be accomplished by any other method provided by law. All sums recovered by the County pursuant to this provision shall be deposited by the County into the fund from which said sums were expended.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Upon the rendition of a judgment or decree by any of the courts of this state against any person and in favor of the Director under any of the provisions of this chapter, the trial court, or, in the event of an appeal in which the Director prevails, the appellate court shall adjudge or decree against said person and in favor of the Director a reasonable sum as fees or compensation for the Director's attorney prosecuting the suit in which the recovery is had. Where so awarded, compensation or fees of the attorney shall be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. This provision shall apply to all civil actions, legal or equitable, filed after the effective date of this ordinance by the Director pursuant to this chapter. Cessation of a nuisance, sanitary nuisance or of any other violation of any of the provisions of this chapter whatsoever, prior to rendition of a judgment or of a temporary or final decree, or prior to execution of a negotiated settlement, but after an action is filed by the Director under any of the provisions of this chapter, shall be deemed the functional equivalent of a confession of judgment or verdict in favor of the Director for which attorneys' fees shall be awarded by the trial court as set forth hereinabove.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Each tree that is not exempt under this chapter and is unlawfully effectively destroyed or removed shall constitute a separate violation of this chapter for which liability shall attach in accordance with the provisions of Section 24-31 and Section 24-49(4), (5), and (6). In addition, the owner and operator of any motor vehicle that destroys or effectively destroys any nonexempt tree due to its negligent operation shall be jointly liable for the replacement cost. Trees destroyed or effectively destroyed by an Act of God shall not constitute a violation of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(11)'>In assessing damages for tree(s) or understory unlawfully removed, the value of the tree(s) or understory shall be based upon the cost of the tree(s) or understory and all costs associated with planting. At a minimum, the value of the tree(s) or understory, including the cost of planting, shall be two (2) times the current wholesale price of the tree(s) or understory based upon the largest available size or actual size of the tree(s) or understory removed, whichever is smaller, as set forth in recognized nursery publications.</section><section prefix='(12)'>Whenever a mangrove tree is unlawfully trimmed, cut or altered, any person who authorized, permitted, suffered, or allowed said violation or whose agent, employee, servant, or independent contractor caused or contributed to the violation or who has a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in the real property upon which such violation occurs or exists, shall be jointly and severally liable for said violation regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation. This provision shall be construed to impose joint and several liability, regardless of fault and regardless of knowledge of the violation, upon all persons, individually or otherwise, who, although said persons may no longer have a legal, beneficial or equitable interest in said real property or may no longer have a relationship with such agent, employee, servant or independent contractor, did have such an interest or relationship at any time during which such violation existed or occurred or continued to exist or occur. This provision shall be liberally construed and shall be retroactively applied to protect the mangrove tree resources of Miami-Dade County and to accomplish the purposes of this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>