<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. WATER AND SOIL QUALITY</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00026' order_by='00026' level='4'>DIVISION 2. WELLFIELD PROTECTION, DOMESTIC WELL SYSTEMS AND POTABLE WATER STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-43</section_number>
<catch_line>Protection of public potable water supply wells.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003354</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-43. Protection of public potable water supply wells.<section>The provisions of this section which impose upon land uses within the West Wellfield Interim protection area regulations which are more restrictive than those regulations applicable to the other public utility potable water supply wellfields in Miami-Dade County shall be deemed interim in nature. Said more restrictive regulations shall be reviewed by such technical review task force(s) or committee(s) as provided by the Board of County Commissioners or its designee upon recommendation of the Director. The Director shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners progress reports, as necessary, pertaining to said review, and recommendations necessary to protect the public health, safety and welfare arising out of said review shall be presented to the Board of County Commissioners. The Miami-Dade County Conflict of Interest and Code of Ethics Ordinance (Section of this Code) shall not be applicable to task forces or committees provided for in this section.<section prefix='(1)'>Legislative intent. The intent and purpose of this section is to safeguard the public health, safety and welfare by providing scientifically established standards for land uses within the cones of influence thereby protecting public potable water supply wells from contamination.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Short title; applicability; construction. This section shall be known as the "Potable Water Supply Well Protection Ordinance." The provisions of this section shall be effective in the incorporated and unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County and shall be liberally construed to effect the purposes set forth herein.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Maps of cones of influence, the Northwest Wellfield protection area, the West Wellfield Interim protection area, and the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex protection area. The Director or the Director's designee, shall maintain maps of cones of influence of public utility potable water supply wells, map(s) of the Northwest Wellfield protection area, map(s) of the West Wellfield Interim protection area, and the map(s) of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex wellfield protection area dated November, 2005. The cone of influence maps dated December 30, 1980, as may be amended from time to time, prepared by the Department are incorporated herein by reference hereto. Any changes, additions or deletions to said maps shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance. The cone of influence maps of the Northwest Wellfield dated December 30, 1980, as amended effective May 31, 1985, shall hereinafter be referred to as the Northwest Wellfield protection area map(s). The Northwest Wellfield protection area map(s) dated May 31, 1985, the West Wellfield Interim protection area map(s) dated February 28, 1989 and the map(s) of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex wellfield protection area dated November, 2005, as all of same may be amended from time to time, prepared by the Department, are incorporated herein by reference hereto. Any changes, additions or deletions to said Northwest Wellfield protection area map(s), West Wellfield Interim protection area map(s) or South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex wellfield protection area map(s) shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance. The Director, or the Director's designee, shall maintain the DERM Technical Report: "Development of a Groundwater Model to Determine Wellfield Protection Zones for the Miami-Dade County, Florida, South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex". The wellfield protection zones of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex have been established using the procedures and input parameters set forth in the aforesaid Technical Report dated, November, 2005. The aforesaid Technical Report dated, November, 2005, a copy of which is attached hereto, is hereby incorporated by reference, as same may be amended from time to time. Any changes, additions or deletions to the aforesaid Technical Report dated November, 2005 shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Septic tanks, sanitary sewers, storm water disposal, liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment and violations of this chapter within wellfield protection area. Notwithstanding any provisions of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any land use served or to be served by a septic tank, sanitary sewer, storm water disposal method, or liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method, and which is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, until the County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. Furthermore, not withstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any land use served or to be served by septic tank, sanitary sewer, storm water disposal method, or liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method, and which is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, until the person has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee finds that all septic tanks, septic tank drain fields, storm water disposal methods and liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods will be installed upon the property as far away as is reasonably possible from all potable water supply wells, and:<section prefix='(a)'>Septic tanks. That the septic tank sewage loadings will not exceed the number of gallons per day for each unsubmerged acre of land as set forth in Tables A-1, A-2, A-3 and A-4, except that neither the Director nor the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval for any land use served or to be served by a septic tank within the Northwest Wellfield protection area unless the septic tank was installed prior to September 30, 1983, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area unless the septic tank was installed prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80], or that the land use served or to be served by a septic tank within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within that portion of the West Wellfield Interim protection area which is west of the Urban Development Boundary of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan as may be amended from time to time, is residential or is an ancillary rockmining use necessary for extracting and processing subsurface materials and which residential or ancillary rockmining use shall not exceed a maximum sewage loading of seventy (70) gallons per day per acre and which septic tanks shall be located within an area of twenty-one thousand seven hundred eighty (21,780) square feet of unsubmerged land, or that the property served or to be served by septic tanks is residential, uses a public water supply, has not been the subject of any zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance, or equivalent municipal zoning action) or any platting action (final plat, waiver of plat, or equivalent municipal platting action) after March 13, 1981, and is in compliance with Section 24-43.1, or that the owner of the property served or to be served by septic tanks is applying for the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license pursuant to a valid building permit obtained prior to June 1, 1983, for property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area obtained prior to September 30, 1983, or, in the case of property within the West Wellfield Interim protection area obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield and Southwest Wellfield, obtained prior to February 1, 1985, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield and Hialeah Wellfield, obtained prior to December 12, 1986, which permit has been valid and continuously in full force and effective since its issuance, or that the owner of the property is applying for a certificate of use and occupancy or municipal occupational license for a land use served or to be served by a septic tank installed prior to March 13, 1981 for property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area installed prior to September 30, 1983, or, in the case of property within the West Wellfield Interim protection area installed prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, and Southwest Wellfield, installed prior to February 1, 1985, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield and Hialeah Wellfield, installed prior to December 12, 1986, which uses a public water supply and which is in compliance with Section 24-43.1.<section prefix='(i)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 24-43(4)(a), there shall be required within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, and within the maximum day wellfield protection area of all public utility potable water supply wells a minimum separation equivalent to ten (10) days travel time between any potable water supply well (other than a public utility potable water supply well) and any septic tank or septic tank drainfield.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Sanitary sewers. That the sewage loading into sanitary sewers will not exceed the number of gallons per day for each unsubmerged acre of land as set forth in Table B-1, or that the property served or to be served by sanitary sewers is residential, uses a public water supply, has not been the subject of any zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance, or equivalent municipal zoning action) or any platting action (final plat, waiver of plat, or equivalent municipal platting action) after March 13, 1981, and is in compliance with Section 24-42.4, or that the owner of the property served or to be served by sanitary sewers is applying for the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license pursuant to a valid building permit obtained prior to June 1, 1983, for property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, obtained prior to September 30, 1983, for property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or, in the case of property within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or for property within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area, but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield and Southwest Wellfield, obtained prior to February 1, 1985, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield and Hialeah Wellfield, installed prior to December 12, 1986, which permit has been valid and continuously in full force and effect since its issuance.<section prefix='(i)'>Notwithstanding the provisions of Section 24-43(4)(b), all sanitary sewers installed within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, after June 13, 1986, shall comply with the following standards:<section>—No gravity sanitary sewer shall have an exfiltration rate greater than fifty (50) gallons per inch pipe diameter per mile per day. Sewer lateral lines located in the public right-of-way shall be a minimum of six (6) inches in diameter.</section><section>—No gravity sanitary sewer shall have an exfiltration rate greater than twenty (20) gallons per inch pipe diameter per mile per day. Sewer lateral lines located in the public right-of-way shall be a minimum of six (6) inches in diameter.</section><section>—All sanitary sewer force mains installed within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, shall be constructed of either ductile iron or reinforced concrete pressure sewer pipe. No such ductile iron sanitary sewer force main shall, exfiltrate at a rate greater than the allowable leakage rate specified in American Water Works Association Standard C600-82 at a test pressure of one hundred (100) pounds per square inch. No such reinforced concrete pressure sanitary sewer force main shall exfiltrate at a rate greater than one-half (½) the allowable leakage rate specified for ductile iron pipe in American Water Works Association Standard C600-82 at a test pressure of one hundred (100) pounds per square inch.</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>Notwithstanding the provision of Section 24-43(4)(b), all gravity sanitary sewers with invert elevations above the average surrounding water table elevation and all sanitary sewer force mains shall be tested to ensure compliance with the aforementioned exfiltration rate standards.<section>A registered professional engineer shall provide written certification of the exfiltration rate for all manhole/gravity sewer pipe systems installed, in equivalent gallons per inch pipe diameter per mile of pipe per day (twenty-four (24) hours), and the exfiltration rate for all sanitary sewer force mains in gallons per hour per one thousand (1,000) feet of sanitary sewer force main installed. Existing gravity sanitary sewers with pipe diameters of eight (8) inches or more shall be visually inspected by television every five (5) years by the responsible utility or property owner to ensure both structural and pipe joint integrity. Existing manholes shall be visually inspected for both structural and incoming pipe connection integrity every five (5) years.</section><section>Certified test and inspection results and repair logs shall be submitted to the Department within thirty (30) days after completion of the particular test, inspection, or repair.</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Storm water disposal methods. That the storm water disposal methods utilized or to be utilized will be limited as set forth in Table C-1.<section>Furthermore, land uses adjacent to the Snapper Creek extension canal and secondary canals directly connected to the Snapper Creek extension canal shall provide an earth berm, or alternative structure as approved by the Director or the Director's designee, which shall be constructed upon the perimeter of all canals to prevent overland storm water runoff from entering the canal. The berm shall be constructed adjacent to the canal top of slope on the landward side. Said berm shall extend one (1) foot above the canal bank elevation. The landward slope of the berm shall have a gradient not steeper than one (1) foot vertical to four (4) feet horizontal. The canalward slope shall not be steeper than the canal slope. The construction of berming and backsloping shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods other than septic tanks utilized for the disposal, discharge, storage or treatment of domestic sewage; sanitary sewer lift stations; and public sanitary sewers. That liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment methods (other than septic tanks utilized for the disposal, discharge, storage or treatment of domestic sewage; sanitary sewer lift stations; and public sanitary sewers); shall be prohibited within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, the West Wellfield Interim protection area, the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, the average day pumpage wellfield protection areas of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, and Hialeah Wellfield, and the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well unless, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, said liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to September 30, 1983, or, unless, in the case of property within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, said liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights wellfield complex installed prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or, unless, in the case of property within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield and Southwest Wellfield, said liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to February 1, 1985, or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, and Hialeah Wellfield, said liquid waste, storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to December 12, 1986, unless in the case of property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, said liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method was installed prior to June 13, 1986.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Violations of this chapter. That the septic tank, sanitary sewer, storm water disposal method or liquid waste storage, disposal or treatment method utilized or to be utilized will serve an existing land use within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, and Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well and which is required by the Director or the Director's designee to correct violation(s) of this chapter. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Director or the Director's designee shall not issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval unless the Director or the Director's designee determines that the land use will comply with all the provisions of this chapter and that the following water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices shall be provided:<section prefix='(i)'>Monitoring and detection of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Secondary containment of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Inventory control and record keeping of hazardous materials, and</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Storm water management of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and</section><section prefix='(v)'>Protection and security of facilities utilized for the generation, storage, usage, handling, disposal or discharge of hazardous materials.</section></section></section><section prefix='(5)'>Prohibition of hazardous materials within wellfield protection areas. Notwithstanding any provisions of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any nonresidential land use, other than a bona fide agricultural land use, a bona fide rockmining use (lake excavation), a public sewer facilities use, or a public water supply facilities use, within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director's or the Director's designee's written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that the nonresidential land use is in compliance with Sections 24-43(5)(a), 24-43(5)(b) or 24-43(5)(c).<section>Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any nonresidential land use, other than a bona fide agricultural land use, a public sewer facilities use, or a public water supply facilities use, within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, and which uses, generates, handles, disposes of, discharges or stores hazardous materials, until the person has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>Pursuant to the foregoing, the Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that all potential sources of pollution will be installed upon the property as far away as is reasonably possible from all potable water supply wells; hazardous materials will not be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on that portion of the property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well; and hazardous wastes will not be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on that portion of the property within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, or within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield.</section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing, fuels and lubricants required for rockmining operations (lake excavations, concrete batch plants, rock crushing and aggregate plants) within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area; electrical transformers serving nonresidential land uses; small quantity generators of hazardous wastes as defined in this chapter, within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, Hialeah Wellfield, and the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex and existing land uses required by the Director or the Director's designee to correct violations of this chapter; shall not be prohibited when the water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices set forth in Sections(5)(a)(i), (ii), (iii), (iv) and (v) will be provided and the Director or the Director's designee has approved same.</section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing, the use, handling or storage of factory prepackaged products intended primarily for domestic use or consumption determined by the Director or the Director's designee to be hazardous materials shall not be prohibited; provided, however, that the requirements of Sections(5)(a)(vi), (vii), (viii) and (ix) are fulfilled.</section><section prefix='(a)'>The owner of the property has submitted to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that hazardous materials shall not be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on that portion of the property located within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well; and that hazardous wastes shall not be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on that portion of the property within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex.<section>Furthermore, the aforesaid covenant shall provide that fuels and lubricants required for rockmining operations (lake excavations, concrete batch plants, rock crushing and aggregate plants) within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area; electrical transformers serving nonresidential land uses; small quantity generators of hazardous wastes as defined in this chapter, within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex or within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, and Hialeah Wellfield and existing land uses required by the Director or the Director's designee to correct violations of this chapter; shall not be prohibited when the following water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices will be provided:</section><section prefix='(i)'>Monitoring and detection of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Secondary containment of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Inventory control and record keeping of hazardous materials, and</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Storm water management of water pollution caused by hazardous materials, and</section><section prefix='(v)'>Protection and security of facilities utilized for the generation, storage, usage, handling, disposal or discharge of hazardous materials.<section>Said water pollution prevention and abatement measures and practices shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>Furthermore, the aforesaid covenant shall provide that use, handling or storage of factory pre-packaged products intended primarily for domestic use or consumption determined by the Director or the Director's designee to be hazardous materials shall not be prohibited, provided, however, that:</section></section><section prefix='(vi)'>The use, handling or storage of said factory prepackaged products occurs only within a building, and</section><section prefix='(vii)'>The nonresidential land use is an office building use (or equivalent municipal land use) or a business district use (or equivalent municipal land use) engaged exclusively in retail sales of factory prepackaged products intended primarily for domestic use or consumption, and</section><section prefix='(viii)'>The nonresidential land use is served or is to be served by public water and public sanitary sewers, and</section><section prefix='(ix)'>Said building is located more than thirty (30) days' travel time from any public utility potable water supply well.</section><section>Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property, or</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>If the Director or the Director's designee determines that the owner of the property is applying for the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license pursuant to a valid building permit obtained prior to June 1, 1983, for property within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or, in the case of property within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, obtained prior to September 30, 1983, or, in the case of the West Wellfield Interim protection boundary, obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex obtained prior to the effective date of this ordinance, or, in the case of property within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area, but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield or Southwest Wellfield, obtained prior to February 1, 1985 or, in the case of property not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield, obtained prior to December 12, 1986 and which permit has been valid and continuously in full force and effect since its issuance, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>If the Director or the Director's designee determines:<section prefix='(i)'>That the application for a building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) is for the replacement, modification or limited expansion of an existing facility, provided in no case shall such replacement, modification or limited expansion cause, permit, let, suffer or allow the use, generation, handling, disposal, discharge or storage of hazardous materials on the property to be increased by more than fifty (50) percent over the use, generation, handling, disposal, discharge or storage of hazardous materials which existed on the property on September 30, 1983, for properties within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or which existed on the property on the effective date of this ordinance [Ord. No. 89-80] for properties within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or which existed on March 13, 1981 for properties within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>That the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion of the existing facility will substantially reduce the existing risk of pollution from the hazardous materials to the closest public utility potable water supply well. In determining whether there will be a substantial reduction of the existing risk of pollution as aforesaid, the Director or the Director's designee shall consider the following factors and shall render written findings as to the Director's or the Director's designee's assessment of each:<section prefix='1.'>Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion of the facility will provide adequate and increased monitoring and detection of pollution which may be or which has been caused by the hazardous materials on the property.</section><section prefix='2.'>Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion of the facility will provide adequate and increased secondary containment of pollution which may be or which has been caused by the hazardous materials on the property.</section><section prefix='3.'>Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion will provide adequate and increased inventory control and record keeping of hazardous materials on the property.</section><section prefix='4.'>Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion will provide adequate and increased storm water management of pollution which may be or which has been caused by the hazardous materials on the property.</section><section prefix='5.'>Whether the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion will provide adequate and increased protection and security of the facilities utilized for the generation, storage, usage, handling, disposal, or discharge of hazardous materials on the property.</section><section>The Director or the Director's designee shall determine that there will be a substantial reduction of the existing risk of pollution from the hazardous materials to the closest public utility potable water supply well only if the Director or the Director's designee makes affirmative findings as to all of the aforesaid factors, and</section></section><section prefix='(iii)'>That the owner of the property has submitted to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that the hazardous materials to be used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on the property after the proposed replacement, modification or limited expansion is approved by the Director or the Director's designee, pursuant to this section, shall not be more hazardous than the hazardous materials used, generated, handled, disposed of, discharged or stored on the property at the time of the aforesaid approval and which furthermore shall require written notice by the owner of the property to the Department of any change in the kind of hazardous materials on the property after the aforesaid approval. Said covenants shall be in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property.</section></section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Applicability of travel time ranges within wellfield protection areas. The Director or the Director's designee shall utilize the following procedures when making a determination under Tables A-1, A-2, A-3, A-4 or B-1:<section prefix='(a)'>Property wholly located within one (1) travel time range having restrictions shall be governed by the restrictions under that travel time range.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Property within two (2) or more travel time ranges having restrictions shall be governed by the total sewage loading for the property. The total sewage loading shall be derived by adding the sewage loading within each travel time range and dividing the resultant amount by the gross acreage for the property.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Property within both restricted and unrestricted travel time ranges shall be governed in accordance with Section 24-43(6)(b) herein except that portion of the property outside of the restricted travel time ranges shall be excluded from averaging the applicable restrictions as aforesaid. However, all septic tanks, septic tank drainfields, storm water disposal methods and liquid waste storage, disposal and treatment methods shall be installed upon the property as far away as is reasonably possible from all potable water supply wells.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Excavations. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant, or issue any permit, of any kind whatsoever, certificate of completion, platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any excavation within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or within one-quarter (¼) of a mile of the perimeter of the Miami-Dade County 58th Street landfill, United Sanitation landfill, or the resources recovery facility until the County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.<section>Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall cause, allow, let, permit or suffer any excavation within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well until the person has obtained the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>The Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that the excavation will comply with the following:</section><section prefix='(a)'>The property upon which the excavation has occurred or will occur and that portion of the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated shall be provided with protection and security measures to prohibit the handling, disposal of, discharge or storage of hazardous materials, solid waste, or liquid waste in the excavation or on the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated. Said protection and security shall be subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee.<section>Furthermore, the owner of the property upon which the excavation has occurred or will occur and that portion of the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated shall submit to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that protection and security measures shall be provided subject to the approval of the Director or the Director's designee. Said covenants shall be executed by the owner of the property upon which the excavation has occurred or will occur and that portion of the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated in form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property upon which the excavation has occurred or will occur and the property which has not been excavated or will not be excavated, and</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The excavation will not be located within thirty (30) days' travel time from any public utility potable water supply well or within thirty (30) days' travel time from potable water supply wells as set forth on the West Wellfield Interim protection area map(s) and the excavation will not exceed a depth of forty (40) feet below existing grade within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>The excavation will not be located within thirty (30) days' travel time from any public utility potable water supply well and there exists property without excavation which will provide an additional thirty (30) days' travel time between the excavation and any public utility potable water supply well.<section>Furthermore, the owner of the property upon which the excavation is to occur shall submit to the Director or the Director's designee a covenant running with the land executed by the owner of the property in favor of Miami-Dade County which provides that the property without excavation aforesaid will not be subject to excavation at any time. Said covenants shall be executed by the owner of the property without excavation aforesaid and in a form(s) prescribed by the Director and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The covenants shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, by the Department at the expense of the owner of the property upon which the excavation is to occur, or</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>The excavation has a valid excavation permit or equivalent municipal permit for excavation and a valid Class IV permit, if required by Article IV of this chapter, which was obtained prior to September 30, 1983, which permits have been valid and continuously in full force and effect since their issuance.</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>Pipelines for hazardous materials. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board, after July 13, 1984 shall approve, grant or issue any permit of any kind whatsoever for the installation, modification, or expansion of that portion of any pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of any hazardous materials and which portion is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield or Southwest Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well or, in the case of that portion of any pipeline not within the basic wellfield protection area but within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield, after December 12, 1986, or, in the case of that portion of any pipeline within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex after the effective date of this ordinance.<section>Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall install, construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any pipeline or portion of any pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of any hazardous materials within the Northwest Wellfield Protection Area or the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield or Southwest Wellfield or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well, after July 13, 1984, unless said person installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied said pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of hazardous materials before July 13, 1984, or, in the case of the West Wellfield Interim protection area, no person shall install, construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any pipeline or portion of any pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of any hazardous materials within the West Wellfield Interim protection area after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] or, in the case of that portion of any pipeline within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex after the effective date of this ordinance unless said person installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied said pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of hazardous materials prior to the effective date of this ordinance, unless said person installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied said pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of hazardous materials prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80].</section><section>Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall install, construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any pipeline or portion of any pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of any hazardous materials within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area but not within the basic wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield or Hialeah Wellfield after the effective date of this subsection [December 12, 1986], unless said person installed, constructed, utilized, operated or occupied said pipeline used or to be used for the transmission or storage of hazardous materials before the effective date of this subsection [December 12, 1986].</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>Water conservation restrictions for the protection of the Northwest Wellfield. The Director or the Director's designee shall evaluate the data from a groundwater elevation monitoring program and a groundwater quality monitoring program for the Northwest Wellfield which programs shall be conducted by the Department or a contractor designated by the County. If the Director or the Director's designee, after evaluating the aforesaid monitoring data, determines that a reduction in wellfield pumpage is necessary to prevent contamination of the Northwest Wellfield, the Director or the Director's designee shall impose water conservation restrictions in the unincorporated and incorporated areas of Miami-Dade County. These water conservation restrictions shall consist of one (1) of, or any combination of, the following:<section prefix='(a)'>Ordering public utilities owning or operating public water systems to reduce water system pressure.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Mandatory water conservation restrictions similar to the applicable water use restrictions set forth in the rules of the South Florida Water Management District, Chapter 40E-21, Florida Administrative Code, as may be amended from time to time.</section><section>The duration of these water conservation restrictions shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee after periodic evaluation of wellfield pumpage data and pertinent monitoring program data. The water conservation restrictions in effect may be subsequently changed or rescinded by the Director or the Director's designee after such periodic evaluation.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>Land uses within the Northwest Wellfield protection area and West Wellfield Interim protection area. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County officer, agent, employee or board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance, new use, similar use) for any land use within the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area, without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any land use within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area without obtaining the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.<section>The Director or the Director's designee shall issue his written approval only if:</section><section prefix='(a)'>The Director or the Director's designee determines that the property is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area and the existing land use(s) for the property or the land use(s) requested for the property is one (1) or more of the land uses set forth in Table E-1 and the land use(s) is not a land use found exclusively in the following Miami-Dade County zoning classifications or that the zoning classification requested is not one (1) or more of the following Miami-Dade County zoning classifications:<section prefix='(i)'>BU-3 (excluding those land uses permitted by BU-1, BU-1A or BU-2),</section><section prefix='(ii)'>IU-1,</section><section prefix='(iii)'>IU-2,</section><section prefix='(iv)'>IU-3,</section><section prefix='(v)'>IU-C, or</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director or the Director's designee determines that the land use is not listed in Table E-1, the land use(s) is not set forth as a permitted use, special exception, unusual use or conditional use in Chapter 33 of this Code, the land use(s) is not a land use(s) found exclusively in the zoning classifications listed in Sections 24-43(10)(a)(i), (ii), (iii), (iv), (v), above the land use(s) is comparable to a land use(s) set forth in Table E-1, and the land use(s) will not have an adverse environmental impact on groundwater quality in the North Wellfield protection area and within the West Wellfield protection area. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Director or the Director's designee shall not determine that the land use is comparable to land use(s) set forth in Table E-1 if the land use is permitted in one (1) or more of the following Miami-Dade County zoning classifications and if the land use is not permitted in one (1) or more Miami-Dade County zoning classifications which are less restrictive than the following BU-3; IU-1; IU-2; IU-3; and IU-C.<section prefix='(i)'>In determining whether a land use is comparable to one (1) or more land use(s) set forth in Table E-1, the Director or the Director's designee shall consider the following factors:<section prefix='1.'>The materials used, handled and stored, and the products and wastes produced;</section><section prefix='2.'>The activities, processes and methods which are employed and utilized;</section><section prefix='3.'>The machinery and other facilities utilized and maintenance requirements of said machinery and facilities;</section><section prefix='4.'>Uses commonly attendant to or associated with the primary use.</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>In determining whether a land use does not or will not have an adverse environmental impact on the groundwater quality in the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield protection area, the Director or the Director's designee shall consider the following factors:<section prefix='1.'>The land use will not be detrimental to the public health, welfare and safety and will not create a nuisance and will not materially increase the level of water pollution within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area;</section><section prefix='2.'>The use, generation, handling, disposal of, discharge or storage of hazardous materials will not occur within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area;</section><section prefix='3.'>The only liquid waste (excluding stormwater) which will be generated, disposed of, discharged, or stored within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area shall be domestic sewage discharged to a public sanitary sewer or septic tank;</section><section prefix='4.'>Stormwater runoff shall be retained on the property and disposed of through infiltration drainage systems supplemented with seepage drainage systems, or</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The Director or the Director's designee, determines that: The property is within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the West Wellfield Interim protection area; the owner of the property is applying for the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license pursuant to a valid building permit obtained prior to December 12, 1986, in the case of the Northwest Wellfield protection area, or August 6, 1989, in the case of the West Wellfield Interim protection area, which permit has been valid and continuously in full force and effect since its issuance; the property is served or will be served by a public water main and public sanitary sewer no later than the date that the original certificate of use and occupancy or original municipal occupational license is issued; and the property is in compliance with Sections 24-43(4), (5) and (6) of this Code and was in compliance with Sections 24-43(4), (5) and (6) of this Code no later than the date of issuance of the aforesaid valid building permit.<section>TABLE E-1</section><section><section></section></section><section>Abstract title</section><section>Accounts, bookkeeping</section><section>Actuaries</section><section>Advertising office only; no printing</section><section>Agricultural use</section><section>Alcoholic beverage district, sales</section><section>Amusement, game room</section><section>Animals, birds, and tropical fish, retail only</section><section>Antique shops</section><section>Apparel sales, rentals</section><section>Apartment house</section><section>Appliance and fixture sales (no service)</section><section>Appraisers (no merchandise)</section><section>Archery range</section><section>Art gallery</section><section>Art goods and bric-a-brac shops</section><section>Artist studios</section><section>Auction sales (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Auditoriums</section><section>Bait and tackle shop</section><section>Bakeries, retail</section><section>Bakeries, wholesale</section><section>Banks</section><section>Barbecue restaurants, stands, pits (wood for cooking) drive-in theaters</section><section>Barbershop</section><section>Bars</section><section>Baseball field</section><section>Bath and massage parlors</section><section>Bathing beaches</section><section>Bicycle sales (no service)</section><section>Billiard parlor/pool hall</section><section>Bindery (books, publications, etc.)</section><section>Bingo</section><section>Boat piers, docks</section><section>Book store (new and used)</section><section>Bottled gas storage (liquefied petroleum gas and natural gas only)</section><section>Bowling alleys</section><section>Box lunches—Wholesale and retail with delivery trucks (no truck maintenance)</section><section>Broadcasting studios (radio and TV, including transmitting station and tower, incidental electrical generation by LP or natural gas only)</section><section>Business machines sales (typewriters, calculators, etc.) (no service)</section><section>Camps</section><section>Card club/public</section><section>Card shops</section><section>Carpet sales</section><section>Caterers</section><section>Churches</section><section>Cigar making and sales</section><section>Cigarette vending</section><section>Clubs (private)</section><section>Coin laundries (no dry cleaning machines)</section><section>Coin shop</section><section>Cold storage warehouses and pre-cooling plants</section><section>Colleges (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Computer service</section><section>Concrete, cement, clay products—Storage and sales (no vehicle maintenance; no on-site fuel storage)</section><section>Confectionery (and ice cream stores)</section><section>Conservatories</section><section>Convent</section><section>Convention halls</section><section>Costuming shops</section><section>Curio stores</section><section>Dance halls, schools, academies</section><section>Day camp</section><section>Day care, nursery</section><section>Department store</section><section>Dependent children (home for)</section><section>Drive shop</section><section>Docks, piers—Boat</section><section>Dog obedience training, training tracks, schools</section><section>Dormitories</section><section>Drapery stores, drapery making</section><section>Dressed poultry and sea food stores</section><section>Drive-through banks and restaurants</section><section>Drug store</section><section>Dry cleaning (no cleaning on premises)</section><section>Dynamite storage</section><section>Electric substations</section><section>Electrolysis office (removal of hair by electrolytic process)</section><section>Employment agencies</section><section>Entrance gates</section><section>Escort service</section><section>Farms</section><section>Fire station (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Fishing camps</section><section>Fish houses, market, smoking</section><section>Fish, tropical, aquariums (retail sales only)</section><section>Flea market</section><section>Florist shops</section><section>Flower importers</section><section>Food distribution (no on-site vehicle maintenance)</section><section>Food sales</section><section>Foster home</section><section>Fraternities</section><section>Fruit packing, fruit stores, fruit stands</section><section>Furniture sales, rental and storage (no restoration, no manufacturing)</section><section>Furriers (sales and storage)</section><section>Garment manufacturing (no dyeing)</section><section>Gas (natural gas, LP gas including distribution system and bottling plant)</section><section>Gift stores</section><section>Glass blowing</section><section>Golf course, clubhouse</section><section>Golf driving range</section><section>Grocery store</section><section>Gun shop</section><section>Haberdashery</section><section>Hall for hire</section><section>Handball court</section><section>Health spa</section><section>Homes for dependent children</section><section>Hotels, motels</section><section>Houses of worship</section><section>Ice cream stores</section><section>Ice manufacturing, distributing (emergency electrical generation by LP or natural gas only)</section><section>Import-export office</section><section>Insurance office</section><section>Interior decorators office, showroom</section><section>Jai alai</section><section>Jewelry sales (no manufacturing)</section><section>Judo and karate instructions</section><section>Key shop</section><section>Kindergartens, day care</section><section>Lake excavation</section><section>Laundries (all types, no dry cleaning)</section><section>Leather goods stores (retail)</section><section>Libraries (public)</section><section>Limestone quarrying, rock crushing and aggregate plants ancillary to section in connection with limestone quarrying (no on-site fuel storage except that the use of fuels and lubricants and LP and natural gas storage are permitted)</section><section>Liquefied petroleum (LP) gas</section><section>Liquor package stores</section><section>Livery stable</section><section>Lodges (private)</section><section>Lounges</section><section>Luggage sales</section><section>Lunches (packaging, catering)</section><section>Mail order office</section><section>Massage parlor</section><section>Meat market</section><section>Men's store</section><section>Messenger office</section><section>Milk store (drive-in)</section><section>Miniature golf course</section><section>Mission</section><section>Mobile homes</section><section>Mobile homes, sales (no manufacturing or repair; and no motor homes or recreational vehicles)</section><section>Monastery</section><section>Motel</section><section>Modeling (agencies, schools)</section><section>Motion picture studio (no film developing)</section><section>Motion picture theatre, indoor and outdoor</section><section>Motion pictures and equipment, sales and rental (no equipment servicing, no film developing)</section><section>Moving and storage company (no on-site vehicle maintenance)</section><section>Municipal recreation building</section><section>Museums, public</section><section>Music stores, teaching</section><section>Newsstand</section><section>Night club</section><section>Notions sales</section><section>Office building</section><section>Office, professional</section><section>Open air theaters</section><section>Optical stores</section><section>Package stores</section><section>Palmistry</section><section>Paneling (wall/retail sales)</section><section>Paper salvage</section><section>Park or playground, public or private</section><section>Parking lot, parking garage (no auto pound, no tow yard, no on-site vehicle repair)</section><section>Passenger stations (railroad, bus)</section><section>Pawn shops (swap shops)</section><section>Pet shops, retail sales only (in air conditioned building)</section><section>Pharmaceuticals (retail)</section><section>Photographic studio (no developing, no printing)</section><section>Pillow renovating</section><section>Plant sales (no propagation)</section><section>Plaster products</section><section>Plasterers, storage area</section><section>Police station</section><section>Pool rooms</section><section>Post office</section><section>Pottery (retail sales only/no manufacturing)</section><section>Private clubs</section><section>Produce or fruit market</section><section>Professional and semiprofessional offices (no medical laboratory or clinic)</section><section>Public art galleries, museums</section><section>Racquet ball clubs</section><section>Radio, broadcasting station, studio, transmitting station/tower (emergency electrical power by LP or natural gas only)</section><section>Railroad and bus passenger stations (no freight terminal, no vehicle maintenance)</section><section>Real estate office</section><section>Recording studios</section><section>Recreational facilities</section><section>Rentals (household equipment, appliances, tools, hardware, etc.) (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Residential uses</section><section>Restaurants, including outdoor patios and service</section><section>Retirement villages</section><section>Rifle, pistol range</section><section>Rock and sand yards</section><section>Rock yards (crushing)</section><section>Saloons and bars</section><section>Savings and loan associations</section><section>Schools (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Seafood stores</section><section>Secondhand stores (inside only)</section><section>Shoe store (no manufacturing)</section><section>Shooting gallery</section><section>Shooting range, trap and skeet</section><section>Shopping center (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Showrooms, salesrooms (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Skating rink</section><section>Sororities</section><section>Souvenir stores</section><section>Sporting goods store</section><section>Stationery stores</section><section>Storage warehouse (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Swap shops</section><section>Swimming pools</section><section>Synagogues</section><section>Tailor shops</section><section>Tattoo parlor</section><section>Telegraph stations (emergency electrical power by LP or natural gas only)</section><section>Telephone answering service</section><section>Telephone exchange</section><section>Television (broadcasting studio)</section><section>Tennis courts</section><section>Textile sales</section><section>Theaters</section><section>Tile sales (no manufacturing)</section><section>Tourist attractions (no hazardous materials)</section><section>Trading post</section><section>Trailer park</section><section>Travel agency</section><section>Upholstery shop</section><section>Utilities: Public and private water production, treatment and distribution facilities; and sewage except that wastewater treatment plants are not permitted (emergency electrical power by LP or natural gas only)</section><section>Vegetable stands</section><section>Wall paper, paneling (retail sales)</section><section>Warehouses (storage of food, fodder, apparel, and other nonhazardous materials)</section><section>Watchman's quarters</section><section>Water tanks or towers</section><section>Water treatment plants (emergency electrical power by LP or natural gas only)</section><section>Wearing apparel stores (sales, rentals)</section><section>Wholesale salesrooms and attendant storage rooms (no hazardous materials)</section></section></section><section prefix='(11)'>Prohibition of resources recovery and management facility within wellfield protection areas. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant, modify or issue any permit (except for renewal of valid operating permits, issued pursuant to this chapter, no later than March 12, 1987), certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plan, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any resource recovery and management facility within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well after December 12, 1986, unless said resource recovery and management facility was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to June 25, 1986 and obtained a valid operating permit issued pursuant to this chapter no later than March 12, 1987 or, in the case of a resource recovery and management facility within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to the effective date of this ordinance.<section>Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no County or municipal officer, agent, employee or Board shall approve, grant, modify or issue any permit (except for renewal of valid operating permits issued pursuant to this chapter, renewed no later than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80]), certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership), platting action (final plat, waiver of plat or equivalent municipal platting action) or zoning action (district boundary change, unusual use, use variance or equivalent municipal zoning action) for any resource recovery and management facility (unless the facility's primary purpose is to collect paper, glass, plastics or aluminium for transport out of the West Wellfield Interim protection area or the facility provides composting for on-site organic plant materials at plant nurseries) within the West Wellfield Interim protection area after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80], unless said resource recovery and management facility was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] and obtained a valid operating permit issued pursuant to this chapter no later than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80].</section><section>Furthermore, notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any resource recovery and management facility within the Northwest Wellfield protection area or within the maximum day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Alexander Orr Wellfield, Snapper Creek Wellfield, Southwest Wellfield, Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, John E. Preston Wellfield, or Hialeah Wellfield, or within the basic wellfield protection area of any public utility potable water supply well after December 12, 1986, unless said resource recovery and management facility was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to June 25, 1986 and obtained a valid operating permit pursuant to this chapter, no later than March 12, 1987 or, in the case of a resource recovery and management facility within the outer wellfield protection zone of the South Miami Heights Wellfield Complex, was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to the effective date of this ordinance.</section><section>Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any resources recovery and management facility within the West Wellfield Interim protection area after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80], unless said resource recovery and management facility was in operation and had obtained all other applicable permits prior to the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80] and obtained a valid operating permit pursuant to this chapter, no later than ninety (90) days after the effective date of this ordinance [Ordinance No. 89-80].</section></section></section><section>TABLE A-1 Residential Property Served by Septic Tank and Using Public Water Supply</section><section>TABLE A-2 Residential Property Served by Septic Tank and Not Using Public Water Supply</section><section>TABLE A-3 Nonresidential Property Served by Septic Tank, Using Public Water Supply, and Not Using, Generating, Handling, Disposing, Discharging or Storing Hazardous Materials</section><section>TABLE INSET:</section><section>TABLE A-4 Nonresidential Property Served by Septic Tank, Not Using Public Water Supply, and Not Using, Generating, Handling, Storing, Disposing or Discharging Hazardous Materials</section><section>TABLE B-1 Residential Property Served by Sanitary Sewers; Nonresidential Property Served by Sanitary Sewers and Not Using, Generating, Handling, Disposing, Discharging or Storing Hazardous Materials</section><section>TABLE C-1 Allowable Storm Water Disposal Methods for Residential and Nonresidential Property</section><section> </section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 06-125, § 3, 9-12-06; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>