<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. WATER AND SOIL QUALITY</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00025' order_by='00025' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WATER QUALITY, WASTEWATER AND SANITARY SEWER PRETREATMENT STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-42.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Sanitary sewer system collection and transmission systems.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003309</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-42.2. Sanitary sewer system collection and transmission systems.<section prefix='(1)'>Existing gravity sanitary sewer requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>Each publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system shall be evaluated in order to identify and reduce infiltration and inflow into the sanitary sewer collection system. The person responsible for the sewer system's operation shall implement a sewer system evaluation survey (SSES) and, if required, a rehabilitation program, incorporating the provisions and requirements set forth in the U.S. EPA's Sewer System Infrastructure Analysis and Rehabilitation Handbook (October 1991, EPA/625/6-91/030), designed to identify and reduce sewer system infiltration and inflow to a level which meets the standards set forth in Section 24-42.2(1)(d). Such evaluation activities shall be conducted in a manner so that the total length of the gravity sewer lines and associated manholes in the sanitary sewer collection system is evaluated during the first five-year period of the program, and every ten-year period thereafter. Alternatively, the person responsible for the sewer system's operation shall, within forty-five (45) days after the effective date of this section, submit to the Director or the Director's designee for the Director's or the Director's designee's review and approval a report which provides a detailed description of a sewer system evaluation survey and rehabilitation program which incorporates the provisions and requirements set forth in the U.S. EPA's Sewer System Infrastructure Analysis and Rehabilitation Handbook (October, 1991 EPA/626/6-91/030) and which, when implemented, provides effective and substantial compliance with the requirements of this section of the Code. Said report shall include, in addition to any of the above requirements, decision making criteria, procedures and protocols for prioritization of the evaluation of gravity sewer lines and associated manholes, and for the selection of rehabilitation methods to be used. Upon its approval, the program shall be implemented in a manner so that the sewer system evaluation survey is conducted on the total length of the gravity sewer lines and associated manholes during the first five-year period of the program and every ten-year period thereafter. For purpose of compliance with either alternative, infiltration and inflow evaluations and rehabilitation work performed between July 1, 1992 and the effective date of this section can be credited towards the first five-year requirements provided the person responsible for the sewer system's operation submits to the Director or the Director's designee, for the Director's or the Director's designee's review and approval, a report detailing the work performed and the results obtained as required under Section 24-42.2(1)(f)(iv).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Those portions of a sewage lateral connection which are the responsibility of the private property owner as identified by policy or ordinance of the publicly-owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system, or when no such identification exists, the portions of lateral located upon privately owned real property, are the responsibility of the private real property owner who shall insure the proper operation, maintenance and repair of said portions of the sewage lateral connection. Where an evaluation pursuant to Section 24-42.2(1)(a) above indicates that a privately owned portion of a sewage lateral connection is a source of infiltration or inflow, or both, to a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer, the owner or operator of the sanitary sewer collection system shall report to the Director or the Director's designee the source of the infiltration or inflow within thirty (30) days from the date of discovery of said discharges. The Director or the Director's designee shall commence enforcement actions, if required, to cause the cessation of the infiltration or inflow.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding any other provision in this section, all publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems shall participate in a County-wide, regional rainfall dependent peak flow management study. Said peak flow management study shall, at a minimum, perform the following functions: (a) characterize infiltration and inflow of water into the sanitary sewer collection system; (b) predict peak flows to each pump station in the sanitary sewer collection system; and (c) assess each pump station's ability to manage peak flows with the back-up pump out-of-service. Upon implementation of a peak flow management study the person responsible for the operation of the publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system shall submit to the Director or the Director's designee the results of said study along with a plan of corrective actions and schedule of implementation for each and every pump station within the sanitary sewer collection system which was identified as not capable of managing peak flows with the back-up pump out-of-service.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The sewer system infiltration and inflow rehabilitation programs shall be sufficient to insure that sewer system infiltration and inflow into the rehabilitated sanitary sewer collection system shall be less than five thousand (5,000) gallons per inch pipe diameter per day per mile of pipe and laterals, or complies with best management practices as required by the U.S. EPA's Sewer System Infrastructure Analysis and Rehabilitation Handbook (October 1991, EPA/625/6-91/030).</section><section prefix='(e)'>In the event that implementation of the initial sewer system infiltration and inflow rehabilitation programs fail to achieve the performance standards established in this section, the person responsible for the system's operation may, in lieu of performing additional rehabilitation, submit a cost-benefit analysis which analyzes the feasibility of performing additional rehabilitation to achieve said performance standards. If the Director or the Director's designee determines that there is no technically feasible, economically reasonable means of compliance, then no further rehabilitation shall be required.</section><section prefix='(f)'>All persons operating a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer system shall provide the following reports to the Director or the Director's designee.<section prefix='(i)'>The daily average pump station operating time and the multiple and variable speed daily average pump station power consumption, as applicable, for each pump station in the sanitary sewer system shall be reported to the Director or the Director's designee on a monthly basis no later than the seventh day after the end of the preceding monthly reporting period. The report shall be in such form as prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee. The report shall include an explanation for any single event, Act of God, or other documentable reason which leads to excessive pump station operating time or power consumption. These can be cause for exclusion of such data from the nominal average pump operating time calculations.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The existence of stormwater discharges into any publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system shall be reported to the Director or the Director's designee within thirty (30) days from the date of discovery of said discharges by the person responsible for the operation of said system. The status of corrective actions to eliminate stormwater discharges into any sanitary sewer collection system shall be reported by the Director or the Director's designee semiannually, January 1 and July 1 of each year, to the person responsible for the operation of said system.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>An annual report to the Director or the Director's designee which sets forth a map and a list of all sewer service areas and sewer subsystems including the total length (in feet) of gravity sewer lines according to pipe diameter and type of material and number of manholes in each service area. This information shall be submitted only if there have been changes in the service areas.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>An annual report documenting all completed sewer system evaluations and rehabilitation work, as well as a schedule for any proposed rehabilitation work shall be submitted to the Director or the Director's designee no later than thirty (30) days after the end of each calendar year. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any and all rehabilitation work proposed to correct deficiencies identified during the sewer system evaluation survey shall be completed within four (4) years after completion of the evaluation work, or unless a revised schedule is approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Monitoring requirements.<section prefix='(a)'>All publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems shall provide a properly functioning meter for each pump in each and every pump station which measures either elapsed pump operating time or power consumption for each pump station or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems shall have the capacity or capability to monitor their pump stations in a manner so as to prevent overflows.<section prefix='(i)'>All pump stations shall, at a minimum, install alarm or monitoring equipment which reports the following information:<section prefix='a.'>High water level alarms in wet wells;</section><section prefix='b.'>Pump station power failures.</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>All system operators shall monitor their systems in a manner that allows sufficient response time to correct the detected problem prior to overflow occurring or to minimize the extent of an overflow.</section></section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Pump station inspection and repairs.<section prefix='(a)'>All publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer system pump stations shall be inspected annually for the purpose of identifying any equipment malfunction and physical deficiencies that could lead to equipment malfunctions. All persons operating any and all publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer pump stations shall complete the correction of all equipment malfunctions and physical deficiencies that could lead to equipment malfunctions identified during the pump station inspections no later than six (6) months after the date during which the inspection was completed. If an equipment malfunction or physical deficiency causes or contributes to an overflow condition, correction or repair of the malfunction or deficiency shall be completed no later than sixty (60) days from the date that the overflow condition is identified.</section><section prefix='(b)'>In the event that the person responsible for the operation of any publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer pump station determines that a pump station which has caused or contributed to an overflow condition, should be upgraded, rather than repaired as set forth in (1) above, said person shall, within thirty (30) days of the date the overflow condition is identified, submit to the Director or the Director's designee for approval a plan for the upgrade along with a proposed schedule of implementation.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Collection and transmission system model. All publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems shall participate in a County-wide, regional computerized collection and transmission system model or models to: i) assist in the development and implementation of operation and maintenance procedures to optimize transmission capacity within the collection system; and ii) evaluate the impact of infiltration and inflow rehabilitation programs, proposed system modifications, upgrades and expansions to the transmission capacity and performance of the collection system. The design and development of the model required herein shall be approved by the Director or the Director's designee prior to implementation.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Maintenance.<section prefix='(a)'>All publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems shall maintain their respective systems in a manner so as to prevent or minimize the possibility of overflows.</section><section prefix='(b)'>All publicly or privately owned and operated sanitary sewer collection systems shall have a written maintenance plan including, but not limited to, inspection procedures preventative maintenance schedules, corrective maintenance procedures and reporting procedures.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Spare parts. All publicly owned or operated sanitary sewer collection systems shall, maintain an inventory of spare parts or suppliers and vendors necessary to prevent sustained sewage spills, overflows and surcharge conditions resulting from equipment malfunction or deterioration. Certain critical parts may be secured from vendors or other systems on an as-needed basis provided, however, that the overall system integrity is maintained.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Exemptions. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any publicly owned and operated sanitary sewer collection system which operates a federal or state permitted wastewater treatment facility and which discharges wastewater to the County's regional system on an emergency basis only, will not be required to comply with the provisions set forth in Section 24-42.2(1) through (6).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>