<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WORK IN CANAL RIGHTS-OF WAY, TIDAL WATERS, SUBMERGED BAY-BOTTOM LANDS, AND WETLANDS; DEWATERING; CONSTRUCTION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.24</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibition of non-water-dependent fixed structures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003388</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-48.24. Prohibition of non-water-dependent fixed structures.<section>It shall be unlawful for any person to construct, place, install, maintain, permit, allow, suffer or cause the construction, placement, installation, maintenance or existence of any fixed structure in, on, over or upon any of the tidal waters of Miami-Dade County which does not have a water-dependent use. Fixed structures which do not have a water-dependent use include, but are not limited to, residences, offices, hotels, motels, restaurants, lounges, retail or wholesale stores, club houses, helicopter pads, meeting facilities, commercial signs, transmitting or receiving antennas and towers, or storage or parking facilities. This prohibition shall not apply to fixed structures that were fully permitted on the effective date of this section or to their repair providing permits are obtained.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>