<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. WATER AND SOIL QUALITY</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00028' order_by='00028' level='4'>DIVISION 4. REGULATION OF UNDERGROUND STORAGE FACILITIES, LIQUID WASTE TRANSPORTERS, AND METAL RECYCLING FACILITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-46</section_number>
<catch_line>Regulation of liquid waste transporters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003364</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-46. Regulation of liquid waste transporters.<section prefix='(1)'>It shall be unlawful for any person to permit, cause, allow, let or suffer the transportation within Miami-Dade County of any liquid waste without having a valid liquid waste transporter operating permit issued by the Director or the Director's designee pursuant to Section 24-18.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Director or the Director's designee shall approve, deny, or approve with conditions, limitations or restrictions any application for a liquid waste transporter operating permit. Violations of any permit condition, limitation or restriction shall constitute a violation of the provisions of this chapter. The Director or the Director's designee may suspend or revoke a liquid waste transporter operating permit for failure to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter. The criterion for issuance of the operating permit pursuant to this section is compliance with Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County. In addition to the liquid waste transporter operating permit, the Director, or the Director's designee, shall issue numbered stickers which shall be visibly posted on each vehicle permitted to transport liquid waste.</section><section prefix='(3)'>All applications for permits issued pursuant to this section shall be on a form prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee and accompanied by a fee which shall be established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>The permit fee payable hereunder shall be deposited in a separate county fund and shall be used exclusively by the Department to pay for the costs of environmental services to and environmental regulation of liquid waste transportation in Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All operating permits required by this chapter shall be in addition to any other permits, registrations or occupational licenses which may be required by federal, State or local law. The Director, or the Director's designee, in his or her discretion, may require conditions, limitations or restrictions as part of the operating permit if said conditions, limitations and restrictions are consistent with the requirements of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Monthly reporting required. All liquid waste transporters shall submit on a monthly basis to the Director or the Director's designee, on a form prescribed by the Department all information required by any conditions, limitations or restrictions which are part of the liquid waste transporter's operating permit.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Immediate reporting required. Any liquid waste transporter who causes, permits, lets, allows, or suffers any liquid waste accident, liquid waste spill, or other liquid waste discharge anywhere within the boundaries of Miami-Dade County, shall immediately report the same to the Department.</section><section prefix='(7)'>It shall be unlawful for any liquid waste transporter to dump, dispose, throw, drain, run, leak or otherwise discharge, or to allow, cause, permit, let, or suffer to be dumped, disposed, thrown, drained, run, leaked or otherwise discharged any liquid waste or solid waste into a sanitary sewer, any type of manhole, storm sewer, catch basin, french drain, disposal well, soakage pit, solid waste transfer or disposal facility, recycling facility, waste oil facility or similar structure or on to or into the ground, or into any of the waters of this county, or at any other place in Miami-Dade County unless said place is a sewage treatment plant or industrial waste treatment plant or a resource recovery and management facility approved by the Director or the Director's designee to receive said liquid or solid wastes and unless the liquid waste transporter's operating permit authorizes said place for disposal.</section><section prefix='(8)'>No person shall utilize a liquid waste transporter unless the liquid waste transporter has a valid operating permit issued by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='(9)'>The following activities shall be exempt from the provisions of this ordinance:<section prefix='(a)'>The on site transportation of liquid waste to a place within the boundaries of a particular facility, location, property or site.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The transportation of fully containerized and hermetically-sealed receptacles approved by the State of Florida Department of Transportation, provided said transportation does not commence or end in Miami-Dade County.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>