<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='4'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Owner-builder permits in lieu of owner-contractor permits.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003331</order_by>
<text><section>At the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee, owner-builder permits may be issued for the following types of work requiring a class I permit, and thereby waive the requirement that the permit be issued jointly to the owner and a contractor holding an applicable certificate of competency:<section prefix='(1)'>Repair of seawalls: Repair of seawalls or bulkheads at the mean high water line or at their existing location (excluding pile-driving operations and/or panel installations).</section><section prefix='(2)'>Placement of riprap: The placement of riprap in front of an existing or new seawall, bulkhead or shoreline, provided there is no adverse environmental impact associated with the project.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Where the upland property is zoned as single-family residential:<section prefix='(a)'>Repair, replacement or restoration of docks which are limited to or less than their original dimensions and which together with associated tie-up facilities, do not protrude into the water more than twenty-five (25) percent of the width of the waterway (excluding pile-driving operations and any associated dredging and filling).</section><section prefix='(b)'>Installation of buoys, when it is determined that the proposed installation will not present a hazard to navigation.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Other work that is nonstructural in nature.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history></law>