<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00014' order_by='00014' level='4'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-49.6</section_number>
<catch_line>Tree relocation standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003357</order_by>
<text><section>The relocation of any tree that is subject to the provisions of this article shall be consistent with the following minimum standards:<section prefix='(1)'>Trees other than palms:<section prefix='(a)'>Tree roots shall be severed in such a manner as to provide a root ball which is sufficient to ensure survival of the tree when relocated. A sufficiently-sized planting hole shall be provided at the relocation site to ensure successful regrowth.</section><section prefix='(b)'>After root severing, adequate time shall be allowed prior to replanting to ensure survival of the tree(s). After root severing and prior to relocation, tree(s) shall be watered a minimum of twice weekly. After relocation, tree(s) shall be watered a minimum of twice weekly until the tree(s) are established.</section><section prefix='(c)'>During removal and transportation of the tree, the root ball and vegetative portions of the tree shall be protected from damage from wind or injury.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any tree that dies or becomes nonviable within one (1) year of relocation shall be replaced according to the standards set forth in Section 24-49.4(2).</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Palms:<section prefix='(a)'>A ball of earth at least one (1) foot from the base of the tree shall be moved with the tree.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Fronds shall be securely tied around the bud prior to relocation and shall remain securely tied around the bud during the entire relocation process and for a minimum of one (1) week after relocation.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The bud shall be protected from damage or injury during relocation.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any palm that dies or becomes nonviable within one (1) year of relocation shall be replaced according to the standards set forth in Section 24-49.4(2).</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history></law>