<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WORK IN CANAL RIGHTS-OF WAY, TIDAL WATERS, SUBMERGED BAY-BOTTOM LANDS, AND WETLANDS; DEWATERING; CONSTRUCTION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Mitigation plans for projects otherwise acceptable but having adverse environmental impact.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003368</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-48.4. Mitigation plans for projects otherwise acceptable but having adverse environmental impact.<section>For any project that is otherwise acceptable under the evaluation factors contained herein and permittable under all applicable laws, but that nevertheless results in adverse environmental impact, the applicant shall be required to mitigate this impact. The purpose of mitigation is solely to compensate for unavoidable adverse environmental impacts. Mitigation should not be used to make an otherwise nonpermittable project permittable. Mitigation plans must maximize the preservation of existing natural resources. In determining mitigation procedures the term mitigation includes the following methods, in the order of priority in which they should be utilized:<section prefix='(1)'>Avoiding the impact altogether by not taking a certain action or parts of an action;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Minimizing impacts by limiting the degree or magnitude of the action or its implementation;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Rectifying the impact by repairing, rehabilitating, or restoring the affected environment;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Reducing or eliminating the impact over time by preservation and maintenance operations during the life of the action;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Compensating for the impact by replacing or providing substitute resources or environments.</section></section><section>The Department of Environmental Resources Management shall adopt rules by ordinance to implement the foregoing evaluation factors.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history></law>