<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='4'>DIVISION 2. TREE PRESERVATION AND PROTECTION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-49.9</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibited plant species and controlled plant species.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003401</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-49.9. Prohibited plant species and controlled plant species.<section prefix='(1)'>Controlled plant species listed in the Miami-Dade County Landscape Manual on the effective date of this ordinance shall not be planted within 500 feet of native plant communities as defined pursuant to Section 18-3, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida. Additionally, the following exotic pest plant and nuisance species, with scientific nomenclature as set forth in Wunderlin, Richard P. and Hansen, Bruce F., Guide to the Vascular Plants of Florida, 2nd Ed. University of Florida Press, Gainesville, FL. (2003), a copy of which shall be maintained by the Director or Director's designee and available for review by the public, may not be sold, propagated or planted anywhere in Miami-Dade County. If present on a development or redevelopment site, they shall be removed prior to development or redevelopment, and their sale, propagation, planting, importation or transportation shall be prohibited. Pursuant to this subsection and in accordance with Chapter 19 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, developed sites shall be maintained to prevent the growth or accumulation of prohibited species including grass, weeds and non-native undergrowth.<section>(Rosary pea)</section><section>(Earleaf acacia)</section><section>(Red beadtree, red sandalwood)</section><section>(Woman's tongue, lebbeck tree, siris tree)</section><section>(Coral vine, queen's jewels)</section><section>(Scratchthroat, coral ardisia)</section><section>(Shoebutton, shoebutton ardisia)</section><section>(Javanese bishopwood, bishopwood, bischofia, toog)</section><section>(Australian pine, sheoak, beefwood)</section><section>(Dayflowering jessamine, day blooming jasmine, day jessamine)</section><section>(Camphortree, camphor tree)</section><section>(Asian nakedwood, leatherleaf, latherleaf)</section><section>(Carrotwood)</section><section>(Indian rosewood, sissoo)</section><section>(White yam, winged yam)</section><section>(Air potato, bitter yam, potato vine)</section><section>(Common water-hyacinth, water-hyacinth)</section><section>(Council tree, lofty fig, banyan tree, false banyan)</section><section>(Banyan tree, banyan fig, Indian banyan, East Indian fig tree, Bengal fig)</section><section>(Indian laurel, laurel fig, Malay banyan, Chinese banyan, glossy leaf banyan)*</section><section>(Governor's plum, Madagascar plum, batoko plum, ramonchi)</section><section>(Water thyme, hydrilla)</section><section>(Indian swampweed, green hygro)</section><section>(Trompetilla, West Indian marsh grass)</section><section>(Cogongrass)</section><section>(Water-spinach)</section><section>(Gold Coast jasmine)</section><section>(Brazilian jasmine, jazmin de trapo)</section><section>(White leadtree, lead tree, jumbie bean, tan-tan)</section><section>(Peruvian primrosewillow)</section><section>except (Climbing fern, e.g. Old World climbing fern, Japanese climbing fern)</section><section>(Catclaw vine)</section><section>(Punk tree, melaleuca, cajeput, paperbark tree, tea tree, swamp tea tree)</section><section>(Chinaberrytree, Chinaberry)</section><section>(yellow morning-glory, woodrose, Hawaiian woodrose)</section><section>(Mile-a-minute, bittervine)</section><section>(Black mimosa, Catclaw mimosa)</section><section>(Burmareed, silkreed)</section><section>(Sewervine, skunkvine, onion vine)</section><section>(Torpedograss)</section><section>(Elephantgrass, Napiergrass)</section><section>(Water lettuce)</section><section>var. (Kudzu)</section><section>(Rose myrtle, Downy rose-myrtle)</section><section>(Rose natalgrass, Natal grass)</section><section>(Castorbean, castor oil plant, palma christi, wonder tree)</section><section>(Popcorntree, Chinese tallowtree)</section><section>(Beach naupaka, scaevola, half-flower)</section><section>(Australian umbrella tree, octopus tree, Queensland umbrella tree)</section><section>(Brazilian pepper, Christmas berry tree, Florida holly)</section><section>var. (Valamuerto, Climbing cassia, Christmas cassia, Christmas senna)</section><section>(Aquatic soda apple, wetland nightshade)</section><section>(Tropical soda apple)</section><section>(Mahoe, sea hibiscus, yellow mahoe)</section><section>(Incised halberd fern)</section><section>(Portia tree, seaside mahoe, cork tree, false rosewood)</section><section>(Puncture vine, burrnut, Jamaican feverplant, billy-goat weed, large yellow caltrop)</section><section>(Paragrass)</section><section>* may be propagated for export outside of the State of Florida.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Definitions for Section 24-49.9(1), Sections 24-49.9(3)(a), 3(b), and 3(c):<section prefix='(a)'>Importation shall mean the conveyance by any means of plants into Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Planting shall mean the placing on or setting into the ground of live plant material.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Propagation shall mean the physical act of causing plants to multiply by any process of reproduction from plant stock.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Sale shall mean the act of transferring or conveying plants to a purchaser for consideration.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Transportation shall mean the act of carrying or conveying plants from one (1) place to another for the purpose of sale, planting, importation or propagation.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Variances.<section prefix='(a)'>A variance by the Director from the requirements or prohibitions of this section may be requested, subject to the conditions justifying variance approval outlined below in Section 24-49.9(3)(b). Said variance request shall be made in writing to the Director and shall include the following information:<section prefix='(i)'>Name and address of the person or persons requesting the variance.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Location of the property for which the variance is requested.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>A sketch or drawing indicating the location within the subject property where the planting or field propagation of the otherwise prohibited plant species will occur. (Container propagation shall be exempt from said sketch or drawing requirements.)</section><section prefix='(iv)'>The reason or reasons for requesting the variance.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The Director may, in the Director's discretion, issue a variance from the provisions of this subsection based upon the following factors:<section prefix='(i)'>Proximity of the subject planting or propagation to any environmentally sensitive areas (e.g., wetlands, hammocks, pinelands, dunes).</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Lack of appropriate alternative plant species to fulfill the same purpose or purposes for planting.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>The designation of a tree as a Historic Tree by the local Historic Preservation Board.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Compensatory actions proposed to offset impacts for any adverse environmental impact or cumulative adverse environmental impact which may result from granting the variance.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The Director shall issue or deny a variance request within thirty (30) days of receipt of the variance request, provided the required information described in Section 24-49.9(3)(a)(i) through (iv) above has been submitted.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 13-24, § 3, 3-5-13)</history></law>