<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WORK IN CANAL RIGHTS-OF WAY, TIDAL WATERS, SUBMERGED BAY-BOTTOM LANDS, AND WETLANDS; DEWATERING; CONSTRUCTION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.21</section_number>
<catch_line>Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin Plan.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003385</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-48.21. Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin Plan.<section>Except as provided in(5)(e), all work performed in the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin shall be consistent with the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Plan, which is hereby included by reference in its entirety. The Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners is directed to keep a copy of the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Plan on file as an attachment to this ordinance. All work in the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin shall be consistent with the goals, guidelines, standards, and project design criteria set forth in the Bird Drive Everglades Basin Plan to ensure the maintenance of, or mitigation for the loss of, biological resources. Work in the Bird Drive Everglades Wetland Basin shall also conform with the Bird Drive Everglades Fill Encroachment and Water Management Criteria which have been set forth to ensure proper water management.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history></law>