<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Application of chapter and time for compliance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003345</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-4. Application of chapter and time for compliance.<section prefix='(1)'>New facilities. On and after the effective date of this chapter, any person installing, constructing, or placing in operation for the first time any facility, equipment or process, the use of which will or may cause, or reasonably tend to cause, any air or water pollution as defined and controlled by this chapter, or who shall undertake the alterations, reconstruction or extension of existing facilities, equipment or processes in such a substantial manner as to materially increase the level or amount of air or water pollution, shall be subject to and required to comply with all the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Existing facilities. All facilities, equipment, plants and projects that are in actual use and operation on the effective date of this chapter shall have until and including January 1, 1968, to fully comply with and conform to the requirements of this chapter, provided that all existing facilities shall comply with, and shall not commit violations of, the following provisions of this chapter after January 1, 1964, namely: Section 24-5 (Nuisance); Section 24-42 (Toxic waste discharges); Section 24-41 (Black smoke emissions); Section 24-41.4 (Open burning); and Section 24-41.9 (Reduction of animal matter).</section><section prefix='(3)'>Intent. It is intended that the provisions of this chapter shall be applicable to all new facilities and to any major or substantial addition, enlargement or extension of existing facilities; that existing facilities shall have until January 1, 1965, to comply with the specific sections of this chapter enumerated in subsection (2) hereinabove; and that existing facilities shall have until January 1, 1968, to comply with all other sections or provisions of this chapter (except those specifically designated in subsection (2) hereof), subject only to variances or extensions of time for compliance granted pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Replacements. The replacement with identical or similar parts and minor changes that do not affect the character of the waste discharge or emission of air contaminants, or do not materially increase the existing amount of air or water pollution, shall not be considered as constituting the alteration, reconstruction or extension of an existing facility, but shall be considered as constituting an existing facility, for the purpose of this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>