<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='4'>ARTICLE III. WATER AND SOIL QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-42</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibitions against water pollution.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003307</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>PROHIBITIONS AGAINST DISCHARGE. It shall be unlawful for any person to throw, drain, run or otherwise discharge into any of the waters of this County, or to cause, permit or suffer to be thrown, run, drained, allowed to seep, or otherwise discharged into such water any organic or inorganic matter which shall:<section prefix='(a)'>Breach the values set forth in Section 24-42(2);</section><section prefix='(b)'>Cause water pollution as herein defined; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Cause a nuisance or sanitary nuisance as herein defined.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>EFFLUENT STANDARDS FOR MIAMI-DADE COUNTY. All sewage treatment plants and industrial waste treatment plants (except those discharging to approved ocean outfalls) shall effect ninety (90) percent treatment or better at the defined sampling point (24-44.2(1)). However, in no case shall the following effluent standards be exceeded (except where the standard is noted to be a minimum).</section><section>In waters other than fresh water, waste shall not increase natural background more than ten (10) percent.</section><section prefix='(3)'>DISCHARGES AFFECTING WATER QUALITY AND PROHIBITION OF POSITIVE DRAINAGE. It shall be unlawful for any person to dewater or to discharge sewage, industrial wastes, cooling water and solid wastes, or any other wastes into the waters of this County, including but not limited to surface water, tidal salt water estuaries, or ground water in such quantities, and of such characteristics as:<section prefix='(a)'>May cause the receiving waters, after mixing with the waste streams, to be of poorer quality than the water quality standards set forth in Section 24-42(4);</section><section prefix='(b)'>To cause water pollution as defined in Section 24-5; or</section><section prefix='(c)'>To cause a nuisance or sanitary nuisance as herein defined.<section>It shall be unlawful for any County or municipal officer, agent, employee or board to approve, grant, or issue any permit, or permit, allow, let or suffer the approval or issuance of any permit, which authorizes positive drainage without the prior written approval of the Director or the Director's designee. The Director or the Director's designee shall issue a written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determine, after reviewing data submitted by the applicant, that one (1) or more of the following conditions exist at the subject site:</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Inadequate size, shape or topographic characteristics of the site to provide full on-site disposal of stormwater.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Extremely poor soil seepage capacity which prevents full on-site disposal of stormwater.</section><section prefix='(f)'>An existing groundwater contamination plume under or in the vicinity of the subject site which will be adversely impacted by full on-site stormwater disposal.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>WATER QUALITY STANDARDS FOR MIAMI-DADE COUNTY:</section><section>Shall not cause the pH of the receiving waters to vary more than 1.0 unit. When the natural background pH lies outside the limits established, the introduction of a waste shall not displace the pH of the receiving waters more than 0.5 pH units from these standards.</section><section>Shall not be visible, defined as iridescence, or cause taste or odors.</section><section>Waste shall not increase natural background more than 10 percent.</section><section>Maximum MPN/100 ml in a surface water used as a drinking water supply shall be 100.</section><section>Maximum MPN/100 ml in a tidal water from which shellfish are harvested for human consumption shall be 70.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>