<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WORK IN CANAL RIGHTS-OF WAY, TIDAL WATERS, SUBMERGED BAY-BOTTOM LANDS, AND WETLANDS; DEWATERING; CONSTRUCTION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.10</section_number>
<catch_line>Maintenance of permitted work; abatement of hazardous conditions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003374</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-48.10. Maintenance of permitted work; abatement of hazardous conditions.<section>Any privately owned work or structure authorized by a permit issued pursuant to the requirements of this article shall be privately maintained by the applicant, his successors and assigns. Whenever, in the opinion of the Director, said work or structures are not maintained in such a manner as to prevent deterioration to the extent that they become a hazard to the public or to navigation, [or] an obstruction of flow, or prevent access for drainage maintenance purposes, or may damage adjacent property, then the Director shall notify the owner in writing to remedy the same by alteration, adjustment or removal at the owner's expense; provided, however, that within fifteen (15) days after receipt of written notice from the Director, the owner may appeal the matter by requesting in writing a hearing before the Environmental Quality Control Board. If no appeal is taken to the Environmental Quality Control Board and the owner has not performed remedial work within thirty (30) days from the date of such notice, or if an appeal is taken and the Board, after hearing and notice thereof, shall determine that remedial work is necessary and the owner does not perform the remedial work within the time established by the Board for the performance, the Director shall have the same or any other remedial work that in the Director's opinion will alleviate or eliminate the situation, including, but not limited to, total demolition of the structure, performed at the County's expense; and the County shall have a lien prior in dignity to all other liens, excepting city and County taxes and liens of equal dignity therewith, on the real property of the owner to the extent of the cost to the County, including administrative cost for the remedial work. Notice of such lien, executed in the name of the County Commission, shall be recorded in the proper books kept by the Clerk of the Circuit Court of the County and shall remain in full force and effect for a period of twenty (20) years from the date thereof, unless sooner paid and satisfied; and the Director shall, in writing, advise the County Attorney at least one (1) year prior to the expiration of the twenty-year period of any such liens that have not been satisfied, in order that the same may be foreclosed if necessary.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>