<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WORK IN CANAL RIGHTS-OF WAY, TIDAL WATERS, SUBMERGED BAY-BOTTOM LANDS, AND WETLANDS; DEWATERING; CONSTRUCTION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.11</section_number>
<catch_line>Inspection of permit work; notice of failure to comply with approved plans and specifications.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003432</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-48.11. Inspection of permit work; notice of failure to comply with approved plans and specifications.<section prefix='(1)'>Any duly authorized representative of the Department may enter and inspect any property, premises or place, except a building, on or at which work is located or is being conducted, at any reasonable time for the purpose of ascertaining the state of compliance with this article, or rules and regulations of the Department. No person shall refuse immediate entry or access to any authorized representative of the Department who requests such entry or access for the purpose of inspection, and who presents appropriate credentials; nor shall any person obstruct, hamper or interfere with any such inspection. If requested, the owner of the premises shall receive a report setting forth all facts found which relate to compliance status.</section><section prefix='(2)'>During work for which a permit has been issued, the Department shall make periodic inspections to insure conformity with the approved plans and specifications referred to in Section 24-48.5 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(3)'>If during the work, the Department finds that the work is not being done in accordance with the said approved plans and specifications, it shall give the permittee and/or contractor and the engineer of record written notice, stating with which particulars of the approved plans and specifications the work is not in compliance. Failure to act in accordance with the requirements of the Department after receipt of written notice may result in the initiation of revocation proceedings in accordance with Section 24-48.13 of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>