<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WORK IN CANAL RIGHTS-OF WAY, TIDAL WATERS, SUBMERGED BAY-BOTTOM LANDS, AND WETLANDS; DEWATERING; CONSTRUCTION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.19</section_number>
<catch_line>Permit issuance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003328</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-48.19. Permit issuance.<section>Approvals of class I, class II, class III, class IV, class V and class VI permits by the Board of County Commissioners shall only be valid for a period of thirty (30) months, in the case of rockmining, or for a period of eighteen (18) months, for all other work, from the date of the approval unless another time period is stated in the resolution granting approval. If the applicant has not obtained a permit issued by the Department within thirty (30) months, in the case of rockmining, or within eighteen (18) months, for all other work, from the date of the approval by the Board of County Commissioners or within the time period stated in the resolution granting approval, then a new application for a permit shall be filed. Upon the timely application of any person, other than the person seeking the permit, filed in a court of competent jurisdiction which seeks judicial review in accordance with of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, of a decision granting or granting with limitations, restrictions or conditions of any permit in this article, the time periods hereinabove shall be tolled until disposition of the judicial review. All approvals of class I, class II, class III and class IV permits by the Board of County Commissioners prior to December 7, 1990 for which the applicant has not obtained a permit issued by the Department within twelve (12) months from the effective date of this ordinance shall be null and void and no permit shall be issued by the Department.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>