<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WORK IN CANAL RIGHTS-OF WAY, TIDAL WATERS, SUBMERGED BAY-BOTTOM LANDS, AND WETLANDS; DEWATERING; CONSTRUCTION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.17</section_number>
<catch_line>Registration, examination, and certification requirements for professional mangrove trimmers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003326</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-48.17. Registration, examination, and certification requirements for professional mangrove trimmers.<section>Pursuant to the authority granted by Section 403.9326, Florida Statutes, and except for work that is not required to be performed by a Professional Mangrove Trimmer pursuant to Section 403.9326, Florida Statutes, it shall be unlawful for any person to perform mangrove trimming or to authorize, allow, suffer, permit, or supervise mangrove trimming anywhere in Miami-Dade County without first having registered with the Department and having paid the registration fee authorized by Section 403.9329, Florida Statutes, in an amount established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. Prior to undertaking to perform any trimming activities authorized under the exemption provided by Sections 403.9326(1)(b) and 403.9326(1)(c), Florida Statutes, a registered professional mangrove trimmer shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Provide written notice to the Department a minimum of ten (10) days prior to the commencement of trimming activities on each property. The notice shall include the location, the property owner's name, principal address and phone number, and the date of the proposed commencement of work. Notice shall be required prior to each separate trimming event; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Personally supervise the trimming activity; and thereafter notify the Department within twenty-four (24) hours if any mangroves are "altered" (as defined in Section 403.9325(1), F.S.) as a result of the work. The professional mangrove trimmer's registration shall be valid for a period of one (1) year and may be renewed by the Department prior to its expiration upon prior payment of the registration renewal fee in an amount established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section>Upon the effective date of the ordinance from which this section derives, all applicants for certification as professional mangrove trimmers shall be required to have passed an examination designed to test the applicant's knowledge and ability in this field. The Department shall offer a written, oral or practical examination, or a combination of the aforesaid. The fee for examination and certification shall be in an amount established by administrative order of the County Manager and approved by the Board of County Commissioners. A person who has paid the required fee and obtained certification shall be exempt from the registration requirements and fees described in of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for the time period the certification is valid.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history></law>