<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. WATER AND SOIL QUALITY</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00026' order_by='00026' level='4'>DIVISION 2. WELLFIELD PROTECTION, DOMESTIC WELL SYSTEMS AND POTABLE WATER STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-43.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Potable water standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003357</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-43.3. Potable water standards.<section prefix='(1)'>GENERAL PROHIBITIONS. It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation, private or public utility, to cause, permit or otherwise allow any potable water supply to breach the values set forth in Section 24-43.3(2).</section><section prefix='(2)'>POTABLE WATER STANDARDS FOR MIAMI-DADE COUNTY.<section prefix='(a)'>Bacteriological quality; sampling. Compliance with the bacteriological requirements of these standards shall be based on examinations of samples collected at representative points throughout the distribution system. The frequency of sampling and the location of sampling points shall be established by the Director or the Director's designee after investigation of the source, method of treatment, and protection of the water concerned. In no event shall the frequency be less than as set forth below:</section><section prefix='(b)'>Laboratories in which water examinations are made for required reports shall be subject to inspection at any time by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Bacterial limits. The presence of organisms of the coliform group as indicated by samples examined shall not exceed the following limits:<section prefix='(i)'>When ten (10) ml standard portions are examined not more than ten (10) percent in any month shall show the presence of the coliform group. The presence of the coliform group in three (3) or more ten (10) ml portions of a standard sample shall not be allowable if this occurs:<section prefix='1.'>In two (2) consecutive samples;</section><section prefix='2.'>In more than one (1) sample per month when less than twenty (20) are examined per month; or</section><section prefix='3.'>In more than five (5) percent of the samples when twenty (20) or more are examined per month.</section><section>When organisms of the coliform group occur in three (3) or more of the ten (10) ml portions of a single standard sample, daily samples from the same sampling point shall be collected promptly and examined until the results obtained from at least two (2) consecutive samples show the water to be of satisfactory quality.</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>When one hundred (100) ml standard portions are examined, not more than sixty (60) percent in any month shall show the presence of the coliform group. The presence of the coliform group in all five (5) of the one hundred (100) ml portions of a standard sample shall not be allowable if this occurs:<section prefix='1.'>In two (2) consecutive samples;</section><section prefix='2.'>In more than one (1) sample per month when less than five (5) are examined per month; or</section><section prefix='3.'>In more than twenty (20) percent of the samples when five (5) or more are examined per month.</section><section>When organisms of the coliform group occur in all five (5) of the one hundred (100) ml portions of a single standard sample, daily samples from the same sampling point shall be collected promptly and examined until the results obtained from at least two (2) consecutive samples show the water to be of satisfactory quality.</section></section><section prefix='(iii)'>When the membrane filter technique is used, the arithmetic mean coliform density of all standard samples examined per month shall not exceed one (1) per one hundred (100) ml. Coliform colonies per standard sample shall not exceed 3/50 ml, 4/100 ml, 7/200 ml, or 13/500 ml in:<section prefix='1.'>Two (2) consecutive samples;</section><section prefix='2.'>More than one (1) standard sample when less than twenty (20) are examined per month; or</section><section prefix='3.'>More than five (5) percent of the standard samples when twenty (20) or more are examined per month.</section><section>When coliform colonies in a single standard sample exceed the above values, daily samples from the same sampling point shall be collected promptly and examined until the results obtained from at least two (2) consecutive samples show the water to be of satisfactory quality.</section></section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Physical characteristics; sampling. The frequency and manner of sampling shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee. Under normal circumstances the Director or the Director's designee may require that samples be collected one (1) or more times per week from representative points in the distribution system and examined for turbidity, color, threshold odor, and taste.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Physical limits. The water shall contain no impurity which would cause offense to the sense of sight, taste, or smell. Under general use, the following limits shall not be exceeded:<section>Turbidity—5 nephelometric turbidity units</section><section>Color—15 units</section><section>Threshold odor number—3</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Chemical characteristics; sampling. The frequency and manner of sampling shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee. Under normal circumstances, analyses for substances listed in Section 24-43.3(2)(h) need be made only annually. If, however, there is some presumption of unfitness because of the presence of undesirable elements, compounds, or materials, periodic determinations for the suspected toxicant or material shall be made more frequently and an exhaustive sanitary survey shall be made to determine the source of the pollution. Where the concentration of a substance is not expected to increase in processing and distribution, available and acceptable source water analyses performed in accordance with standard methods may be used as evidence of compliance with these standards.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Chemical limits. The water shall not contain impurities in concentrations which may be hazardous to the health of the consumers. It should not be excessively corrosive to the water supply system. Substances used in its treatment shall not remain in the water in concentrations greater than required by good practice. Substances which may have deleterious physiological effect, or for which physiological effects are not known, shall not be introduced into the system in a manner which would permit them to reach the consumer. Each public water supply utility shall test the finished water produced by each of its water treatment plants on an annual basis for the materials identified as priority pollutants by the United States Environmental Protection Agency as set forth in Schedule A, attached hereto and made a part hereof [but not reproduced at length herein], and such other materials as may be designated by the Director or the Director's designee. Each of the other community water systems shall test the finished water produced by its water treatment system every third year for the aforesaid materials identified as priority pollutants by the United States Environmental Protection Agency, and such other materials as may be designated by the Director or the Director's designee.<section>The first of the previously mentioned analyses shall be performed, and the results submitted to the Director or the Director's designee, no later than one hundred fifty (150) days after the effective date of Ordinance No. 84-41. Subsequent analyses shall be performed, and the results submitted to the Director or the Director's designee, no later than July first of the respective year.</section><section>Analyses conducted to determine compliance with this section shall be made in accordance with an analytical method acceptable to the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with Schedule A, attached hereto and made a part hereof, and at the detection limits achievable using the specific technique. The laboratory performing these tests shall have appropriate experience in these types of drinking water analyses and shall be certified by the State of Florida.</section><section>After submittal of the test results to the utilities and community water systems for their review and comments at a public workshop, the Director or the Director's designee shall make available to the public thirty (30) days thereafter an annual publication of the test results. Said publication shall contain the test results of all public water supply utilities and other community water systems in Miami-Dade County including comments regarding the test results by the utilities and community water systems.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>The following chemical substances shall not be present in a water supply in excess of the listed concentrations:</section><section prefix='(i)'>The presence of the following substances in excess of the concentrations listed shall constitute grounds for rejection of raw water supply:</section><section prefix='(j)'>Analytical methods. Analytical methods to determine compliance with the requirements of these standards shall be those specified in Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Waste Water, sixteenth edition.</section><section prefix='(k)'>All public water supply systems shall employ an approved method of disinfection acceptable to the Director or the Director's designee. Such disinfection shall be accomplished continuously in such a manner as to assure the continued feeding of the disinfection agent.<section prefix='(i)'>Those systems utilizing gas chlorine shall provide duplex systems that will assure the continued application of chlorine to the water even as containers are expended and replaced;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Those systems utilizing chlorine shall maintain a minimum three-tenths (0.3) milligrams per liter as free chlorine throughout its distribution system. In no case shall a chlorine residual in excess of two (2.0) milligrams per liter be maintained in the distribution system;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Utilization of other methods of disinfection acceptable to the Director or the Director's designee shall have established limits set by the Director;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>The minimum amount of chlorine to be stored at the water treatment facility or immediately accessible to the facility shall be a thirty-day supply. In lieu of this requirement the utility may provide to the Director or the Director's designee copies of long term contracts indicating available quantity together with transportation contracts;</section><section prefix='(v)'>All public water supply systems shall provide to the Director or the Director's designee breakpoint chlorination curves for:<section prefix='1.'>All individual wells which are used as a supply of raw water;</section><section prefix='2.'>Composite breakpoint curves for the raw water supply used for average and maximum day demand.</section></section></section><section prefix='(l)'>Every public water supply shall install a suitable measuring device at each source of supply and at the point that water is pumped to the distribution system in order that a record may be maintained of the water produced and treated. The quantities indicated by these measuring devices shall be tabulated daily and recorded.</section><section prefix='(m)'>When the annual average of the maximum daily air temperatures for the location in which the public water system is situated is the following, the corresponding concentration of fluoride shall not be exceeded:</section><section prefix='(n)'>Public water supply systems cleaning and disinfection. No person, Board, or municipality charged with the management or control of a public water supply shall put into service any new plant, pumping station, main, standpipe, reservoir, tank, or other pipe or structure through which water is delivered to consumers for potable or household purposes, nor resume the use of any such structure, facilities, or main after it has been cleaned, until such structure, facilities or main has been effectively sterilized or disinfected. Provided, that this may not necessarily apply to mains, reservoirs, tanks, or other structures, the waters from which are subsequently treated or purified.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Adequate pressure shall be maintained in the mains to deliver the water for which they were designed, whether it be for fire, industrial, or domestic use. In no event, however, shall the pressure at the point of delivery to any customer fall below twenty (20) pounds per square inch, nor shall the static pressure exceed one hundred (100) pounds per square inch.</section><section prefix='(p)'>By-passing unlawful. Where a potable water treatment facility has been provided, it shall be unlawful to by-pass the facility or any part thereof. In the event of an emergency, the supplier may temporarily utilize a by-pass. However, it shall be unlawful to fail to immediately notify the Director or the Director's designee of such an emergency. Such notification shall not be a defense to any civil liability under this chapter.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Reserved.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Public water supply systems; cross-connections and use of dual supplies.<section prefix='(i)'>Certain cross-connections prohibited. No officers, Board, corporation, municipality or other persons having the management of a public water supply shall permit any physical connection between the distribution system of such supply and that of any other water supply unless such other supply is regularly examined as to its quality by those in charge of the public supply to which the connection is made and is also found to be safe and potable. This provision shall apply to all water distribution systems either inside or outside of any building or buildings.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Permissible arrangement where dual supplies are used. If a potable water supply is used as an auxiliary supply delivered to an elevated tank, or to a suction tank, which tank is also supplied with water from a source with which cross-connections are not permitted by Section 24-43.3(2)(r)(i), such tank shall be opened to atmospheric pressure and the potable water supply shall be discharged at an elevation above the high water line of the tank.</section></section><section prefix='(s)'>Facilities in actual use and operation as of the date of the enactment of this section which exceed the criteria set forth in any of the provisions of Section 24-43.3 hereof, certified by a competent state or county agency as a present or potential health hazard, shall be designated by the Director as priority public water supply areas. Upon such designation the Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Department and the County Manager shall initiate proceedings for the creation of a special taxing district for public water system for the elimination of the potable water wells therein or take such other commensurate steps as to assure the elimination of the potable water wells therein, on a timely basis.</section><section prefix='(t)'>All treatment facilities shall be designed to have a treatment capacity equal to maximum day demand.</section><section prefix='(u)'>Any cross-connections in the treatment facility or distribution system are to be eliminated upon direction of the Director, Environmental Resources Management. In the event such a cross-connection is maintained by a user after an order to disconnect is given by the Director or the Director's designee, the Director or the Director's designee may order the discontinuance of service by the utility to the user until the cross-connection is eliminated.</section><section prefix='(v)'>No water supply well shall be constructed or used until a written approval from the Director or the Director's designee has been received by the owner and/or driller of the well:<section prefix='(i)'>The Director or the Director's designee shall be notified by the well driller at least twenty-four (24) hours prior to initiating construction of a permitted well;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>In wells where the casing is driven it shall be known as drive pipe, and shall be equipped with couplings allowing for butt joints between lengths of casing. For wells in which the casing is not driven "merchant casing," standard pipes or pipe especially constructed for gravel wall wells will be acceptable;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Where telescoped casing is utilized, an approved watertight seal shall be made where increases or reductions occur in casing size. The initial stage of the telescope casing shall extend a minimum of thirty (30) feet into the groundwater table;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>When water is to be obtained from limestone strata, the casing shall extend sufficiently far into unbroken limestone to be seated firmly in it but in no case shall it be less than thirty (30) feet into the aquifer;</section><section prefix='(v)'>Wells drilled by the rotary method shall have an annular space sealed by the use of a neat cement grout at the bottom of the hole and to the surface by neat cement or other approved material;</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Once the construction of the well is completed it shall be protected at all times to prevent entrance of contaminating material until such time as the pump may be placed;</section><section prefix='(vii)'>The top of the casing shall be so constructed as to exclude any influent but shall not extend less than one (1) foot above the surface of the ground;</section><section prefix='(viii)'>A concrete pad shall be constructed around the well a minimum of twelve (12) inches thick, two (2) feet horizontal from the casing;</section><section prefix='(ix)'>Pump houses or pump pits shall be constructed so as to provide for positive drainage. Where such is not possible, sump pumps or an alternative acceptable to the Director or the Director's designee shall be provided. Such systems shall be installed as duplex systems;</section><section prefix='(x)'>Where provided, well vents shall be adequately protected;</section><section prefix='(xi)'>In those situations where suction lines from a well casing are indicated, the suction pipe shall be so constructed to prohibit inundation. Minimum requirement shall be twelve (12) inches of clearance between the invert and ground surface;</section><section prefix='(xii)'>A sampling tap shall be provided on the discharge of the well pump piping or in such a location as to assure a true raw water sample;</section><section prefix='(xiii)'>The use of dynamite for the construction of wells shall be prohibited;</section><section prefix='(xiv)'>Dug wells, infiltration galleries and other sources of water supply requiring rearrangement of natural features are hereby prohibited as a source of public water supply;</section><section prefix='(xv)'>The use of surface water as a raw water source is prohibited;</section><section prefix='(xvi)'>All wells shall be located on terrain not subject to ponding or flooding. Furthermore, the slope of the ground surface in the vicinity of the well(s) shall be away from the well. In level areas, well compacted earth shall be placed around the well so as to elevate the platform, pad or apron;</section><section prefix='(xvii)'>As far as is practical, wells shall be located on the upstream side of possible sources of pollution;</section><section prefix='(xviii)'>The minimum separation between a well or wells and possible sources of contamination shall be a function of the drawdown and radius of influence of the well or wells. It shall be the responsibility of the design engineer to present data showing the radius of influence and drawdown together with a sanitary survey of the area influenced by the well. Such a survey shall extend one-half (½) mile beyond the radius of influence of the well field. In the cases involving multiple wells the interference among wells shall be determined. It shall be the design engineer's responsibility to show that the top thirty (30) feet of the aquifer is not tapped by the well(s). In no case shall the well be located less than one hundred (100) horizontal feet from any source of contamination. However, the Director or the Director's designee shall have the power to require additional spacing when conditions justify;</section><section prefix='(xix)'>All wells shall be accessible for such attention as necessary;</section><section prefix='(xx)'>All wells shall be equipped with an opening suitable for introduction of a disinfecting agent and measurement of drawdown and static water level;</section><section prefix='(xxi)'>When using chlorine as a disinfecting agent, a quantity, at least equal to the volume of the casing, of a strength of fifty (50) milligrams per liter shall be injected into the well. The solution shall be permitted to stand a minimum of twenty-four (24) hours and then pumped out for a sufficient length of time to remove the disinfecting agent;</section><section prefix='(xxii)'>Once the well has been evacuated in accordance with subsection (21), a series of twenty (20) or more daily samples, twenty (20) series, shall be collected and submitted to the Division of Health laboratory, the well being pumped for a minimum of thirty (30) minutes each day at its proposed capacity just prior to collecting the samples. At the discretion of the Director or the Director's designee the samples may be reduced to duplicate daily samples for a minimum of ten (10) days. Such samples will necessitate pumping for a minimum of thirty (30) minutes as indicated above;</section><section prefix='(xxiii)'>Interpretation of the laboratory results in the well survey will be made in accordance with applicable parts of the water supply standards;</section><section prefix='(xxiv)'>Once the series of twenty (20) or more consecutive satisfactory samples have been collected a complete analysis shall be performed of the raw water for both physical and chemical characteristics of the complete analysis shall be furnished to the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 14-48, § 3, 5-6-14)</history></law>