<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00030' order_by='00030' level='4'>DIVISION 2. TREE PRESERVATION AND PROTECTION</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-49.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Permits generally.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003393</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-49.1. Permits generally.<section>Tree removal permits are required for the removal or relocation of any tree not specifically exempted under(4). The Department shall provide permit application forms which shall be used by permit applicants. An owner, agent of the owner, or lessee of a property may apply for a tree removal permit. If the permit application is a lessee or agent of the owner, a statement from the owner of the property indicating that the owner has no objection to the proposed tree removal shall be submitted with the application. The permit applicant shall submit to the Department a completed application form. Permit application forms shall be accompanied by two (2) sets of site plans which are subject to review and approval by the Department. The site plan shall include the locations of all existing tree resources and all proposed structures or utilities which may require removal or relocation of trees. The Department may require that said plans be prepared by either a landscape architect, architect or an engineer registered in the State of Florida. If the submitted site plan does not provide sufficient information to determine which trees will be affected by the proposed development, the Department may require that a tree survey of the site be prepared and submitted to the Department for review.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history></law>