<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00029' order_by='00029' level='4'>DIVISION 1. WORK IN CANAL RIGHTS-OF WAY, TIDAL WATERS, SUBMERGED BAY-BOTTOM LANDS, AND WETLANDS; DEWATERING; CONSTRUCTION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-48.13</section_number>
<catch_line>Suspension, revocation, modification, change of permit; notice.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003379</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-48.13. Suspension, revocation, modification, change of permit; notice.<section prefix='(1)'>If the Director or the Director's designee determines that the permittee or contractor is not performing the work in accordance with the provisions of the permit or the approved plans upon which the permit was issued, the Director or Director's designee may order suspension of the permit or the stopping of work until such time as the permittee or contractor has complied with the permit or plans. In such cases, the permittee or contractor shall take all necessary precautions to leave the work area in a safe and secure condition.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Modification(s) to a permit issued for work hereunder and any associated covenant running with the land shall be approved by the Department. If, in the opinion of the Director, the proposed modification(s) will result in a substantial change to the project, said modification(s) shall be subject to a public hearing before the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A violation of the conditions, restrictions or limitations imposed by the Board of County Commissioners or the Department and made part of the permit, or authorization, or failure of the permittee or contractor to perform said work in accordance with the approved plans and specifications thereof, or any material false statement in the application may result in the revocation in whole or in part of a permit issued for work hereunder.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 5, 7-3-12)</history></law>