<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. WATER AND SOIL QUALITY</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00027' order_by='00027' level='4'>DIVISION 3. CONTAMINATED SITE CLEANUPS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-44</section_number>
<catch_line>Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs) and Procedures for Site Rehabilitation Actions (SRAs).</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003303</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-44. Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs) and Procedures for Site Rehabilitation Actions (SRAs).<section prefix='(1)'>STATE PROGRAM CONTAMINANT CLEAN-UP TARGET LEVELS (CTLs) AND PROCEDURES.<section prefix='(a)'>For contaminants subject to Chapter 62-770, F.A.C., the CTLs and SRA procedures set forth in Chapter 62-777 and 62-770, Florida Administrative Code (F.A.C.) shall apply.</section><section prefix='(b)'>For sites which have entered into a Brownfields Site Rehabilitation Agreement with the Department or the Florida Department of Environmental Protection pursuant to Chapter 62-785, F.A.C., the CTLs and SRA procedures set forth in Chapter 62-777 and 62-785, F.A.C. shall apply.</section><section prefix='(c)'>For contaminants subject to Chapter 62-782, F.A.C., the CTLs and SRA procedures set forth in Chapter 62-777 and 62-782, F.A.C. shall apply.</section><section prefix='(d)'>For lands owned by the state university system, the risk-based clean-up criteria as described in 376.3071, 376.3078, and 376.81, Florida Statutes, shall apply.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>CLEAN-UP TARGET LEVELS (CTLs) AND PROCEDURES FOR SITES OR CONTAMINANTS OTHER THAN THOSE IDENTIFIED IN SECTION 24-44(1).<section prefix='(a)'>Intent. To protect human health, public safety and environmental resources using risk-based corrective action strategies and to establish the point at which a site rehabilitation action is determined to be accomplished.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The acceptable level of protection for the establishment of human health based CTLs shall be a lifetime excess cancer risk level of one in one million (1.0E-06) and a hazard quotient of one (1) or less. In addition, the CTLs shall be established to protect aquatic life and to prevent nuisance conditions as applicable.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Applicability. The CTLs set forth in this section are not effluent standards and are not for the purpose of disposal or reuse.<section>The CTLs and SRA procedures set forth in this section shall not apply to those contaminants that are subject to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 as amended by the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986, the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, the federal Hazardous and Solid Waste Amendments of 1984, or the Toxic Substance Control Act of 1976.</section><section>In addition, the soil CTLs set forth in(2)(f)(v)2. shall not apply to contaminants in soil that are present as a result of the application of registered pesticides that were applied in accordance with state and federal law and the EPA approved applicable registered labels. In making a determination of the applicability of CTLs pursuant to this provision, the party or parties responsible for SRAs shall provide records substantiating such pesticide applications to the Department upon request. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of(2)(b), if groundwater contains contaminants above the groundwater CTLs set forth in(2)(f)(v)1. as a result of the pesticide application, then the CTLs and SRA procedures set forth in Section 24-44(2) shall apply.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Party or parties responsible for site rehabilitation actions shall be the discharger or, if the discharger is unknown or the contamination was the result of a previously unreported discharge, the property owner or operator who is subject to the provisions of Section 24-44(2).</section><section prefix='(e)'>Retroactivity. The CTLs and the SRA procedures set forth herein shall not apply to those contaminants for which, on or before the effective date of this ordinance, a no further action plan, a source removal plan, a remedial action plan or a monitoring only plan has been approved in writing by the Director, or the Director's designee, unless the party or parties responsible for SRAs have failed to comply with the conditions of the plan approval. However, the party or parties responsible for SRAs may elect to complete site rehabilitation as provided in Section 24-44(2).</section><section prefix='(f)'>The Clean-up Target Levels are as follows:<section prefix='(i)'>The groundwater and surface water CTLs are set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)1. The groundwater CTLs are equivalent to the numerical standards set forth in Section 24-43.3(2)(h) of this chapter. For contaminants not listed in Section 24-43.3(2)(h), the groundwater CTLs are equivalent to the numerical standards set forth in Chapter 62-550, F.A.C., Table 1, Table 2, Table 3, Table 4, Table 5 and Table 6, as same may be amended from time to time.<section>For contaminants not listed in(2)(h) or Chapter 62-550, F.A.C., Table 1, Table 2, Table 3, Table 4, Table 5 and Table 6, as same may be amended from time to time, groundwater CTLs are based upon the protection of human health and the prevention of nuisance conditions as set forth in(2)(b). The groundwater CTLs have been established using the procedures, equations and input parameters set forth in the DERM Technical Report: "Development of Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs) for of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida" (dated September, 2005).</section><section>The surface water CTLs are equivalent to the water quality standards set forth in(4) of this chapter.</section><section>For contaminants not listed in(4), the surface water CTLs are based upon the protection of human health and aquatic life and the prevention of nuisance conditions as set forth in(2)(b). The surface water CTLs have been established using the procedures, equations and input parameters set forth in the DERM Technical Report: "Development of Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs) for of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida" (dated September, 2005) and, as applicable, the numerical standards set forth in Chapter 62-302, F.A.C, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of(2)(f)(i), no groundwater or surface water CTLs shall be more stringent than the practical quantitation limits or naturally occurring background concentrations determined in a natural background concentration study which has been approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>The soil CTLs are set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)2.. The soil CTLs are based upon the protection of human health as set forth in Section 24-44(2)(b) and groundwater and surface water CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)1.. The soil CTLs have been established using the procedures, equations and input parameters set forth in the DERM Technical Report: "Development of Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs) for Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida" (dated September, 2005).<section>However, the applicable leachability-based soil CTLs may be exceeded if it is demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Director, or the Director's designee, that:</section><section prefix='1.'>Leachate concentrations do not exceed the applicable groundwater or surface water CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)1., using a laboratory leaching procedure which simulates soil leachability and which has been approved by the Director or the Director's designee; or</section><section prefix='2.'>For soil that is and has been exposed to the elements (i.e., open ground, not covered by impermeable or semi-permeable cover) and subject to infiltration throughout the entire unsaturated zone for a minimum of two years, it has been subsequently demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Director, or the Director's designee, by a minimum of one year of groundwater monitoring data, that contaminants will not leach into the groundwater at concentrations that exceed the applicable groundwater or surface water CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)1.. This demonstration shall consider site-specific characteristics such as the thickness of the unsaturated zone, depth and mass of soil contaminants, soil lithology, actual precipitation, concentration gradients, and the chemical and physical characteristics of the contaminants.</section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of(2)(f)(ii), no soil CTLs shall be more stringent than the practical quantitation limits or naturally occurring background concentrations determined in a natural background concentration study which has been approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section><section prefix='(iii)'>The Director, or the Director's designee, may approve alternative CTLs provided that: human health, public safety, and the environment are afforded equivalent protection to that provided in Section 24-44 (2)(f)(i) and Section 24-44(2)(f)(ii); and same are based upon one (1) of the following, or a combination of the following:<section prefix='1.'>The application of the procedures set forth in Section 24-44 (2)(k)(ii) or Section 24-44(2)(1)(ii).</section><section prefix='2.'>A demonstration, provided in a feasibility study approved by the Director, or the Director's designee, that achieving the CTLs is not feasible utilizing the best available technologies.</section><section prefix='3.'>Calculations of site-specific soil CTLs using appropriate site-specific soil properties and equations provided in the DERM Technical Report: "Development of Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs) for Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida" (dated September, 2005), and approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='4.'>Calculations of site-specific soil CTLs for total recoverable petroleum hydrocarbons (TRPH) based upon the site-specific composition of TRPH, as determined by an analytical method approved by the Director or the Director's designee. Calculations utilized to comply with this provision shall be in accordance with the DERM Technical Report: "Development of Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs) for Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida" (dated September, 2005).</section></section><section prefix='(iv)'>The Director, or the Director's designee, shall maintain the DERM Technical Report: "Development of Clean-up Target Levels for Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida" (dated September, 2005) which contains the risk equations, leachability equations and default input parameters used to calculate the CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v) herein. The aforesaid Technical Report dated September, 2005, a copy of which is attached hereto, is hereby incorporated by reference, as same may be amended from time to time. Any changes, additions or deletions to the aforesaid Technical Report shall be approved by the Board of County Commissioners by ordinance.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs).<section prefix='1.'>Groundwater and Surface Water CTLs.</section></section></section></section><section>Table 1 Groundwater and Surface Water Clean-up Target levels<section>CTLs are expressed in units of ug/l (ppb).</section><section># = These default Target Organ(s)/Systems or Effects are those reported to occur at the doses used to derive the referenced dose. Non-default Target Organ(s)/Systems or Effects may be justified through a detailed toxicological analysis of the chemicals present at a specific site.</section><section>* = There are no surface water standards for these individual polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons. Per Chapter 62-302, F.A.C., the surface water criterion for PolycyclicAromatic Hydrocarbons (PAHs) shall apply to the total concentration of Acenaphthylene, Benzo(a)anthracene, Benzo(a)pyrene, Benzo(fluoranthene, Benzo(g,i,h) perylene, Benzo(k)fluoranthene, Chrysene, Dibenzo(a,h,)anthracene, Indenol(1,2,3-cd)pyrene, and Phenanthrene.</section><section>** = Groundwater CTLs for Class C carcinogens with no cancer slope factor were developed using the referenced dose divided by a factor of 10, as described in the DERM Technical Report: Development of Cleanup Target Levels (CTLs) for, of the Code of Miami-Dade County (September 2005).</section><section>(a) = Freshwater surface water criterion for Ammonia based on un-ionized ammonia only. All other water criteria for ammonia are based on total ammonia.</section><section>(b) = The common name BHC is a misnomer for Hexachlorocyclohexane.</section><section>(c) = Criteria for Dioxins, as total 2,3,7,8-TCDD equivalents shall be compared to the total dioxin equivalents for chlorinated dioxin and dibenzofuran congeners using the approach set forth in the DERM Technical Report: Development of Cleanup Target Levels (CTLs) for of the Code of Miami-Dade County (September 2005).</section><section>(d) = Surface water values protective of human health for Vinyl chloride calculated assuming continuous lifetime exposure from birth as described in the DERM Technical Report: Development of Cleanup Target Levels (CTLs) for of the Code of Miami-Dade County (September 2005).</section><section>(e) = Not to exceed 10% above ambient, as set forth in(4).</section><section>(f) = Hardness-dependent as set forth in Chapter 62-302, F.A.C.</section><section>(g) = Criteria for these metals are measured as total recoverable metal. However, they may be applied as dissolved metals when, as part of a permit application, a dissolved metals translator has been established according to the procedures set forth in the document, "Guidance for Establishing a Metals Translator", Florida Department of Environmental Protection, December 17, 2001.</section><section>(h) = In the absence of concentration data specific for the III and VI valence states of chromium, total chromium concentrations in surface water shall be compared to the criteria for Chromium (hexavalent).</section><section>(i) = 12789-03-6 or 57-74-9</section><section>NA = Not available.</section><section>None Specified = Target organ(s) not available.</section><section>Note: Freshwater and marine surface waters, and groundwater at the point of discharge into surface water shall pass acute and chronic toxicity bioassay tests: The user shall consult the standard definitions for acute and chronic toxicity set forth in F.A.C. 62-302.200(1) and F.A.C. 62-302.200(4), respectively.</section></section><section>Table 2 Soil Clean-up Target Levels</section><section> <section>CTLs are expressed in units of mg/kg (ppm) on a dry weight basis and rounded to two significant figures if &gt;1 and to one significant figure if &lt;1.</section><section># = These default Target Organ(s)/Systems or Effects are those reported to occur at the doses used to derive the referenced dose. Non-default Target Organ(s)/Systems or Effects may be justified through a detailed toxicological analysis of the chemicals present at a specific site.</section><section>* Contaminant is not a health concern for this exposure scenario.</section><section>** Direct exposure value based on acute toxicity considerations. This criterion is applicable in scenarios where children might be exposed to soils (e.g. residences, schools, playgrounds).</section><section>*** Leachability values may be derived using the SPLP Test to calculate site-specific SCTLs or may be determined using TCLP in the event oily wastes are present.</section><section>## = Site concentrations for carcinogenic polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons shall be converted to Benzo(a)pyrene equivalents before comparison with the appropriate direct exposure SCTL for Benzo(a)pyrene using the approach described in the DERM Technical Report: Development of Cleanup Target Levels (CTLs) for, of the Code of Miami-Dade County (September 2005).</section><section>(a) = See discussion on the development of SCTLs for Ammonia in the DERM Technical Report: Development of Cleanup Target Levels (CTLs) for of the Code of Miami-Dade County (September 2005).</section><section>(b) = Leachability values derived from USEPA Soil Screening Guidance (1996). These values were derived assuming soil pH 6.8. These leachability values are dependent upon both the metal concentration in soil and soil characteristics. Thus, if site-specific soil characteristics are different than the defaults, these leachability values may not apply. If this is the case, site-specific leachability values may be derived using methods such as TCLP or SPLP.</section><section>(c) = Phytotoxicity must be considered.</section><section>(d) = Residential direct exposure value from USEPA Revised Interim Soil Guidance for CERCLA Sites and RCRA Corrective Action Facilities. OSWER Directive 9355.4-12 (1994). The industrial direct exposure value was derived using methodologies set forth in USEPA "Recommendations of the Technical Review Workgroup for Lead for an Interim Approach to Assessing Risks Associated with Adult Exposures to Lead in Soil', December 1996; and in 'Blood Lead Concentrations of U.S. Adult Females: Summary Statistics from Phases 1 and 2 of the NHANES III', March 2002.</section><section>(e) = The SCTL for Dioxins, as total 2,3,7,8-TCDD equivalents should be compared to the total dioxin equivalents for chlorinated dioxin and dibenzofuran congeners using the approach described in the DERM Technical Report: Development of Cleanup Target Levels (CTLs) for of the Code of Miami-Dade County (September 2005).</section><section>(f) = The common name BHC is a misnomer for hexachlorocyclohexane.</section><section>(g) = Unless concentratons for both chromium III and VI are known, total chromium concentrations may be compared with direct exposures SCTLs for chromium VI.</section><section>(h) = Residential chronic SCTL for cadmium shall be used as a not-to-exceed value because the residential chronic SCTL for cadmium is indistinguishable from the SCTL based on acute toxicity.</section><section>(i) = Residential chronic SCTL for vinyl chloride calculated by adding prorated and non-prorated risks, as discussed in the DERM Technical Report: Development of Cleanup Target Levels (CTLs) for of the Code of Miami-Dade County (September 2005).</section><section>(j) = 12789-03-6 or 57-74-9</section><section>(k) = Hardness-dependent fresh surface water CTLs shall be calculated using the site-specific hardness prior to calculating the leachcability based upon fresh surface water CTLs or comparing the SPLP leachate concentrations.</section><section>None Specified = Target organ(s) not determined.</section><section>NA = Not available.</section><section prefix='3.'>For contaminants not listed in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v), CTLs shall be established as set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(i) and Section 24-44(2)(f)(ii). The CTLs calculated pursuant to Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)3. shall be provided in a technical report approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section prefix='(g)'>All technical plans, reports, proposals, or studies shall be submitted by the party or parties responsible for SRAs in accordance with the written orders of the Director, or the Director's designee, or as set forth herein. The Director, or the Director's designee, shall review each technical plan, report, proposal, or study and approve, approve with modifications or disapprove the aforesaid in writing within sixty (60) calendar days from receipt of the submittal.<section>To facilitate a phased risk-based assessment process that is iterative and that tailors site rehabilitation actions to site-specific conditions, the party or parties responsible for SRAs may submit to the Department for approval a proposal to establish applicable exposure factors and a risk management approach based upon land use at the site pursuant to the requirements set forth in(2)(k)(ii) and(2)(l)(ii).</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Site rehabilitation actions shall neither be, nor reasonably be expected to be, a source of pollution, as herein defined, or cause, or reasonably be expected to cause, a nuisance as defined in Section 24-5, Section 24-27 or Section 24-28.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Emergency response actions may be performed without prior approval from the Director, or the Director's designee, provided that these actions do not cause any adverse effects upon human health, public safety or the environment. The party or parties responsible for SRAs and performing the emergency response actions shall notify the Director, or the Director's designee, within 24 hours of the commencement of any such emergency response actions.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Point of compliance, notification, source removal, and assessment procedures shall be as follows:<section prefix='(i)'>The sampling points to determine compliance with Section 24-44(2) shall be as set forth in Section 24-44.1 herein. However, contamination may exist beyond the property boundary while clean-up, including natural attenuation in conjunction with appropriate monitoring, is proceeding.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>When contamination exists beyond the property boundary of the site from which SRAs have been initiated the party or parties responsible for SRAs shall commence notification in accordance with the following:<section prefix='1.'>Laboratory analytical results, which comply with appropriate quality assurance protocols pursuant to Chapter 62-160, F.A.C., that document the off-site contamination, shall be submitted to the Department no later than ten (10) calendar days from the date that the laboratory analyses are completed. A site sketch shall be submitted along with the laboratory analytical data which indicates the locations where the samples were obtained that resulted in the confirmation of the contamination.</section><section prefix='2.'>The property owners, residents, and tenants of any property onto or into which the contamination extends shall be notified within sixty (60) calendar days of the approval of the site assessment report. Notification shall include, but not be limited to, the following type of information: the type of contaminant and site remedy selected, a description of the location of the subject site, the name and address of the party or parties responsible for SRAs, and the name of a Department contact. Persons receiving notice shall have thirty (30) calendar days upon receipt of the notice to comment on the assessment and the site remedy selected. Nothing herein shall preclude any persons from initiating a civil action as a result of said contamination.</section></section><section prefix='(iii)'>Prior to site closure as set forth in Section 24-44(2)(k), source removal of free product and soil saturated with contaminants or free product is required, unless demonstrated through a feasibility study approved by the Director, or the Director's designee, that the source removal is neither cost effective nor technically feasible. Source removal of free product from a new discharge shall be initiated as soon as possible but, in any event, no later than seven (7) calendar days after the discovery of free product. Source removal of free product from a previous discharge shall be initiated in accordance with the written orders of the Director, or the Director's designee, or the timeframes set forth in a source removal plan approved by the Director or the Director's designee.<section>Source removal of contaminated soils and saturated soils by excavation may be implemented at any time upon prior written notification by the party or parties responsible for SRAs to the Director or the Director's designee. Such notification shall be submitted to the Department at least three (3) calendar days prior to performing the source removal by excavation. Excavated soils shall be disposed of in accordance with 40 CFR 261, 40 CFR 761, Chapter 62-701, F.A.C., Chapter 62-713, F.A.C., and any other applicable federal, state and local regulations. A source removal report shall be submitted to the Department within sixty (60) calendar days of completion of the source removal. The source removal report shall describe all activities performed during the source removal including all analytical results as well as all disposal manifests.</section><section>When excavated soil is temporarily stored or stockpiled on site, the soil shall be secured in a manner which prevents human exposure to contaminated soil and prevents soil exposure to conditions which may facilitate the spread of contamination. Any excavation shall be secured to prevent accidental or intentional entry by the public and shall comply with applicable federal, state and local regulations. Contaminated soils may be stored on site for ninety (90) calendar days, unless otherwise ordered by the Director or the Director's designee. Prior to the expiration of the ninety (90) calendar day period, the soils shall be disposed of in accordance with this section.</section></section><section prefix='(iv)'>The site assessment report shall include, but not be limited to: an investigation of the source(s) of contamination; an identification of the types of contaminants present; a determination of the extent and degree of contamination in all media which are impacted; a determination of the physical and environmental conditions and characteristics of the site and the underlying aquifer(s), if applicable; an identification of potential human and environmental receptors; and an evaluation of the current exposure and potential risk of exposure to those identified receptors. Groundwater sampling shall be performed less than two hundred seventy (270) calendar days before the submittal of the site assessment report.</section><section>The summary and conclusions of the approved site assessment report shall propose one of the following: no further action, no further action with conditions, monitoring only, risk assessment, or a remedial action plan.</section></section><section prefix='(k)'>Site closure, in the form of a no further action or a no further action with conditions, shall be approved by the Director, or the Director's designee, when the CTLs or alternative CTLs established pursuant to Section 24-44(2)(f)(iii) and the requirements set forth in this section have been achieved.<section prefix='(i)'>A no further action proposal shall be approved by the Director, or the Director's designee, if such proposal demonstrates that human health, public safety and the environment are protected and the following criteria are met:<section prefix='1.'>Concentrations of contaminants detected in soil shall not exceed the lower of the direct exposure residential soil CTLs or the applicable leachability-based soil CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)(ii).<section>The applicable leachability-based soil CTLs shall be the groundwater leachability-based CTLs. If surface waters are, or are reasonably expected to be, affected by contaminated groundwater, as demonstrated using monitoring well data, groundwater flow rate and direction, or fate and transport modeling, then the applicable leachability-based soil CTLs shall be the lower of the groundwater or the applicable freshwater or marine surface water leachability-based CTLs.</section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of(2)(k)(i)1, alternative residential direct exposure and leachability-based CTLs may be proposed in accordance with the procedures set forth in(2)(f)(iii)3. and(2)(f)(iii)4.</section></section><section prefix='2.'>Concentrations of contaminants detected in groundwater shall not exceed the groundwater CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)1.<section>If surface waters are, or are reasonably expected to be, affected by contaminated groundwater, as demonstrated using monitoring well data, groundwater flow rate and direction, or fate and transport modeling, then the groundwater CTLs shall be the lower of the groundwater CTLs or the applicable freshwater or marine surface water CTLs set forth in(2)(f)(v)1.</section></section><section prefix='3.'>Concentrations of contaminants detected in surface water shall not exceed the applicable freshwater or marine surface water CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)1.<section>Nothing herein shall supersede the rules governing Outstanding Florida Waters, aquatic preserves, areas of critical state concern and any other rules adopted pursuant to Section 403.061(34), Florida Statutes.</section></section><section prefix='4.'>It is demonstrated that contaminants in sediments are not detected in concentrations, quantities, properties, levels or accumulations which are, or are reasonably expected to be, injurious to human, plant, animal, fish and other aquatic life, or property. This demonstration may be based, as applicable, on the Threshold Effects Levels published in the FDEP's guideline "Approach to the Assessment of Sediment Quality in Florida Coastal Waters" (dated November 1994), site specific bioassays, a site-specific risk assessment developed in accordance with Section 24-44(2)(1)(ii), or a combination thereof.</section><section prefix='5.'>If more than one contaminant is present or contamination is present in more than one (1) medium, the human health-based CTLs shall be adjusted to achieve the following: for non-carcinogenic compounds affecting the same organ(s), the hazard index (sum of the hazard quotients) shall be one (1) or less; and for carcinogens, the cumulative lifetime excess cancer risk level (sum of the lifetime excess cancer risk levels for each carcinogenic contaminant) shall be 1.0E-06 or less.</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>A no further action with conditions proposal shall be approved by the Director, or the Director's designee, provided the following: the property owner of the location elects to implement institutional and, if applicable, engineering controls; it is demonstrated, using site-specific data, modeling results, risk assessment studies, risk reduction techniques or a combination thereof, that human health, public safety and the environment are afforded protection equivalent to that provided in Section 24-44(2)(f)(i) and Section 24-44(2)(f)(ii); and the following criteria are met:<section prefix='1.'>For contaminants detected in soil, a proposal for alternative soil CTLs shall be submitted to the Department and shall achieve one of the following or a combination of the following:<section prefix='a.'>Concentrations of contaminants detected in soil shall not exceed the lower of the industrial direct exposure soil CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)2. or the applicable leachability-based soil CTLs, set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f).<section>The applicable leachability-based soil CTLs shall be the groundwater leachability-based CTLs or alternative groundwater leachability-based CTLs derived in accordance with(2)(k)(ii)1c and(2)(k)(ii)2. If surface waters are, or are reasonably expected to be, affected by contaminated groundwater, as demonstrated using monitoring well data, groundwater flow rate and direction, or fate and transport modeling, then the applicable leachability-based soil CTLs shall be the lower of the groundwater or the applicable freshwater or marine surface water leachability-based CTLs.</section><section>If a marine surface water is, or is reasonably expected to be, affected by contaminated groundwater, and no other property or fresh surface water bodies are located between the source property boundary and the marine surface water body and the groundwater on-site is not utilized, then the applicable leachability-based soil CTLs shall be the marine surface water leachability-based soil CTLs.</section><section>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of(2)(k)(ii)1a, alternative industrial direct exposure and leachability-based CTLs may be proposed in accordance with the procedures set forth in(2)(f)(iii)3 and(2)(f)(iii)4. In addition, the applicable leachability-based soil CTLs may be exceeded if it is demonstrated using groundwater monitoring data supported, if required, by site-specific modeling, that contaminants will not leach into groundwater at concentrations which exceed the applicable groundwater CTLs. The groundwater monitoring data shall be compiled for a minimum period of one (1) year and shall include four (4) quarterly sampling events.</section></section><section prefix='b.'>Concentrations of contaminants may exceed the soil CTLs if an engineering control, approved by the Director, or the Director's designee, in conjunction with the institutional control, is utilized to eliminate or control contaminant exposure and migration such that human health, public safety and the environment are afforded protection equivalent to that provided in Section 24-44(2)(f)(i) and Section 24-44(2)(f)(ii).</section><section prefix='c.'>Concentrations of contaminants detected in soil shall not exceed the alternative soil CTLs derived in accordance with Section 24-44(2)(f)(iii) and Section 24-44(2)(1)(ii).</section></section><section prefix='2.'>For contamination detected in groundwater, a proposal for alternative groundwater CTLs shall be submitted to the Department and shall provide the following:<section prefix='a.'>A complete evaluation of the current and projected use of the affected groundwater and documentation that the following conditions have been met:<section prefix='(1)'>Source removal is completed as set forth in Section 24-44(2)(j)(iii).</section><section prefix='(2)'>Groundwater contamination is not migrating away from a localized source.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Groundwater concentrations at the property boundary, as determined by groundwater monitoring data supported, if required, by site-specific modeling, do not, and are not reasonably expected to, exceed the groundwater CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)1. The groundwater monitoring data shall be compiled for a minimum period of one (1) year and shall include four (4) quarterly sampling events.</section><section>If surface waters are, or are reasonably expected to be, affected by contaminated groundwater, as demonstrated using monitoring well data, groundwater flow rate and direction, or fate and transport modeling, then the groundwater CTLs shall be the lower of the groundwater CTLs or the applicable freshwater or marine surface water CTLs set forth in(2)(f)(v)1.</section><section>If a marine surface water is, or is reasonably expected to be, affected by contaminated groundwater, and no other property or fresh surface water bodies are located between the source property boundary and the marine surface water body and the groundwater on-site is not utilized, then the groundwater CTLs shall be the marine surface water CTLs.</section></section><section prefix='b.'>If there is a receptor which may potentially be exposed to on-site groundwater and such exposure has not been eliminated by the implementation of institutional and, if applicable, engineering controls, then concentrations of contaminants detected in groundwater shall not exceed the alternative groundwater CTLs derived in accordance with Section 24-44(2)(f)(iii) and Section 24-44 (2)(1)(ii).</section></section><section prefix='3.'>Concentrations of contaminants detected in surface water shall not exceed the applicable freshwater or marine surface water CTLs set forth in Section 24-44(2)(f)(v)1.<section>Nothing herein shall supersede the rules governing Outstanding Florida Waters, aquatic preserves, areas of critical state concern and any other rules adopted pursuant to Section 403.061(34), Florida Statutes.</section></section><section prefix='4.'>It is demonstrated that contaminants in sediments are not detected in concentrations, quantities, proportions, levels or accumulations which are, or are reasonably expected to be, injurious to human, plant, animal, fish and other aquatic life, or property. This demonstration may be based, as applicable, on the Threshold Effects Levels published in the FDEP's guideline "Approach to the Assessment of Sediment Quality in Florida Coastal Waters" (November 1994), site specific bioassays, a site-specific risk assessment developed in accordance with Section 24-44(2)(l)(ii), or a combination thereof.</section><section prefix='5.'>If more than one (1) contaminant is present or contamination is present in more than one (1) media, the human health-based CTLs or alternative human health-based CTLs shall be adjusted to achieve the following: for non-carcinogenic compounds affecting the same organ(s), the hazard index (sum of the hazard quotients) shall be one (1) or less; and for carcinogens, the cumulative lifetime excess cancer risk level (sum of the lifetime excess cancer risk levels for each carcinogenic contaminant) shall be 1.0E-06 or less.</section><section prefix='6.'>The property owner of the location at which site rehabilitation actions are being conducted elects to implement an institutional and, if applicable, engineering control to eliminate or control exposure of human and environmental receptors to contaminants. When an engineering control is used in conjunction with institutional controls, an engineering control plan shall be submitted to the Department. The engineering control plan shall provide details of the design and construction of the engineering control and shall demonstrate that the engineering control is effective, reliable and capable of being monitored and maintained.<section>The no further action with conditions proposal shall include a copy of the proposed institutional control, in a form prescribed by the Director, or the Director's designee, and approved by the Board of County Commissioners, with site-specific closure conditions. Upon written approval by the Director, or the Director's designee, of the institutional control and, if applicable, the engineering control plan, the institutional control shall be recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County. A copy of the recorded instrument shall be submitted to the Department and the engineering control, if applicable, shall be implemented prior to approval of the no further action with conditions proposal.</section><section>Upon demonstration to the satisfaction of the Director, or the Director's designee, by the party or parties responsible for SRAs that institutional and, if applicable, engineering controls are no longer required because the conditions set forth in(2)(k)(i) have been achieved, the Director, or the Director's designee, shall release the institutional control.</section></section><section prefix='7.'>An operating permit in accordance with Section 24-18 shall be required for all sites for which site rehabilitation actions have been completed in accordance with the provisions set forth in Section 24-44(2)(k)(ii). The Director, or the Director's designee, shall approve, deny, or approve with conditions, restrictions or limitations any application for an operating permit.</section></section></section><section prefix='(l)'>For sites which do not qualify for site closure in accordance with Section 24-44(2)(k), one (1) of the following, or a combination of the following, shall be submitted for approval by the Director, or the Director's designee, to achieve site closure pursuant to Section 24-44(2)(k): a monitoring only plan, a risk assessment report, or a remedial action plan.<section prefix='(i)'>The monitoring only plan:<section prefix='1.'>The monitoring only plan for natural attenuation shall include, but shall not be limited to, an evaluation of the contaminant plume history, site conditions and aquifer chemical characteristics to demonstrate that the applicable CTLs will be attained in accordance with the approval by the Director, or the Director's designee, and that monitoring only is the most cost-effective remedial approach. The monitoring period shall be a minimum of one (1) year, unless two (2) consecutive quarterly samplings have indicated that applicable CTLs have been met. The monitoring only plan shall also demonstrate that human health, public safety, and the environment will be protected. Upon completion of the approved monitoring, a proposal for a no further action, a no further action with conditions, an extension of the monitoring only plan, risk assessment, or a remedial action plan, in accordance with the requirements herein, shall be submitted to the Department.</section><section prefix='2.'>The monitoring only plan to verify that compliance with the approved remedial action as set forth in Section 24-44(2)(l)(iii) has been achieved shall be for a minimum of a one (1) year period and shall include four (4) quarterly sampling events. However, if contamination was only present in the unsaturated zone during the site assessment and remediation tasks, only one groundwater sampling event approved by the Director, or the Director's designee, shall be required. Upon completion of the approved monitoring, a proposal for a no further action, a no further action with conditions, an extension of the monitoring only plan, risk assessment, or a remedial action plan modification, in accordance with the requirements herein, shall be submitted to the Department for approval.</section></section><section prefix='(ii)'>The risk assessment shall include, but shall not be limited to, a human and environmental exposure assessment, toxicity assessment, cumulative risk characterization, and supporting documentation for the development of alternative CTLs. Alternative health-based CTLs shall be calculated using the risk equations set forth in the DERM Technical Report: "Development of Clean-up Target Levels (CTLs) for Chapter 24 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida" (dated September, 2005), and site-specific exposure scenarios and input parameters. Upon approval of the risk assessment, a proposal for a no further action, no further action with conditions, monitoring only plan for natural attenuation or remedial action, in accordance with the requirements herein, shall be submitted to the Department.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>The remedial action plan shall include, but not be limited to, all supporting documentation for the remedial technique proposed to achieve CTLs or alternative CTLs, or to qualify for natural attenuation in all contaminated media. Groundwater sampling shall be performed less than two hundred seventy (270) calendar days before the submittal of the remedial action plan to the Department. Detailed technical documentation shall be provided for all elements of the proposed remedial process. Pilot testing may be required to support the design. A monitoring schedule shall be included to evaluate the performance of the clean-up. Within one hundred twenty (120) calendar days after the approval of the remedial action plan, the approved remedial action plan shall be implemented and record drawings of the operating remedial system shall be submitted. Upon achieving the CTLs or alternative CTLs, or qualifying for natural attenuation in all contaminated media, a monitoring only plan, prepared in accordance with the requirements set forth in Section 24-44(2)(l)(i), shall be submitted to the Department.<section>If implementation of the approved remedial action plan does not achieve the CTLs or alternative CTLs, or does not qualify for natural attenuation in all contaminated media a proposal for a monitoring only plan for natural attenuation, a risk assessment, or a remedial action plan modification, in accordance with the requirements herein, shall be submitted to the Department.</section></section></section><section prefix='(m)'>All sampling and analyses shall be performed in accordance with Chapter 62-160, F.A.C., Quality Assurance. Reports submitted to the Department which contain analytical data shall include, at a minimum, the following: original laboratory reports which include all information required in Chapter 62-160.670, F.A.C.; copies of the completed chain of custody records; copies of the completed water sampling log forms; and results from screening tests or on-site analyses.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 06-34, §§ 1—8, 3-7-06; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>