<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='4'>ARTICLE III. WATER AND SOIL QUALITY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-42.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Certification of sanitary sewer system collection, transmission and treatment capacity.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003310</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no county or municipal officer, agent, employee or board shall approve, grant or issued any building permit, certificate of use and occupancy (except for changes in ownership) or municipal occupational license (except for changes in ownership) for any land use served or to be served by a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system until the county or municipal officer, agent, employee or board has obtained the prior written unconditional approval or prior written conditional approval of the Director or the Director's designee. Notwithstanding any provision of this Code, no person shall construct, utilize, operate, occupy or cause, allow, let, permit or suffer to be constructed, utilized, operated or occupied any land use served or to be served by a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system until the person has obtained the prior written unconditional approval or the prior written conditional approval of the Director or the Director's designee.<section prefix='(a)'>The Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director or the Director's designee's unconditional written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee finds that there will be adequate transmission capacity and adequate treatment capacity at the time that the land use is to be connected to an operable and available publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system or at the time that the existing land use will discharge additional sewage flow.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If the Director or the Director's designee determines that there is not adequate treatment capacity or adequate transmission capacity, or both, the Director or the Director's designee shall issue the Director or the Director's designee's conditional written approval only if the Director or the Director's designee determines that the following requirements are met:<section prefix='(i)'>The person(s) responsible for the operation of the publicly or privately owned treatment works has obtained all local, state and federal environmental approvals for the construction of additional wastewater treatment capacity;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The person(s) responsible for the operation of the publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system(s) has obtained the written approval of the Director or the Director's designee, and all other local, state and federal environmental approvals for plan(s) of corrective action designed to provide adequate transmission capacity; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>The person seeking the written conditional approval submits an executed estoppel document, in such form as prescribed by the Director or the Director's designee and recorded in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, at the expense of the person seeking the written conditional approval. Said estoppel document shall contain, at a minimum, the following requirements:<section prefix='1.'>The person obtaining a building permit pursuant to a conditional written approval issued by the Director or the Director's designee shall not apply for a certificate of use and occupancy or municipal occupational license, nor shall the facilities being constructed under said building permit be connected to the publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system, until all of the conditions set forth in (i) and (ii) above have been complied with, that the construction pursuant to (i) above has been completed and certified and that the plan(s) of corrective action pursuant to (ii) above has been implemented, completed and certified.</section></section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding any of the foregoing provisions in (b) above, the Director or the Director's designee shall not issue a written conditional approval if:<section prefix='(i)'>A previously implemented approved plan for corrective action designed to provide adequate transmission capacity pursuant to (b)(ii) above failed to achieve adequate transmission capacity.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Any and all conditional or unconditional written approvals issued by the Director or the Director's designee pursuant to the provisions of (1) above shall remain valid and in full force and effect for a period not to exceed one (1) year from the date of issuance of such written approval. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if the person(s) seeking such written approval applies for a building permit within said one-year period and obtains such building permit and commences construction of the project, as defined by Section 304.3(b) of the South Florida Building Code, within one hundred eighty (180) days of issuance of the building permit, the conditional or unconditional written approval issued by the Director or the Director's designee shall remain valid and in full force and effect. However, if any of the requirements set forth herein are not met, the written conditional or unconditional written approval issued by the Director or the Director's designee and any building permit issued pursuant to such approval, shall be rendered null and void and be of no further force and effect.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notwithstanding any of the foregoing, no county or municipal officer, agent, employee or board shall approve, grant or issue any building permit for any land use served or to be served by a public water main or public sanitary sewer unless and until the owner or operator of said public water main or public sanitary sewer has issued the owner's or operator's written approval of said service.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>