<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='4'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-50.8</section_number>
<catch_line>Considerations for evaluating lands for acquisition and management; EEL Program Manual.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003369</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>Evaluation of each acquisition proposal shall be based upon the following considerations:<section prefix='(a)'>The primary considerations for evaluating environmental land shall be:<section prefix='(i)'>The biological value and viability of the resource;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The vulnerability of the resource to degradation or destruction; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>The requirements (including costs) for managing the resource to maintain its natural attributes, and the feasibility of meeting those management requirements.</section><section>Ancillary land shall be evaluated in conjunction with the adjacent environmental land.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The primary considerations for evaluating buffer land shall be:<section prefix='(i)'>The biological value and viability of the environmental land;</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The vulnerability of the buffer land to development; and</section><section prefix='(iii)'>The existing and potential impact on the environmental land if the buffer land were not acquired.</section></section></section><section prefix='(2)'>The Board of County Commissioners hereby approves and makes a part hereof the Criteria for Evaluating EEL Acquisition Proposals attached hereto. The County Manager, pursuant to Section 4.02 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, shall propose to the Board of County Commissioners an Environmentally Endangered Lands Program Manual (hereinafter referred to as the EEL Program Manual) which shall be used as a guide for implementing the provisions of this chapter, and shall include the criteria for evaluating EEL Acquisition Proposals which are adopted hereby.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history></law>