<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='4'>DIVISION 3. ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-50.4</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003365</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-50.4. Purpose.<section>The purpose of the EEL Program shall be:<section prefix='(1)'>To acquire environmentally-endangered lands which contain natural forest or wetland communities, native plant communities, rare and endangered flora and fauna, endemic species, endangered species habitat, a diversity of species, or outstanding geologic or other natural features;</section><section prefix='(2)'>To acquire environmentally-endangered lands which function as an integral and sustaining component of an existing natural system;</section><section prefix='(3)'>To protect environmentally-endangered lands which are publicly owned by acquiring inholdings or adjacent properties which, if not acquired, would threaten the environmental integrity of the existing resource, or which, if acquired, would enhance the environmental integrity of the resource;</section><section prefix='(4)'>To implement the objectives and policies of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County which have been promulgated to preserve and protect environmental protection areas designated in the Plan and other natural forest resources, wetlands, and endangered species habitat;</section><section prefix='(5)'>To identify Miami-Dade County's best and most endangered environmental lands for acquisition and management by evaluating the biological characteristics and viability of the resource, the vulnerability of the resource to degradation or destruction, and the feasibility of managing the resource to maintain its natural attributes;</section><section prefix='(6)'>To manage environmentally-endangered lands with the primary objective of maintaining and preserving their natural resource values by employing management techniques that are most appropriate for each native community so that our natural heritage may be preserved for present and future generations;</section><section prefix='(7)'>To use the acquired sites, where feasible within financial constraints and with minimal risk to the environmental integrity of the site, to educate Miami-Dade County's school-age population and the general public about the uniqueness and importance of Miami-Dade County's subtropical ecosystems and natural communities; and</section><section prefix='(8)'>To cooperate actively with other acquisition, conservation, and resource management programs, including, but not limited to, such programs as the State of Florida Conservation and Recreation Lands program, the Land Acquisition Trust Fund, and Save Our Rivers program, where the purposes of such programs are consistent with the purposes of the EEL Program as stated hereinabove.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>