<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='4'>DIVISION 3. ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-50.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003346</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-50.1. Legislative intent.<section>The historic loss, fragmentation, and degradation of native wetland and upland forest communities in Miami-Dade County are well documented, and remaining native wetland and upland forest communities are collectively endangered. On May 8, 1990, the electorate of Miami-Dade County authorized the county to exceed the constitutional millage limitation by levying an ad valorem tax of three-quarters of one mil, for a period not to exceed two (2) years, for acquisition, preservation, enhancement, restoration, conservation and maintenance of environmentally-endangered lands for the benefit of present and future generations; and limiting all uses of, and all investment earnings on, such levies to such purposes. It is the intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Miami-Dade County to establish the Environmentally Endangered Lands Program to implement this mandate and to support its purposes to the fullest.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>