<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='4'>DIVISION 3. ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-50.11</section_number>
<catch_line>Procedure for selection of acquisition proposals for placement on the acquisition list.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003411</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-50.11. Procedure for selection of acquisition proposals for placement on the acquisition list.<section prefix='(1)'>Upon receipt of a completed property nomination application, the County Manager shall forward the application to designated staff for initial review.<section prefix='(a)'>Upon completion of initial review, acquisition proposals accepted by the County Manager shall be evaluated by staff based upon the criteria provided in Section 24-50.8. The staff evaluation shall be completed within sixty (60) days of receipt by the County Manager of the completed application.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If, upon initial review, staff finds that the biological value of a candidate environmental land is low, that management is not feasible, or that the proposed acquisition would not fulfill the purposes of the EEL Program set forth herein, the County Manager shall be notified immediately and may order that no further evaluation be undertaken. Notwithstanding the County Manager's order, the LASC may, by extraordinary majority of five (5) votes, require a complete evaluation of said property.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Upon completion of the staff evaluation process, the Environmentally Endangered Lands Project Review Committee, created pursuant to Section 24-50.13 hereinbelow, shall define the preliminary boundaries for each acquisition proposal and shall assist the County Manager in preparing his recommendation on each proposal for the LASC. Within sixty (60) days of the completion of this staff evaluation process, the County Manager shall transmit his recommendation to the LASC along with a map of each site, a description of the biological characteristics of the site, a description of the development potential of the site and adjacent land, an assessment of the management needs and costs, the assessed value, and other information as may be deemed relevant for each proposal evaluated.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Within sixty (60) days of receiving the County Manager's transmittal, the LASC shall hold a duly-noticed public hearing to consider the recommendations regarding each site, the applicant's comments, and comments from the public. A courtesy notice shall be provided to the owner(s) of properties which are the subject of the hearing. Failure to notify said owner(s) shall not invalidate these proceedings.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Within thirty (30) days of its public hearing, the LASC shall meet to adopt its recommended acquisition list for consideration by the Board of County Commissioners as provided for in Section 24-50.9 hereinabove. In developing its recommendation, the LASC shall consider all information received from County staff, the County Manager's recommendation, information that has been submitted in writing through the date of the public hearing, and testimony received at the public hearing. The LASC shall forward the recommended acquisition list to the County Manager for scheduling on the County Commission agenda for consideration and action by the Board.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Deadlines established in Sections 24-50.11(1) through (4) hereinabove shall be waived in processing applications filed in 1992.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history></law>