<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='4'>DIVISION 3. ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-50.12</section_number>
<catch_line>Management plan and use of environmentally endangered lands.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003412</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-50.12. Management plan and use of environmentally endangered lands.<section prefix='(1)'>No later than thirty (30) days from the date of acquisition, an interim management plan for the property shall be submitted to the Environmentally Endangered Lands Project Review Committee for approval. Upon approval, interim management plans shall be implemented by the County Manager; provided, however, that such interim management plan(s) shall not be implemented for more than two (2) years after acquisition of the property.</section><section prefix='(2)'>A ten-year management plan shall be prepared for each property acquired by the EEL Program which shall:<section prefix='(a)'>Identify such management activities as are necessary to preserve, enhance, restore, conserve, maintain, or monitor the resource, as appropriate; and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Identify such uses as are consistent with the preservation, enhancement, restoration, conservation, and maintenance of the resource; and</section><section prefix='(c)'>Estimate the annual costs of managing the project.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Annually, the ten-year management plans prepared during the preceding year shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners for its approval. Each ten-year management plan shall be updated at least every five (5) years from the last date of Board approval, and may be amended as often as required. Management plan updates and amendments shall be submitted to the Board of County Commissioners for approval.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All management plans shall be consistent with the purposes set forth in Section 24-50.4 herein. All properties acquired or managed by the EEL Program shall be managed in accordance with the approved management plan for that property.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No use, infrastructure, or improvement shall be permitted on any property acquired or managed under the EEL Program that is inconsistent with the purposes of the program or that is not provided by an approved management plan for the property.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history></law>