<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-5</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003250</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-5. Definitions.<section>In construing the provisions of this chapter, where the context will permit and no definition is provided herein, the definitions provided in Chapter 403, Florida Statutes, as may be amended from time to time, and in rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, as may be amended from time to time, shall apply. The following words and phrases when used in this chapter shall have the meanings ascribed to them in this section:</section><section>shall mean the line established by the Miami-Dade County Board of County Commissioners on July 8, 1983 by Ordinance 83-58 delineating the approved urban development boundary for Miami-Dade County, as amended by ordinance from time to time.</section><section>shall mean:<section prefix='(1)'>Installation and sampling of the monitoring wells and soil borings required for the TCAR, and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Emptying, inerting and cleaning the interior of the underground storage facility, and</section><section prefix='(3)'>Filling the underground storage facility with a non-shrinking, inert and solid material approved by the Department.</section></section><section>shall mean a tank, pipe, vessel or other container, or any combination of the foregoing, used or designed to be used for the aboveground storage or aboveground transmission of hazardous materials including but not limited to line leak detectors, monitoring wells and secondary containment systems associated therewith.<section prefix='(1)'>Aboveground storage facilities have less than ten (10) percent of their total volume below the surface of the ground.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Facilities with ten (10) percent or more of their volume below the ground surface and which are contained within a vault or structure of sufficient size to allow human access and visual inspection of all components thereof are hereby determined to be aboveground storage facilities.</section></section><section>shall mean one (1) or more of the following processes of nature that produces water consistently meeting the requirements of the standards in this chapter: dilution, storage, sedimentation, sunlight, aeration, and the associated physical and biological processes which tend to accomplish natural purification in surface waters and, in the case of groundwaters, the natural purification of water by infiltration through soil and percolation through underlying material and storage below the ground water table, as may be approved by the Director.</section><section>shall mean complete or full treatment which is the combination of the controlled processes of coagulation, sedimentation, absorption, filtration, disinfection, or other processes which produce a water consistently meeting the potable water standards including processes which are appropriate to the quality of the raw water supply; works which are of adequate capacity to meet maximum demands without creating health hazards, and which are located, designed and constructed to eliminate or prevent pollution; and conscientious operation by well trained and competent personnel whose qualifications are commensurate with the responsibilities of the position and acceptable to the DERM.</section><section>shall mean that each pump station receiving sewage flow from the sewer service connection, the pump station immediately upstream from the pump station receiving sewage flow from the sewer service connection, and all pump stations through which sewage flow from the sewer service connection is transmitted to the wastewater treatment facility receiving such sewage flow, is operating (A) with fixed-speed pumps at a nominal daily average pump station operating time equal to or less than ten (10) hours per day, taking into account all existing sewage flow and loadings, including anticipated sewage flow resulting from all previously authorized sewer service connections or (B) with multiple-speed pumps at a nominal average power consumption that is equal to or less than forty-six (46) percent of the rated multiple-speed pump station motor horsepower or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee or (C) with variable-speed pumps at a nominal average power consumption that is equal to or less than a percentage of the rated variable-speed pump station motor horsepower as follows: (i) the percentage for all of the variable frequency driven pumps in the pump station shall be forty-nine (49) percent; (ii) the percentage for all of the magnetic-drive type variable speed pumps in the pump station shall be sixty-five (65) percent; and (iii) the percentage for all of the electrolyte rheostat or resistor bank type of variable speed drive pumps in the pump station shall be sixty-one (61) percent; or the equivalent of any of the foregoing, as applicable, as approved by the Director or the Director's designee, or (D) in such a manner that, upon completion of a rainfall-dependent peak flow management study approved by the Director or the Director's designee, the pump station is capable of managing peak flows (during a one (1) in two-year storm event as determined by the South Florida Water Management District) with a back-up pump out-of-service without causing or contributing to overflows in the collection and transmission system.</section><section>shall mean that the wastewater treatment plant which will receive flow from a sewer service connection shall not be in noncompliance as defined in 40 C.F.R. Part 123.45, Appendix A.</section><section>shall mean the vertical extent of the water column above submerged bottom lands which is sufficient at all times to prevent any damage to the submerged bottom lands and to any natural resources in or upon the submerged bottom lands.</section><section>shall mean any change in the physical or biological conditions of the natural environment within or adjacent to the area that results in a substantial detrimental effect upon flora, fauna, air, water, minerals or other natural characteristic(s) of the area.</section><section>shall mean any tree which shall be, or already has been, removed, relocated, or effectively destroyed, thereby requiring a permit pursuant to Ordinance Number 89-8.</section><section>shall mean a period of inactivity, not to exceed five years, of a previously established, lawfully permitted agricultural operation prior to the resumption of an agricultural operation.</section><section>shall mean the growing of crops, the raising of fowl, animals or bees, as a gainful occupation, but shall not include such activities engaged in as a hobby or truck farming in residential areas.</section><section>shall mean preparation of a site for commercial or noncommercial horticultural or floricultural uses including, but not limited to: row crops, farms, groves, nurseries, horticultural farming, truck farming, barns, sheds or other structures not habitable by human beings which are used for the storage of farm machinery, fertilizer, seed or other items or equipment ancillary to an on-site agricultural use; and the maintenance and raising of animals for commercial purposes.</section><section>shall mean a facility which repairs or maintains vehicles or equipment ancillary to and directly supportive of a bona fide agricultural purpose and which vehicle or equipment are owned or operated by the owner or leasee of the agricultural vehicle or agricultural equipment maintenance facility.</section><section>shall mean a particulate, gas or odor, including, but not limited to, smoke, charred paper, dust, soot, grime, carbon or any particulate matter, or irritating, malodorous or noxious acids, fumes or gases, or any combination thereof, but shall not include uncombined water vapor.</section><section>shall mean the presence in the outdoor atmosphere of one (1) or more air contaminants or the combination thereof in such quantities and of such duration which are injurious to human, plant or animal life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business.</section><section>or shall mean removing, poisoning, defoliating, or destroying a mangrove tree, either partially or entirely.</section><section>shall mean the existing temperature of the receiving water at a location which is unaffected by man-made thermal discharges and a location which is also of a depth and exposure to winds and currents which typify the most environmentally stable portions of the receiving bodies of water.</section><section>shall mean the space between two (2) casings or between the outer casing and the wall of the well hole.</section><section>shall mean any device designed to recapture or reuse ozone-depleting compounds which has the written approval of the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>shall mean a fibrous, rock-forming material, including, but not limited to, such amphibole varieties as tremilite, actinolite, anthophyllite, grunerite, richterite, edenite, amosite, crocilolite, and such serpentine varieties as amianthus and chrysotile, as well as synthetic asbestos fibers, including, but not limited to, fluor-tremilite, fluor-richterite, and fluor-edenite.</section><section>shall mean an assemblage of primary and secondary wetland species within a defined area. In order for said assemblage to be classified as an association, it must be composed of at least twenty-five (25) percent primary wetland species.</section><section>shall mean the area within the cone of influence of a public utility potable water supply well based upon average day pumpage.</section><section>shall mean the arithmetic average of the results of at least three (3) separate samples collected within a referenced specific time period. At least one (1) of these samples shall be taken at peak flow conditions, where applicable, and a minimum of twenty-five (25) percent of the referenced time period shall serve as an interval between successive samples.</section><section>shall mean the highest capacity pump installed in a pump station.</section><section>shall mean a gasoline or gasohol vapor recovery system that draws such vapor through a nozzle boot to an underground storage tank by means of the pressure differential created as the volume of gasoline or gasohol in the underground storage tank is reduced and the volume of gasoline or gasohol in the motor vehicle fuel tank is increased during motor vehicle refueling.</section><section>shall mean the area within two hundred ten (210) days travel time from a public utility potable water supply well based upon maximum day pumpage.</section><section>shall mean those lands within the following geographical boundary:<section>, 14, and 24, Township 52 South, Range 39 East, less those portions thereof lying southwesterly of the southwesterly right-of-way of Okeechobee Road, and</section><section>Sections 16, 17, 18 and 20, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, and</section><section>, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, less that portion thereof lying southwesterly of the northeasterly right-of-way of the Miami Canal and northwesterly of the northwesterly right-of-way of the Florida Turnpike, and</section><section>that portion of, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, lying westerly of the westerly right-of-way of Interstate I-75, and</section><section>, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, less that portion thereof lying northwesterly of the northwesterly right-of-way of the Florida Turnpike, and less those portions included within the right-of-way of the Miami River, and</section><section>, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, and</section><section>Sections 6, 7, 8, 17, 18 and 19, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, and</section><section>, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, less the southeast one quarter thereof.</section></section><section>All lying in Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section>shall mean the wetlands described below:<section>That portion of Section 3, Township 54 South, Range 39 East lying south of U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail) and lying west of S.W. 143 Avenue north of S.W. 9th Terrace and lying west of S.W. 144 Avenue south of S.W. 9th Terrace; those portions of Sections 4, 5, and 6, Township 54 South, Range 39 East lying south of U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail); that portion of Section 10, Township 54 South, Range 39 East lying west of S.W. 144 Avenue; that portion of, Township 54 South, Range 39 East, lying north of S.W. 88th Street (North Kendall Drive); and Sections 7, 8, 9, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 29, 30, and, Township 54 South, Range 39 East.</section></section><section>shall mean that portion of domestic sewage not emanating from residential showers, residential baths, residential bathroom washbasins, or residential clothes washing machines.</section><section>shall mean a place where vessels may be secured to a fixed or floating structure or to the shoreline.</section><section>shall mean a berthing space for a vessel which has been created or authorized pursuant to a permit or permits issued by the Department.</section><section>shall mean a facility where recreational vessels are stored on uplands by one (1) or more of the following methods:<section prefix='(1)'>On boat trailers on a paved or unpaved surface; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>On individual boat racks; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>On multi-story boat racks.</section></section><section>shall mean good faith commercial or domestic agricultural use of the land. In determining whether the use of the land for agricultural purposes is bona fide, the following factors as set forth in Section 193.461, Florida Statutes (and as amended from time to time), though nonexclusive, shall be taken into consideration:<section prefix='(1)'>The length of time the land has been so utilized;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Whether the use has been continuous;</section><section prefix='(3)'>The purchase price paid;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Size, as it relates to specific agricultural use;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Whether an indicated effort has been made to care sufficiently and adequately for the land in accordance with accepted commercial agricultural practices, including, without limitation, fertilizing, liming, tilling, mowing, reforesting, and other accepted agricultural practices;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Whether such land is under lease and, if so, the effective date, length, terms and conditions of the lease; and</section><section prefix='(7)'>Such other factors as may from time to time become applicable.</section></section><section>shall mean a grove of fruit trees specifically planted to produce edible fruit for commercial purposes or for personal consumption by the owner.</section><section>shall mean any publicly-owned real property used for the cultivation of plants for display or scientific research.</section><section>shall mean the wetlands within the following geographic boundaries:<section>Beginning at the intersection of U.S. Highway 27 (Okeechobee Road) and the south right-of-way of the C-9 Canal; thence run easterly to the west right-of-way of Interstate Highway 75; thence run southerly to the west right-of-way line of the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike; thence run southwesterly and southerly to the north right-of-way of U.S. Highway 27 (Okeechobee Road); thence run northwesterly to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>shall mean the areal extent of ground within the drip line of a tree.</section><section>shall mean those trees which constitute the tallest layer within a forest.</section><section>shall mean the tubular material utilized to shut off or exclude a stratum or strata other than the source bed and conduct water from only the source bed to the surface.</section><section>shall mean material consisting of soil, rock, sand, earth, marl, clay, stone and/or concrete rubble.</section><section>shall mean cessation of operation of a County solid waste management system facility and the act of securing such a facility, in accordance with applicable regulatory requirements, so that it will pose no significant threat to human health or the environment. This includes closing, long term monitoring, maintenance and financial responsibility.</section><section>shall mean a mangrove community which borders Biscayne Bay or one (1) of the tributaries of Biscayne Bay and which receives frequent tidal inundation and whose dominant floral constituent is mature The boundary of a coastal band community shall not be limited or affected by artificial boundaries such as, but not limited to, property lines.</section><section>shall mean the landward extent of the areas where detrital cycles contribute to the ecological productivity of coastal waters.</section><section>shall mean all waters in the State which are not classified as fresh waters.</section><section>shall include all organisms considered in the coliform group as set forth in Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Waste Water, sixteenth edition.</section><section>shall mean any combustible waste material containing carbon in a free or combined state.</section><section>shall mean particulate matter discharged into the atmosphere from the burning of any kind of material containing carbon in a free or combined state.</section><section>shall mean a boat docking facility which has boat slips, moorings, davit spaces, or vessel tieup spaces of which more than fifty (50) percent are designated for or contain commercial vessels.</section><section>shall mean any vessel engaged in any activity wherein a consideration is paid by the user either directly or indirectly to the owner, operator or custodian of the vessel; or any vessel engaged in the taking of saltwater fish or saltwater products for sale either to the consumer, retail dealer or wholesale dealer.</section><section>shall mean a public water system which serves at least fifteen (15) service connections used by year-round residents or which regularly serves at least twenty-five (25) year-round residents.</section><section>("CEIS") shall mean a detailed report, based upon current data obtainable at the time of permit application submittal, which describes the proposed work and its purposes and which addresses one (1) or more of the following assessment points so as to permit assessment of the probable environmental impacts, benefits and detriments of the proposed work:<section prefix='(1)'>An analysis of the probable impact of the proposed work in the wetland environment, including impact on ecological systems such as floral, faunal, marine and freshwater communities. Both direct and indirect potential adverse environmental impacts shall be included in the analysis. The statement shall include the effect, if any, of the proposed work upon the ability of the wetland to:<section prefix='(a)'>Receive and store surface waters and to recharge groundwater.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Contribute to quantity and quality of the water supply and protect against saltwater intrusion.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Protect adjacent uplands from hurricane and tidal storm surges.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Provide filtration and uptake of nutrients and pollutants from surface waters.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Contribute sheet flow of surface waters to adjacent areas.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Provide habitat for indigenous floral and faunal species, and rare, threatened and endangered species, as defined in this chapter.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Provide protection for the recharge area of a wellfield.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>An analysis of other adverse environmental impacts which cannot be avoided should the proposal be implemented, such as water or air pollution, undesirable land use patterns, urban congestion, threats to health or other consequences adverse to the County's environmental goals, as set forth in this Code and the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A description and analysis of alternatives to the proposed work which avoid or mitigate some or all of the probable adverse environmental impacts of the proposed work or which increase the beneficial environmental effects of the proposed work. An economic cost-benefit analysis may be submitted by the applicant for the proposed work and each such alternative.</section><section prefix='(4)'>An analysis of the cumulative and long-term effects of the proposed work. The analysis shall compare the proposed work's short-term use of the environment with long-term environmental parameters including, but not limited to, biological productivity, habitat quality, protection of hydrological resources, and nutrient and pollution attenuation capacity.</section><section prefix='(5)'>An analysis of all irreversible commitments of natural resources which would occur if the proposed work is implemented. This analysis shall include the extent to which the proposed work would curtail the range of beneficial uses of the environment.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A summary of the problems and objections raised by any federal, State or local entities and by the public in the review process, the disposition of the issues involved, and the reasons therefor.</section><section prefix='(7)'>A description and analysis of the socioeconomic benefits that may be derived from implementation of the proposed work as well as the potential negative impacts to the public resulting from denial of or modifications to the proposed work.</section></section><section>shall mean minute solid particles generated by the condensation of vapors from solid matter volatilization from the molten state, or may be generated by chemical processes, operations or reactions, when these processes create air-borne particles.</section><section>means a localized depression or draw-down of the groundwater due to water supply well pumpage.</section><section>shall mean solid waste comprised exclusively of materials which are not hazardous materials and which are not water soluble, including steel, concrete, glass, brick, soils not containing any hazardous materials, asphalt roofing and paving material, and lumber from a construction or demolition project.</section><section>shall mean any substance present in any medium which may cause an adverse effect upon public health, public safety, public welfare or the environment, or causes a nuisance as defined in, or.</section><section>shall mean a body of water enclosed by natural or constructed restraints which has been approved by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection for purposes of controlling heat dissipation from thermal discharges.</section><section>shall mean any physical connection or arrangement whereby contamination may enter a water supply system; such as two (2) otherwise separate piping systems, one (1) of which contains or is designed to contain potable water and the other waste water or other fluids or material of unknown or questionable safety, where intermixing may occur depending on the pressure or temperature differential between the two (2) systems.</section><section>shall mean Clean-up Target Levels as set forth in.</section><section>shall mean adverse environmental impact, as defined in this chapter, resulting from a proliferation of a particular proposed work or land use within a wetland area.</section><section>shall mean the total of the number of operating hours for all nonvariable speed and non-multiple-speed pumps in the pump station for the month divided by the number of days in the month which is then divided by the total number of the same type of pumps in the pump station less one (1) pump of the same type, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>shall mean an area along a bulkhead or pier where a vessel may be suspended over tidal waters by a mechanical device.</section><section>shall mean the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management.</section><section>shall mean the collection and temporary storage of stormwater in a manner that will provide treatment through physical, chemical or biological processes, with subsequent gradual release of the stormwater in a manner not to exceed the design limitations of the temporary storage area.</section><section>shall mean an open basin which intercepts the groundwater table and is used for the temporary storage of stormwater runoff.</section><section>shall mean land upon which structures or facilities have been constructed.</section><section>shall mean any parcel of land which contains an impervious area.</section><section>shall mean any proposed activity or material change in the use or character of land, including, but not limited to, the placement of any structure, utility, fill, or site improvement on land, and any act which requires a building permit.</section><section>shall mean to discharge off-site or on-site water from an excavation, underground structure, or depressed land.</section><section>shall mean the diameter of a tree's trunk measured at a point four and one-half (4½) feet from where the tree emerges from the ground at natural grade. In the case of multiple-trunked trees, the DBH shall mean the sum of each trunk's diameter measured at the point four and one-half (4½) feet from where the tree emerges from the ground at natural grade.</section><section>shall mean the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, with duties created pursuant to of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section>shall mean any substance soluble in fluorocarbon-113 and dispersed, emulsified, or otherwise dissolved throughout a sample.</section><section>shall mean waste water from toilets, showers, sinks, baths, and other facilities designed for human sanitation whether located within residential or nonresidential land uses.</section><section>shall mean the species or group of species having the largest total number of individuals in the canopy and/or understory within a defined area.</section><section>shall mean a minimum of fifty-one (51) percent of the plant cover within an area based on the following formula: Dominance equals one hundred (100) multiplied by the total estimated basal area of wetland plant species divided by the total estimated basal area of all plant species.</section><section>shall mean a geographically defined land surface having topographical features such that stormwater runoff will be directed towards a drainage structure or natural waterway.</section><section>shall mean any excavation that is drilled, cored, bored, washed, driven, dug, jetted or otherwise constructed when the intended use of such excavation is for the artificial recharge of groundwater, or the intentional introduction of water into any underground formation.</section><section>shall mean the removal of soil (i.e., rock, clay, peat, sand, marl, sediments or other naturally occurring soil material) from the surface of submerged or unsubmerged coastal or freshwater wetlands, tidal waters or submerged bay-bottom lands. Dredging shall include, but not be limited to, the removal of soils by use of clamshells, suction lines, draglines, dredges or backhoes.</section><section>shall mean an imaginary vertical line extending from the outermost horizontal circumference of a tree's branches to the ground.</section><section>shall mean an underground stormwater disposal system where the invert of a perforated conveyance pipe is placed at or above the average October groundwater level as set forth in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, Part II, Section D4, dated September 1, 1974, as may be amended from time to time.</section><section>or shall mean the process which occurs when stormwater is conveyed to a grassed swale or open basin for disposal into the ground where the bottom of the grassed swale or open basin is at least one (1.0) foot above the average October groundwater level as set forth in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, Part II, Section D4, dated September 1, 1974, as may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean a designated place where a recreational vessel is stored on uplands by one (1) of the following methods:<section prefix='(1)'>On a boat trailer on a paved or unpaved surface; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>On an individual boat rack; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>On a multi-story boat rack.</section></section><section>shall mean minute solid particles released into the air by natural forces or by mechanical processes such as crushing, grinding, milling, drilling, demolishing, shoveling, conveying, covering, bagging, sweeping, etc.</section><section>shall mean any building which is wholly or partly used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking and eating.</section><section>shall mean any room or group of rooms located within a dwelling and forming a single habitable unit with facilities used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking and eating. This term shall include, for the purposes of this ordinance, rooming units.</section><section>shall mean the wetlands described below:<section>Those portions of Sections 18 and 19, Township 52 South, Range 40 East, lying east of the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike; and Sections 6, 7, 8, 17 and 18, Township 53 South, Range 40 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>shall mean the girdling, or damaging of a tree's trunk, branch or root system or cutting, pruning or trimming not done in accordance with the most recent American National Standards (ANSI) A-300 Standard Practices for Tree Care Operations.</section><section>shall mean the act of passing into the atmosphere an air contaminant or gas stream which contains or may contain an air contaminant; or the material so passed to the atmosphere.</section><section>shall mean a process or structure which eliminates or reduces the migration of contaminants or eliminates or reduces the exposure of human and environmental receptors to contaminants.</section><section>shall mean the complex of climatic, edaphic and biotic factors that act upon an organism or an ecological community and ultimately determine its form and survival and which will be affected by the proposed work.</section><section>shall mean clean-up of, or mitigation for, air, soil or water contamination from the County solid waste management system and those facilities for which the County is legally responsible for environmental clean-up or mitigation.</section><section>shall mean a specimen tree, natural forest community, or any other tree or trees that substantially contribute(s) to the aesthetics of an area, and which are not exempted from permit requirements under(4)(f).</section><section>(sometimes hereinafter referred to as "ERU") shall mean the statistically estimated average horizontal impervious area of residential developed property per dwelling unit. This estimated average is calculated by dividing the total estimated impervious area of four (4) residential categories, to wit, single family, mobile home, multifamily and condominium, by the estimated total number of residential dwelling units. For the purposes of this ordinance each dwelling unit, to wit, single family residence, mobile home, multifamily, or condominium, is assigned one (1) ERU.</section><section>shall mean the action or process of creating any lake, rockmining (excluding ancillary property uses necessary for extracting and processing subsurface materials), reservoir, pond or other surface water.</section><section>shall mean the process by which stormwater flows out of a trench or a buried perforated pipe into the surrounding ground.</section><section>shall mean any thermal discharge:<section prefix='(1)'>Which is presently taking place, or</section><section prefix='(2)'>For which a construction or operating permit has been issued prior to the effective date of these rules.</section></section><section>shall mean anything that is built or purchased to make an action or operation easier or to serve a special purpose.</section><section>shall mean the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is not excessive as determined by the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Residential uses. If the distance between the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is less than the distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of twelve (12) square feet per linear foot of public water main, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required, or<section>Notwithstanding the above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is located within two hundred (200) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Office building uses. If the distance between the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is less than the distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of ten (10) square feet per linear foot of public water main, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required, or<section>Notwithstanding the above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is located within four hundred (400) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Business district uses. If the distance between the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is less than the distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of ten (10) square feet per linear foot of public water main, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required, or<section>Notwithstanding the above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is located within six hundred (600) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Industrial uses. If the distance between the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is less than the distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of ten (10) square feet per linear foot of public water main, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required, or<section>Notwithstanding the above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is located within seven hundred fifty (750) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public water mains to serve the property is required.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>In determining whether or not the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main is excessive, the Director or the Director's designee shall follow the principles set forth below:<section prefix='(a)'>The nearest available point of connection to an available public water main shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with good engineering practices.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this definition, additions, modifications, or remodelings of existing improvements on the property shall not require extension of public water mains to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public water main, if the gross floor area of the new construction and new improvements is less than twenty-five (25) percent of the existing gross floor area.</section></section></section><section>shall mean that distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is not excessive as determined by the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Residential uses.<section prefix='(a)'>Development requiring gravity sewer line extensions: If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of twenty (20) square feet of gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>Development requiring the installation of a sanitary sewer lift station for eleven (11) residential units or more: If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by subtracting one thousand (1,000) linear feet of public sanitary sewer from that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of seventeen (17) square feet of gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding subsections (1)(a) or (1)(b) above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public gravity sanitary sewer is located within one hundred (100) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Office building uses.<section prefix='(a)'>If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of fifteen (15) square feet gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding subsection (2)(a) above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is located within three hundred (300) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Business district uses.<section prefix='(a)'>If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of fifteen (15) square feet gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding subsection (3)(a) above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is located within five hundred (500) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Industrial uses.<section prefix='(a)'>If the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is less than that distance derived by dividing the sum of the existing and proposed gross floor area by a factor of fifteen (15) square feet gross floor area per linear foot of public sanitary sewer, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>Notwithstanding subsection (4)(a) above, if the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is located within seven hundred (700) feet of the closest point of the property, extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property is required.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>In determining whether or not the distance between the closest point of the property and the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer is excessive, the Director or the Director's designee shall follow the principles set forth below:<section>The nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer shall be determined by the Director or the Director's designee in accordance with good engineering practices.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this definition, additions, modifications, or remodelings of existing improvements on the property shall not require extension of public sanitary sewers to serve the property from the nearest available point of connection to an available public sanitary sewer, if the gross floor area of the new construction and new improvements is less than twenty-five (25) percent of the existing gross floor area.</section></section><section>shall mean the alteration of wetlands, tidal waters or bay-bottom lands, by adding material or soil to obtain higher elevations or better compaction of existing elevations.</section><section>shall mean an area of bare ground no more than ten (10) feet in width in a forest which has been created to prevent the spreading of wild fires.</section><section>shall mean the disposal by on-site retention of the volume of stormwater generated by the first inch of runoff from a defined drainage area.</section><section>shall mean the volume of stormwater runoff generated during the initial stages of a rainfall event and is calculated as the volume of stormwater runoff generated during the time required to supply and transport to the emergency overflow outfall, one (1) inch of stormwater runoff from the farthest point in the basin, as set forth in "DESIGN OF DRAINAGE STRUCTURE, AN UPDATED POLICY FOR THE DESIGN OF STORM RUNOFF DRAINAGE STRUCTURES, DECEMBER 1980," a document prepared by and on file in the offices of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management.</section><section>shall mean anything of a permanent or temporary nature which is built, constructed, placed or installed in, on, over or upon tidal waters. Fixed structures shall not include vessels or floating structures.</section><section>shall mean any substance soluble in fluorocarbon-113 as set forth in EPA Method 413.1 and floating or otherwise forming a visible layer upon any aqueous surface.</section><section>shall mean a barge-like entity, with or without accommodations, which is not used as a means of transportation on water but which serves purposes or provides services typically associated with a structure upon or improvements to real property. A floating structure includes, but is not limited to, a residence, place of business, office, hotel, motel, restaurant, lounge, retail or wholesale store, clubhouse, helicopter pad, meeting facility, or a storage or parking facility. Incidental movement or the capability of movement upon water shall not preclude an entity from classification as a floating structure. Registration of the entity as a vessel in accordance with Chapter 327, Florida Statutes, shall not preclude an entity from classification as a floating structure.</section><section>shall mean the accumulation of stormwater on the ground surface which occurs as a result of excessive rainfall precipitation which has saturated the soil and filled the canals, lakes, ditches and drainage structures beyond their storage and transmission capacities.</section><section>shall mean the classification of the quality of a nursery plant as published in Grades and Standards for Nursery Plants, Part II, Florida Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Division of Plant Industry.</section><section>shall mean any duct or passage for air, gases, or airborne materials, such as a stack or chimney.</section><section>shall mean a document which specifies the techniques that will be implemented to maintain and preserve an individual natural forest community.</section><section>shall mean chlorine existing in water as hypochlorous acid, hypochlorite ions, and molecular chlorine.</section><section>shall mean any non-aqueous liquid.</section><section>shall mean a structure consisting of a perforated, slotted or open joint pipe buried in a trench and surrounded by ballast rock and used for the underground disposal of stormwater runoff into groundwater or the unsaturated zone.</section><section>shall mean all waters of the state which are contained in lakes and ponds, or are in flowing streams above the zone in which tidal actions influence the salinity of the water and where the concentration of chloride ions is normally less than five hundred (500) milligrams per liter.</section><section>shall mean:<section prefix='(1)'>All of the vessel's fuel tanks, water tanks and other tanks are full, and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The vessel has the maximum allowable number of crew, passengers, equipment and provisions pursuant to the manufacturer's specifications and, where applicable, the United States Coast Guard certification, and</section><section prefix='(3)'>The vessel has all safety and rescue equipment required pursuant to state, federal and, if applicable, international law, and</section><section prefix='(4)'>The vessel contains the maximum authorized amount (by weight) of cargo pursuant to state, federal and, if applicable, international law.</section></section><section>shall mean every refuse accumulation of animal, fruit or vegetable matter that attends the preparation, use, cooking and dealing in, or storage of edibles, and any other matter, of any nature whatsoever, which is subject to decay, putrefaction and the generation of noxious or offensive gases or odors, or which, during or after decay, may serve as breeding or feeding material for flies or other germ-carrying insects.</section><section>shall mean a formless fluid which occupies space and which can be changed to a liquid or solid state only by increasing pressure with decreased or controlled temperature, or by decreased temperature with increased or controlled pressure.</section><section>shall mean a depression on the ground surface which is covered by vegetation and is located entirely within the unsaturated zone.</section><section>means the introduction of water into a well from which the water enters the groundwater without any force other than the force of gravity. Said well shall be in excess of two (2) feet below the average yearly highest groundwater elevation as specified in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean that portion of domestic sewage emanating from residential showers, residential baths, residential bathroom washbasins, or residential clothes washing machines.</section><section>shall mean plants, other than turf grass, normally reaching an average maximum height of not more than twenty-four (24) inches at maturity.</section><section>shall mean the introduction into or upon any ground of any organic or inorganic matter or deleterious substances in such quantities, proportions or accumulations which are injurious to human, plant, animal, fish and other aquatic life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business. It shall be a rebuttable presumption that the introduction of any hazardous waste as defined in or hazardous materials as defined in into or upon the ground, which exceeds any of the clean-up target levels (CTLs) set forth in, shall constitute and shall be deemed to be ground pollution.</section><section>shall mean the following species:<section>Aizoaceae (carpetweed family)— (sea purslane)</section><section>Amaranthaceae (amaranth family)— (marsh samphire)</section><section>Amaryllidaceae (amaryllis family)— (spider lily)</section><section>Apocynaceae (oleander family)— (mangrove rubber vine)</section><section>Asteraceae (aster family)— var. (salt-marsh aster)</section><section>(false willow)</section><section>(groundsel tree)</section><section>(oxeye daisy)</section><section>(oxeye daisy)</section><section>(marsh elder)</section><section>Avicenniaceae (black mangrove family— (black mangrove)</section><section>Batidaceae (saltwort family)— (saltwort)</section><section>Chenopodiaceae (goosefoot family)— (perennial glasswort)</section><section>(annual glasswort)</section><section>(sea blite)</section><section>(saltwort)</section><section>Combretaceae (white mangrove family)— (buttonwood)</section><section>(white mangrove)</section><section>Cymodoceaceae (manatee grass family)— (Cuban shoal weed)</section><section>(manatee grass)</section><section>Cyperaceae (sedge family)— (sedge)</section><section>(sedge)</section><section>(sedge)</section><section></section><section></section><section>Hydrocharitaceae (frog's bit family)—</section><section>Juncaceae (rush family)</section><section>(rush)</section><section>Juncaginaceae (arrow grass family)—</section><section>Plumbaginaceae (leadwort family)— var. (sea lavender)</section><section>var. (sea lavender)</section><section>Poaceae (grass family)— (seashore salt grass)</section><section>(Key grass)</section><section>(salt joint grass)</section><section>(smooth cord grass)</section><section>(salt-meadow cord grass)</section><section>(gulf cord grass)</section><section>(Virginia dropseed)</section><section>Primulaceae (primrose family)— (water pimpernel)</section><section>Pteridaceae (bracken family)— (coastal leather fern)</section><section>Rhizophoraceae (red mangrove family)— (red mangrove)</section><section>Ruppiaceae (widgeon grass family)— (widgeon grass)</section><section>Solanaceae (nightshade family)— (Christmasberry)</section><section>Surianaccac (bay-cedar family)— (bay cedar)</section></section><section>shall mean any substantial diversion, obstruction, creation of backwater conditions, interruption, adverse change in velocity, volume, or depth of the natural flow of surface water. Natural flow need not be uniform or uninterrupted and may be seasonal or periodic.</section><section>shall mean the sum of more than one (1) hazard quotient for multiple contaminants or for multiple exposure pathways.</section><section>shall mean the ratio of a single contaminant exposure level over a specified time period to a reference dose for that contaminant derived from a similar exposure period.</section><section>shall mean any waste, product, substance, or combination or breakdown product thereof which, because of its biological or chemical characteristics, if introduced into a potable public water supply well, will impair the potability of the water withdrawn by the potable public water supply well or which will be harmful or potentially harmful to human, plant or animal life or property or the conduct of business or which will increase the cost of operation of public water supply treatment facilities or which will increase the reliance by consumers of potable water from such potable public water supply wells on the operation of public water supply treatment facilities to provide potable water which is not harmful or potentially harmful to human, plant or animal life or property or the conduct of business.</section><section>Within ninety (90) days from the effective date of Ord. No. 83-96 and at least annually thereafter, the Director or the Director's designee shall submit to the Board of County Commissioners a list of wastes, products, substances or combination or breakdown products thereof which the Director or the Director's designee has determined to be hazardous materials as hereinabove defined. The Board of County Commissioners shall designate, by resolution, which of the wastes, products, substances or combination or breakdown products thereof so listed by the Director or the Director's designee shall be legally presumed to be hazardous materials as defined hereinabove. Such designation by the Board of County Commissioners shall create a rebuttable presumption that the wastes, products, substances or combination or breakdown products thereof so designated are hazardous materials as hereinabove defined. Such designations shall be deemed nonexclusive. Nondesignation by the Board of County Commissioners shall not create any presumption that the nondesignated wastes, products, substances or combination or breakdown products thereof are not hazardous materials. Nothing herein shall be construed to limit in any way the power of the Director or the Director's designee in the performance of his duties and responsibilities to determine that a waste, product, substance or combination or breakdown product thereof is a hazardous material as defined hereinabove.</section><section>shall mean:<section prefix='(1)'>A waste defined as a hazardous waste in 40 C.F.R. Part 261, or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Used radiator fluid,</section><section prefix='(3)'>Used lubricating oil,</section><section prefix='(4)'>Used transmission fluid,</section><section prefix='(5)'>Used brake fluid, or</section><section prefix='(6)'>Used power steering fluid.</section></section><section>shall mean hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, clinics, intermediate care facilities, ambulatory surgical centers, health maintenance organizations, doctor's offices, dentist's offices or free standing hemodialysis centers.</section><section>shall mean any conditions, devices, or practices in a water supply system or its operation which create a possible danger to the health and well-being of the water consumer. (An example of a health hazard is a structural defect in the water supply system, whether of location, design or construction, which may regularly or occasionally prevent satisfactory purification of water supply or cause it to be polluted from extraneous sources.)</section><section>shall mean the effluents from commercial or industrial activities or processes in which water is used for the purpose of transporting waste heat.</section><section>shall mean any public thoroughfare, including streets, designed for motor vehicles.</section><section>shall mean a division of the horizontal ground surface which is incapable of being penetrated by rainwater. This shall include, but not be limited to, all structures, roof extensions, slabs, patios, porches, driveways, sidewalks, parking areas, swimming pools, athletic courts, and decks.</section><section>shall mean a well or wells or other source of water, and pump and piping if any, located on the premises served for supplying twenty-five (25) persons or less.</section><section>shall mean any facility engaged in the manufacture, production, fabrication, packaging, repackaging, repair, processing or sale of goods or services, and which produces or generates or may reasonably be expected to produce or generate liquid waste.</section><section>shall mean discharges, effluents, spills, or leaks of any hazardous wastes, hazardous materials, process wastewater, or wastes other than domestic sewage, from an industrial liquid waste facility.</section><section>means the distribution of water on the surface of land to permit the water to soak through the vegetation and soil into the groundwater.</section><section>shall mean the process by which stormwater flows vertically downward through the ground into the Biscayne Aquifer.</section><section>shall mean any water, other than domestic sewage or other wastewater approved by the Director or the Director's designee to be discharged into a sanitary sewer system, introduced into any publicly or privately owned or operated gravity sanitary sewer or pump station wet well which is not sewer system infiltration.</section><section>shall mean a restriction on the use of, or access to, a site to eliminate or minimize exposure to contaminants. Examples include, but are not limited to, deed restrictions, restrictive covenants, or conservation easements.</section><section>shall mean any sewage treatment plant, public or private, including but not limited to interim package sewage treatment plants, that discharges its effluent directly into the Biscayne Aquifer or inland surface waters of Miami-Dade County.</section><section>shall mean day care centers, day nurseries, convalescent homes, adult congregate living facilities, rooming houses, boarding homes, homes for the elderly, homes for dependent children or retirement villages or any other facility providing shelter and supervision for dependent individuals who because of their mental or physical condition require health related care and services above the level of room and board.</section><section>shall mean the sanitary sewer manhole into which the entire sewage flow from a sewer subsystem is discharged.</section><section>shall mean the removal of vegetation or soils from submerged or unsubmerged wetlands. Landclearing shall not mean the removal of the following undesirable exotic vegetation: Melaleuca, Australian pine, or Brazilian pepper trees.</section><section>shall mean a drawing containing proposed tree removal, tree replacement planting, tree relocation and preservation areas.</section><section>shall mean any person or entity whose act or process produces liquid waste, or who by the nature of its operations uses materials in a process which would subsequently require disposal as a liquid waste as defined in this chapter.</section><section>shall mean sludge resulting from, but not limited to, a waste treatment works, air pollution control facility, domestic, commercial, mining, institutional, agricultural, or governmental operations; or other waste materials, including materials to be recycled or otherwise beneficially reused; or septic tank, grease trap, sediment trap, portable toilet, or oil and grease separator pump-outs; or solvents, sewage, industrial waste, hazardous waste, semisolid waste, or potentially infectious waste; or any similar materials which would cause a nuisance or would otherwise cause a violation of this chapter if discharged to the ground or waters of Miami-Dade County. However, sewage and industrial wastes which have been permitted by the Department to be discharged and which are discharged through a lateral connection to the sewerage system or on-site treatment facility are not included in this definition. Furthermore, subsurface materials extracted as a result of rock mining which are not discharged to canals or other water bodies are not included in this definition.</section><section>shall mean any person or entity which carries, conveys, bears or transports any liquid waste in any moving vehicle including but not limited to a car, truck, tank car, railroad car or other vehicle.</section><section>shall mean a gasoline, gasohol or petroleum distillates storage and distribution facility with an average daily throughput (calculated over a thirty-day period) equal to or greater than twenty thousand (20,000) gallons of gasoline, gasohol or petroleum distillates.</section><section>shall mean any county or municipal government or agency thereof.</section><section>shall mean any of the following species, regardless of size, including mangrove trees as small as rooted seedlings: (black mangrove), (red mangrove), (white mangrove). Notwithstanding the foregoing, mangrove tree shall not include seedlings smaller than 3—5 leaf stage rooted seedlings.</section><section>shall mean the maximum permissible level of a contaminant in water which is delivered to any user of a public water system.</section><section>shall mean the area within the cone of influence of a public utility potable water supply well based upon maximum day pumpage.</section><section>shall mean a facility using equipment to crush, shred, cut or otherwise process ferrous scrap metal into prepared ferrous scrap for resale or reuse. For the purpose of this definition, facilities limited to dealing in non-ferrous metals are not included.</section><section>shall mean a monthly, published bulletin listing availability of trees, prices of trees, and stock of many major nurseries in Miami-Dade County which is prepared by the Florida Nurserymen and Grower Association.</section><section>shall mean the rate of sewage flow, expressed in gallons per day per inch diameter per mile, measured at a pump station wet well or a key manhole of a sewer subsystem from 1:00 a.m. to 5:00 a.m. or at such other time when the rate of sewage flow transmitted through the pump station or key manhole is at the lowest rate during any one (1) twenty-four-hour period exclusive of known or estimated sewage flows from commercial and industrial sources of wastewater.</section><section>shall mean a suspension of any finely divided liquid in any gas.</section><section>shall mean the same term as defined by Section 320.01(2), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>or shall mean a well constructed with a surface seal and a sand filter pack in accordance with accepted technical design practices to provide for the collection of representative groundwater samples for laboratory analyses. Such wells may also be used to detect the presence of free product or collect water-level elevation data to aid in determining the direction of groundwater flow.</section><section>shall mean a temporary or permanent piling or floating device anchored in tidal waters for the purpose of securing a vessel.</section><section>shall mean a tank truck or trailer equipped with a storage tank used for the transportation of gasoline or gasohol from sources of supply to stationary storage tanks at motor vehicle fuel service stations.</section><section>shall mean any location which has underground storage facilities or aboveground storage facilities or both and which location has a total storage capacity of gasoline or gasohol of ten thousand (10,000) gallons or more, or which dispenses ten thousand (10,000) gallons or more per month of gasoline or gasohol to motor vehicle fuel tanks from such location.</section><section>shall mean any car, truck, bus or other self-propelled wheeled conveyance that does not run on rails.</section><section>shall mean the equivalent of the daily average pump station operating time, computed as follows: The average daily kilowatt-hours of consumption of all pumps of the same type in a pump station divided by the average daily kilowatt criteria in kilowatt hours multiplied by ten (10). The average daily kilowatt criteria in kilowatt hours ("A") is computed as follows: A = M × 24 hrs. × .746 KW/HP multiplied by P/100 where M is the Maximum Station HP. The applicable pump control factor ("P") is expressed as a percentage in parts (B) and (C) of the definition of adequate transmission capacity in this chapter. M is computed as follows: The rated horsepower of each pump at high speed multiplied by the number of pumps of the same type in the pump station less one (1) pump of the same type having the greatest rated horsepower, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>shall mean any article, machine, equipment, contrivance, structure or part of a structure, used to dispose of combustible refuse by burning, consisting of three (3) or more refractory-lined combustion chambers in a series, physically separated by refractory walls, interconnected by gas passage ports or ducts and employing adequate design parameters necessary for maximum combustion of the material to be burned.</section><section>The refractories shall have a pyrometric cone equivalent of at least seventeen (17), tested according to the method described in the American Society for Testing [and] Materials, Method C-24.</section><section>shall mean a plant species with a geographic distribution indigenous to all or part of Miami-Dade County. Plants which are described as being native to Miami-Dade County in botanical manuals such as, but not limited to, "A Flora of Tropical Florida" by Long and Lakela and "The Biology of Trees Native to Tropical Florida" by P.B. Tomlinson, are native plant species within the meaning of this definition. Plant species which have been introduced into Miami-Dade County by man are not native plant species.</section><section>shall mean a method of site rehabilitation action which allows natural processes to contain the spread of contaminants and to reduce the concentration of contaminants in groundwater and soil. Natural attenuation processes include, but are not limited to, diffusion and dispersion in conjunction with the following: sorption, biodegradation, chemical reactions, or volatilization.</section><section>shall mean all stands of trees (including their associated understory) which were designated as Natural Forest Communities on the Miami-Dade County Natural Forest Community Maps and approved by the Board of County Commissioners, pursuant to Resolution No. R-1764-84. These maps may be revised from time to time by resolution in order to reflect current conditions and to insure that, at a minimum, the canopy and understory of designated natural forest communities are dominated by native plant species, as defined herein. The Department shall evaluate the following additional factors when reviewing existing and proposed natural forest community sites:<section prefix='(1)'>The presence of endangered, threatened, rare or endemic species included on the Federal List of Endangered and Threatened Species, the Florida Game and Fresh Water Fish Commission List of Endangered and Potentially Endangered Fauna and Flora in Florida, or the Miami-Dade County Comprehensive Development Master Plan List of Endangered, Threatened, Rare and Endemic Plants in Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Overall plant species diversity of the site.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Size of the trees.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Size of the site.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Wildlife habitat value of the site.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Geological features of the site.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Percentage of the site covered by exotic (non-native) species.</section></section><section>Within one hundred twenty (120) days of the effective date of Ordinance Number 89-8, the Department shall develop a quantitative evaluation form incorporating the above factors to be used in evaluating natural forest community sites, and shall include a minimum quantitative threshold standard for inclusion on the revised natural forest community maps. Said evaluation form may be revised from time to time as appropriate, and shall be reviewed and approved by the Tree and Forest Resources Committee prior to its utilization.</section><section>Upon completion of the review of the existing natural forest community maps, the Director shall recommend to the Board of County Commissioners that only those sites which meet the minimum quantitative threshold standard established in the above-described evaluation form be maintained on the list and that all other sites be deleted. This shall not preclude the further addition of sites to the maps. The Director shall also recommend to the Board of County Commissioners that all applicable boundary changes be made to all remaining sites.</section><section>shall mean the ground elevation of a property prior to the placement of any fill on the site.</section><section>shall mean concentrations of contaminants which are naturally occurring in the groundwater, surface water, soil or sediment in the vicinity of a site.</section><section>shall mean the total power consumption for the month of all of the pumps of the same type in the pump station divided by the number of days in the month and which is then divided by the total number of the same type of pumps in the pump station less one (1) of the same type of pumps, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee, which is then averaged with the same computations performed for the previous eleven (11) months.</section><section>shall mean the total of the number of operating hours for all nonvariable speed and non-multiple-speed pumps in the pump station for the month divided by the number of days in the month and which is then divided by the total number of nonvariable speed and non-multiple speed pumps in the pump station less one (1) of the same type of pumps, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee, which is then averaged with the same computations performed for the previous eleven (11) months.</section><section>shall mean any parcel of land which contains an impervious area and which is classified by the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser as land use types 10 through and including 49 and 70 through and including 99 as set forth in the Florida Administrative Code Rule 12D-8.008(2)(c), as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean any activity designed to reduce pollutant loading of stormwater including, but not limited to, pollution prevention management policies and public education programs.</section><section>shall mean not capable of existing and continuing to provide the biological or aesthetic qualities associated with a healthy, functioning tree resource.</section><section>shall mean a basin located in western Miami-Dade County comprising the following lands:<section>Sections, 34, 35 and 36, Township 53 South, Range 39 East and, Government Lots 1, 2, 3 and 4, Townships 53-54 South and, those portions of Sections 1, 2, 3 and 4, Township 54 South, Range 39 East, which lie north of the north right-of-way line of the Tamiami Canal.</section></section><section>shall mean the wetlands described below:<section>That portion of Section 3, Township 54 South, Range 39 East, lying north of U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail); that portion of Section 4, Township 54 South, Range 39 East, lying north of U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail); Government Lot 2, located between Townships 53 and 54 South, Range 39 East; Government Lot 3, located between Townships 53 and 54 South, Range 39 East and Government Lot 4, located between Townships 53 and 54 South, Range 39 East, Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section></section><section>shall mean and include the use of any property, facilities, equipment, processes, products or compounds, or the commission of any acts or any work that causes or materially contributes to:<section prefix='(1)'>The emission into the outdoor air of dust, fume, gas, mist, odor, smoke or vapor, or any combination thereof, of a character and in a quantity as to be detectable by a considerable number of persons or the public so as to interfere with their health, repose or safety, or cause severe annoyance or discomfort, or which tends to lessen normal food and water intake, or produces irritation of the upper respiratory tract, or produces symptoms of nausea, or is offensive or objectionable to normal persons because of inherent chemical or physical properties, or causes injury or damage to real property, personal property or human, animal or plant life of any kind, or which interferes with normal conduct of business, or is detrimental or harmful to the health, comfort, living conditions, welfare and safety of the inhabitants of this County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The discharge into any of the waters of this County of any organic or inorganic matter or deleterious substance or chemical compounds, or any effluent containing the foregoing, in such quantities, proportions or accumulations so as to interfere with the health, repose or safety of any considerable number of persons or the public, or to cause severe annoyance or discomfort, or which tends to lessen normal food and water intake, or produces symptoms of nausea, or is offensive or objectionable to normal persons because of inherent chemical or physical properties, or causes injury or damage to real property, personal property, human, plant or animal life of any kind, or which interferes with normal conduct of business, or is detrimental or harmful to the health, comfort, living conditions, welfare and safety of the inhabitants of this County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any violation of provisions of this chapter which becomes detrimental to health or threatens danger to the safety of persons or property, or gives offense to, is injurious to, or endangers the public health and welfare, or prevents the reasonable and comfortable use and enjoyment of property by any considerable number of the public.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Adverse environmental impact to a coastal or freshwater wetlands.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Cumulative adverse environmental impact to a coastal or freshwater wetlands.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Adverse environmental impact to environmentally-sensitive tree resources.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Cumulative adverse environmental impact to environmentally-sensitive tree resources.</section></section><section>shall mean that property of a substance which materially offends the sense of smell.</section><section>shall mean any tank, box, sump or other container in which any petroleum or product thereof, floating on or entrained or contained in water entering such tank, box, sump or other container, is physically separated and removed from such water prior to outfall, drainage, or recovery of such water.</section><section>shall mean any water supply system using a well and piping to provide potable water for human consumption.</section><section>shall mean within the boundaries of a facility location, property or site including those sites spatially separated by public or private rights-of-way.</section><section>shall mean the containment and disposal of stormwater runoff by means other than positive drainage within the limits of the project site.</section><section>shall mean any combustion of combustible material of any type outdoors, in the open, not in any approved enclosure or device, where the products of combustion are not directed through a flue.</section><section>shall mean an underground storage facility which is empty, does not have hazardous materials transferred into or withdrawn from the underground storage facility, is not in active use and is in compliance with the requirements set forth in Chapter 62-761.800, Florida Administrative Code.</section><section>shall mean the maximum extent of area protected by the wellfield protection provisions set forth in of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, for one wellfield or if a wellfield complex exists, the maximum extent of area protected by the wellfield protection provisions set forth in of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, as set forth in the wellfield protection maps adopted by the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section>shall mean a drainage structure designed to discharge to an on-site or off-site location any excess stormwater runoff after an initial runoff volume has been retained on-site.</section><section>shall mean the discharge of sewage from any publicly or privately-owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system or wastewater treatment facility to the surface of the ground or to a surface water.</section><section>shall mean stormwater runoff flowing over an unrestricted ground surface area.</section><section>shall mean (an) owner(s) in fee who construct(s) no more than one (1) single-family or duplex residence per year for personal use and occupancy by said owner(s), and not intended for sale.</section><section>shall mean any of the substances identified in Section 602(a) and Section 602(b) of Title VI of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 by the United States Environmental Protection Agency as contributing to the depletion or destruction of the stratospheric ozone layer of the Earth.</section><section>shall mean any material which at standard conditions, is emitted into the atmosphere in a finely divided form as liquid or solid or both, but shall not include uncombined water vapor.</section><section>shall mean the discharger or, if the discharger is unknown or the contamination was the result of a previously unreported discharge, the property owner or operator who is subject to the provisions of(2).</section><section>shall mean the ability of an aquifer, soil, rock or other geological formation to transmit water.</section><section>shall be construed to include any natural person, individual, public or private corporation, firm, association, joint venture, partnership, municipality, governmental agency, political subdivision, public officer or any other entity whatsoever, or any combination of such, jointly or severally.</section><section>shall mean either that point at which the effluent physically leaves its carrying conduit (open or closed) and discharges into the waters of the State, or a specific point designated by the Florida Department of Environmental Protection for that particular thermal discharge.</section><section>shall mean the use of materials processes, or practices that reduce or eliminate the creation of, or toxicity of, pollutants or wastes at the source.</section><section>shall mean the presence of any foreign substance (organic, inorganic, radiological, biological or thermal) in water which tends to degrade its quality so as to constitute a hazard or impair the usefulness of the water.</section><section>shall mean the direct disposal of stormwater runoff by overland sheet flow or through a channel ditch, or closed pipe system into an on-site or off-site surface water body such as, but not limited to, a lake, lagoon, river, canal, bay or the ocean.</section><section>shall mean water that is satisfactory for drinking, culinary and domestic purposes meeting the quality standards defined in this chapter.</section><section>shall mean parts per million by volume.</section><section>shall mean parts per million by weight and is equivalent to milligrams per liter.</section><section>shall mean any scrap iron or steel which has been mechanically or otherwise processed into a raw material meeting any of the specifications contained in the Scrap Specifications Circular 1993, published by the Institute of Scrap Recycling Industries, Inc., Washington, D.C. Guidelines for Ferrous Scrap.</section><section>shall mean the process of periodic deliberate burning of a pineland in a controlled manner taking into consideration weather and understory moisture conditions, for the purposes of maintaining the pineland in a natural condition and for the promotion of pine regeneration.</section><section>shall mean portions of a site that are to be protected from any tree or understory removal (except as required by the Department) and maintained without any development.</section><section>shall mean any pump station in a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system which directly receives sewage flow from gravity sanitary sewers.</section><section>shall mean any sanitary sewer collection and transmission facilities, including that located both on private property and within a public right-of-way or easement, which is owned or operated by any person other than Miami-Dade County, the state, the United States of America, or any municipality in Miami-Dade County.</section><section>shall mean the total weight of all materials, except uncombined water, introduced into any unit process, which process may cause any discharge into the atmosphere. Solid fuels charged will be considered as part of the process weight, but liquid and gaseous fuels, combustion air, excess air, infiltrated and other air added to the process, will not be so considered. The process weight per hour will be derived by dividing the total process weight by the number of hours in one (1) complete operation from the beginning of any given process to the completion thereof, excluding any time during which the equipment is idle.</section><section>shall mean a temporary fence or other structure built to restrict passage into an area surrounding a tree or stand of trees for the purpose of preventing any disturbance to the roots, trunk or branches of the tree or trees.</section><section>shall mean plumbing for the provision to the public of water for human consumption, such plumbing has at least fifteen (15) service connections or regularly serves an averages of at least twenty-five (25) individuals daily at least three (3) months out of the year or serves at least five (5) individuals and is not a single-family residence or a duplex residence. Such term includes:<section prefix='(1)'>Any collection, treatment, storage and distribution facilities under control of the operator of such system and used primarily in connection with such system, and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any collection or pretreatment storage facilities not under such control which are used primarily in connection with such system.</section></section><section>shall mean any water main in a public water system owned and operated by a public utility.</section><section>shall mean any sanitary sewer collection and transmission facilities, including that portion of the sewage lateral connection located within a public right-of-way or easement, which is owned or operated by Miami-Dade County, the state, the United States of America, or any municipality in Miami-Dade County.</section><section>shall mean any device or system that is used in the treatment (including recycling and reclamation) of sewage and that is owned by a state, county, or municipality. Sewers, pipes, or other conveyances are included only if they convey sewage to a POTW.</section><section>shall include all species classified as endangered, threatened or rare by Sections 581.185—581.187 and Chapter 372 of the Florida Statutes, as amended from time to time; or by Appendix A or B of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Miami-Dade County, Florida, as amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean the sum of the rated horsepower for the same type of pumps in the pump station less the rated horsepower of the one (1) pump of the same type having the greatest rated horsepower, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>shall mean the sum of the rated horsepowers for the same type of pumps in the pump station less the rated horsepower of the one (1) pump of the same type having the greatest rated horsepower, or the equivalent thereof as approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>shall mean a boat docking facility which has boat slips, moorings, vessel tieup spaces, or davit spaces of which fifty (50) percent or more are designated for or contain recreational vessels.</section><section>shall mean any vessel used by its owner or operator for noncommercial purposes.</section><section>shall mean any substance containing any ozone-depleting compound which is utilized in any refrigeration system.</section><section>shall mean any refrigerator, freezer, chiller, cold storage warehouse, refrigeration unit, or any kind of air conditioner (mobile, portable, stationary, motor vehicle).</section><section>shall mean a tree which has been transplanted pursuant to Ordinance Number 89-8 and which continues to be viable at least one (1) year after transplanting.</section><section>shall mean a shade tree, small tree, or palm tree required to be planted pursuant to the provisions of Ordinance Number 89-8.</section><section>shall mean any parcel of land which contains an impervious area and which is classified by the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser as land use types 00 through and including 09 and land use types 50 through and including 69 if said land use contains a single-family or multifamily residence, as set forth in Florida Administrative Code Rule 12D-8.008(2)(c), as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean any facility the purpose of which is disposal, recycling, incineration, processing, storage, transfer, or treatment of solid or liquid waste; but for the purpose of permitting does not include sewage treatment, industrial waste treatment, or facilities exclusively within State or federal jurisdiction.</section><section>shall mean an open basin which intercepts the groundwater table and is used for the storage and ultimate disposal of stormwater runoff by evaporation and seepage.</section><section>shall mean a strip of ground dedicated by the subdivider, or deeded by the owner, for public use.</section><section>shall mean the method of estimating smoke density described in U.S. Bureau of Mines Information Circular 7718.</section><section>shall mean the lowering or elimination of the level of risk posed to human health or the environment through interim remedial actions, remedial action, or institutional, and, if applicable, engineering controls.</section><section>shall mean any cleared, plowed, bulldozed, filled, graded, excavated or paved area, elevated boardwalk or roadway used or capable of being used for the passage of vehicles or persons. Roads shall not mean tracks used or capable of being used solely by off-road vehicles such as airboats, swamp buggies and all-terrain vehicles.</section><section>shall mean the dredging or excavation of an area for the purpose of extracting subsurface materials. Rockmining shall also include ancillary property uses necessary for extracting and processing subsurface materials.</section><section>shall mean the alteration of wetlands by breaking up the limestone surface of a wetland in preparation for agriculture. Rockplowing may include the regrading of surface materials into planting beds at elevations sufficiently high to protect crops from flooding.</section><section>shall mean any room or group of rooms, forming a single habitable unit, used or intended to be used for living and sleeping but not for cooking or eating purposes.</section><section>shall mean a group of roots extending from the base of a tree trunk that must be intact when relocating a tree in order to promote survival of the tree.</section><section>shall mean the commission of any action, by an individual, municipality, organization or corporation, or the keeping, maintaining, propagation, existence or permission of anything, by an individual, municipality, organization or corporation, by which the health or life of an individual or the health or life of individuals, may be threatened or impaired or by which or through which, directly or indirectly, disease may be caused.</section><section>shall mean a conduit which is a part of a gravity or pressurized force main system which receives and transports waste water for treatment and disposal.</section><section>shall mean an impervious layer of materials which is installed so that any volume of hazardous materials which may be discharged from an underground storage facility will be prevented from contacting the environment outside said impervious layer for the period of time necessary to detect and recover all the discharged hazardous materials. Materials or devices used to provide a secondary containment system may include concrete, impervious liners, slurry walls, double-walled tanks, double-walled piping or other devices or materials approved by the Director or the Director's designee.</section><section>shall mean the introduction of water into a subsurface excavation from which the water enters the groundwater. Said excavation shall not exceed a depth of two (2) feet below the average yearly highest groundwater elevation described in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>or shall mean a trench cut into a rock strata supporting a reinforced concrete slab and providing the necessary wall and bottom areas required for exfiltration of stormwater.</section><section>shall mean any settling tank in which the settled sludge is in immediate contact with sewage flowing through the tank thereby allowing the organic solids to be partially decomposed by putrefaction, i.e., anaerobic bacterial action.</section><section>shall mean the pipe(s) which transmits wastewater from a building, residence or facility to a publicly or privately-owned or operated gravity sanitary sewer collection system.</section><section>shall mean the estimated average amount of waste water generated by the actual and projected use of a property as a function of the unsubmerged area of said property. Abutting easements and rights-of-way shall be included to the center lines thereof in calculating the unsubmerged area of the property.</section><section>shall mean that portion of a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system which contributes sewage flow to a particular primary pump station.</section><section>shall mean a portion of a publicly or privately owned or operated sanitary sewer collection system which discharges sewage to a particular key manhole.</section><section>shall mean the introduction of groundwater into any publicly or privately owned or operated gravity sanitary sewer or pump station wet well.</section><section>shall mean the predominantly non-metallic solid material including, without limitation, plastic, broken glass, rubber, foam rubber, soil and fabric, resulting from the shredding of ferrous metals such as, but not limited to, scrap automobiles and appliances.</section><section>shall mean a self-supporting woody perennial plant of low to medium height characterized by multiple stems and branches continuous from the base.</section><section>shall mean a drawing having a scale sufficient to provide the following information: Location of all proposed or existing buildings, septic tanks, utility easements, fences, walls, parking areas, driveways, access roads, setbacks, and any other site development.</section><section>or shall mean source removal, if applicable, site assessment and, if required, one or more of the following: risk assessment, monitoring or remediation. These site rehabilitation actions serve to characterize the nature and extent of contamination and to reduce the levels of contaminants through applicable treatment methods to comply with the clean-up target levels (CTLs) set forth in this chapter.</section><section>shall mean any person who brings into existence a quantity of fifty-five (55) gallons or less of hazardous waste during any one (1) period of three hundred sixty-five (365) consecutive days. However, within the average day pumpage wellfield protection area of the Miami Springs Lower Wellfield, Miami Springs Upper Wellfield, Hialeah Wellfield and John E. Preston Wellfield, a small quantity generator of hazardous waste shall mean any person who brings into existence a quantity of fifty-five (55) gallons or less of hazardous waste during any one (1) period of one hundred twenty (120) consecutive days.</section><section>shall mean the solid particles produced by incomplete combustion or organic substances, including, but not limited to, particles, fly ash, cinders, tarry matter, soot and carbon.</section><section>shall mean garbage, rubbish, refuse, trash, yard trash, construction and demolition debris, or other discarded material, including solids or contained gaseous material resulting from domestic, industrial, commercial, mining, agricultural, or governmental operations. However, subsurface materials which do not contain hazardous materials and which are extracted as a result of rockmining are not included in this definition.</section><section>shall mean the stratum or strata from which water is drawn in the well.</section><section>shall mean the volume, in standard cubic feet, of all gases leaving a source operation; and the boundary of a source operation is that point or surface at which the separation of the air contaminants from the process materials, or the conversion of the process materials into air contaminants, is essentially complete.</section><section>shall mean the last operation preceding the emission of an air contaminant, which operation:<section prefix='(1)'>Results in the separation of the air contaminant from the process material or in the conversion of the process materials and air contaminants, as in the case of combustion fuel; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>Is not an air pollution abatement operation.</section></section><section>shall mean the following wellfields: South Miami Heights, Roberta Hunter Park, Caribbean Park and Rockpit 77 Park wellfields.</section><section>shall mean a tree with any individual trunk which has a DBH of eighteen (18) inches or greater, provided, however, that the following trees are not specimen trees:<section prefix='(1)'>All trees listed in Section 24-49(4)(f).</section><section prefix='(2)'>Non-native fruit trees that are cultivated or grown for the specific purpose of producing edible fruit, including, but not limited to, mangos, avocados, or species of citrus.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Non-native species of the genus Ficus.</section><section prefix='(4)'>All multitrunk trees in the palm family, except Acoelorrhaphe wrightii and Phoenix reclinata which have a minimum overall height of fifteen (15) feet.</section></section><section>(see Site rehabilitation action)</section><section>shall mean a pressure of fourteen and seven-tenths (14.7) pounds per square inch, absolute, and a temperature of sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit. Results of all analyses and tests shall be calculated or reported at this gas temperature and pressure.</section><section>is taken to mean that for the bacteriological test it shall consist of:<section prefix='(1)'>For the bacteriological fermentation tube test, five (5) standard portions of either:<section prefix='(a)'>Ten milliliters (10 ml).</section><section prefix='(b)'>One hundred milliliters (100 ml).</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>For the membrane filter technique, not less than fifty milliliters (50 ml).</section></section><section>shall mean a fund established under Florida Statutes Chapter 375 (as amended from time to time) for the purposes of purchasing environmentally-sensitive land.</section><section>shall mean a business actively engaged in propagating, growing, maintaining and selling tree species that has been licensed to conduct such business by the State of Florida or Miami-Dade County.</section><section>shall mean any conduit which is designed to carry stormwater runoff.</section><section>shall mean the structural, nonstructural or natural features of a parcel of land or watershed which collect, convey, store, absorb, inhibit, treat, use, reuse, or otherwise affect the quantity or quality of stormwater.</section><section>shall mean that portion of a tract of land which shall be left at natural grade (unfilled), filled to an elevation no less than four (4) inches above the seasonal high water table, or excavated below natural grade for the purposes of: managing water which results from rainfall, storing water in the Biscayne Aquifer and recharging the Biscayne Aquifer.</section><section>shall mean the same term as defined by Section 403.031(14), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean the same term as defined by Section 403.031(15), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean the excess rainfall precipitation which runs over the ground surface when the rate of rainfall precipitation exceeds the rate of infiltration of stormwater into the ground.</section><section>shall mean the water which results from rainfall.</section><section>shall mean the same term as defined by Section 403.031(16), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean physical devices used to control stormwater including, but not limited to, levees, dikes, pump stations, spillways, locks, embankments, roadways, lakes, retention ponds, and detention ponds.</section><section>shall mean a reduction in natural infiltration rates or reduction of volume of surface water from a defined area; or transportation of surface waters off-site to the extent that a site's natural hydrological regimen is changed.</section><section>shall mean a condition during which a gravity sanitary sewer contains sewerage flows above the crown of the pipe.</section><section>(see Monitoring well)</section><section>shall mean the removal of any distal branches or limbs of a mangrove tree which will result in the reduction in the overall height of the mangrove tree.</section><section>shall mean the sum of all quantifiable concentration values of organics presumed to be hazardous materials by the designation of the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section>shall mean the sum of the concentration of copper, nickel, total chromium, and zinc.</section><section>shall mean the sum of all quantifiable concentration values of those organics set forth in 40 CFR 413 and 40 CFR 433 of the Code of Federal Regulations, and Xylene.</section><section>shall mean the wetlands within the following geographic boundaries:<section>Beginning at a point on the north right-of-way line of theoretical N.W. 12th Street as it intersects the east side of the Miami-Dade-Broward levee, thence run northerly along the east side of the Miami-Dade-Broward levee for approximately 10 miles to its point of intersection with the eastern right-of-way line of the State Road 997 (Krome Avenue); thence, run northeasterly along the eastern right-of-way line of said State Road 997 (Krome Avenue); to its intersection with the west right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 27 (Okeechobee Road); thence run southeasterly along said west right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 27 (Okeechobee Road); to its intersection with the western right-of-way line of the Homestead Extension of Flordia's Turnpike; thence run southerly along said western right-of-way line of the Homestead Extension of Florida's Turnpike; for approximately 8 miles to theoretical N.W. 12th Street; thence run westerly along theoretical N.W. 12th Street to the point of beginning.</section><section>Beginning at a point on the south right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 41 as it intersects the west right-of-way line of State Road 997; thence run southerly along the west right-of-way line of State Road 997 for approximately 4 miles to the southeast corner of, Township 54 South, Range 38 East; thence run westerly for approximately 1 mile along the south section line of said to its intersection with the east right-of-way line of Levee 31N; thence run northerly for approximately 4 miles along the east right-of-way line of Levee 31N to its intersection with the south right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 41; thence run easterly for approximately 1 mile to the point of beginning.</section></section><section>shall mean the rate at which groundwater is transmitted through a unit width of aquifer under a unit hydraulic gradient.</section><section>shall mean solid waste comprised of yard trash or construction and demolition debris, and shall include but not be limited to paper, cardboard, cloth, glass, plastics, street sweepings, and vehicle tires.</section><section>shall mean the period of time in days or equivalent distance in feet for groundwater to travel from one (1) point in an aquifer to another point in the aquifer.</section><section>shall mean a vegetative community located within freshwater wetlands whose dominant vegetative components consist of native hardwood trees and shrubs.</section><section>shall mean directly or indirectly cutting down, destroying, removing or relocating, or effectively destroying (through damaging, trimming, authorizing or allowing the cutting down, destroying, removing, moving or damaging of) any tree.</section><section>shall mean a woody or fibrous perennial plant with a trunk having a minimum DBH of three (3) inches or with an overall height of twelve (12) or more feet. Tree shall not include any mangrove tree as defined in.</section><section>shall mean a drawing overlaid directly upon the site plan sufficient to provide the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>The location, plotted by accurate techniques, in relation to all proposed development, of all existing trees which are proposed to be destroyed, relocated or preserved,</section><section prefix='(2)'>The common and scientific name of each tree,</section><section prefix='(3)'>The DBH of each tree, or if a multiple trunk tree, the sum DBH for all trunks, and</section><section prefix='(4)'>An estimate of the height of the canopy.</section></section><section>shall mean a soil retaining structure designed to maintain the existing natural ground elevation beneath a tree to preserve the tree when the surrounding area is filled to raise the ground elevation. Tree wells shall have a minimum radius of three (3) feet from the trunk of the tree and a maximum radius of ten (10) feet from the trunk of the tree.</section><section>shall mean a tank, pipe, vessel or other container, or any combination of the foregoing, used or designed to be used for the underground storage or underground transmission of hazardous materials, including but not limited to line leak detectors, monitoring wells, continuous automatic leak detection systems and secondary containment system associated therewith, excluding hydraulic lift systems, excluding sanitary sewers, septic tanks, septic tank drainfields, the primary pipeline transmitting jet fuel from Port Everglades to Homestead Air Base, and any other primary pipeline transmitting hazardous materials from one (1) county to another county. Underground storage facilities have ten (10) percent or more of their total volume below the surface of the ground.</section><section>shall mean the complex of woody, fibrous, herbaceous, and graminoid plant species that are typically associated with a natural forest community.</section><section>shall mean an underground storage facility which was not or is not properly closed or placed out of service in accordance with the rules and regulations of the State of Florida and(6) of this Code and for which there is neither a valid operating permit issued pursuant to(2) of this Code nor, a valid registration placard issued by the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection.</section><section>shall mean any land which meets or exceeds the minimum elevation required by Miami-Dade County flood criteria.</section><section>shall mean a gasoline or gasohol vapor recovery system that uses a vacuum generating device to create a vacuum in the vapor return line from the nozzle boot to the underground storage tank during motor vehicle refueling.</section><section>shall mean any mixed material in a gaseous state which is deformed from a substance usually a liquid, by increased temperature.</section><section>shall mean a watercraft, boat, ship, yacht, barge, canoe, or kayak, used or capable of being used as a means of transportation on water. Vessel shall not mean a floating structure as defined in. Notwithstanding that the floating structure has previously been used as a means of transportation on water or is capable of being used as a means of transportation on water, vessel shall not mean a floating structure as defined in.</section><section>shall mean an area abutting a bulkhead or shoreline where a vessel may be secured.</section><section>shall mean any outfall, ditch, pipe, soakage pit, drainage well, drainfield, or any other method or device by which treated or untreated sewage, industrial waste, or other wastes can enter the surface waters, tidal salt water, or groundwaters, so as to cause water pollution as herein defined.</section><section>shall mean a use which cannot exist or occur without association with marine, freshwater or estuarine water masses.</section><section>shall mean the introduction in, on or upon any surface water or ground water, or tidal water, of any organic or inorganic matter or deleterious substances in such quantities, proportions, accumulations or levels which exceed any of the clean-up target levels (CTLs) set forth in, or which are injurious to human, plant, animal, fish and other aquatic life, or property, or which unreasonably interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property, or the conduct of business.</section><section>shall mean a system which supplies water for drinking, culinary, fire, industrial, commercial, or domestic purposes.</section><section>shall mean the same term as defined by Section 403.031(17), Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean two or more wellfields which: a.) provide raw water to the same water treatment facility or provide raw water to interconnected water treatment facilities for treatment of raw water from the same wellfield and, b.) which wellfields are within the same outer wellfield protection zone.</section><section>shall mean the disposal of stormwater runoff to a storage basin having a bottom elevation lower than one (1) foot below the average October groundwater level as set forth in the Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual, Part II, Section D4, dated September 1, 1974, as may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean those areas as defined in Chapter 373, Florida Statutes, as same may be amended from time to time.</section><section>shall mean any project, activity, or any artificial or man-made alteration of the environment, including, but not limited to, the construction or maintenance of roads; landclearing; trimming or cutting of a mangrove tree(s); dredging; filling; construction or placement of structures, floating structures, fixed structures, facilities or dwellings; excavations; or rockplowing.</section><section>shall mean solid waste comprised of vegetative matter resulting from landscaping maintenance or land clearing operations and shall include, but not be limited to, Melaleuca, Australian pine, Brazilian pepper and other tree and shrub trimmings, grass clippings, palm fronds, trees and tree stumps, and soils not containing any hazardous materials.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 05-196, § 1, 11-3-05; Ord. No. 06-125, § 1, 9-12-06; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08; Ord. No. 12-58, § 1, 7-3-12; Ord. No. 13-27, § 1, 4-2-13)</history></law>