<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00031' order_by='00031' level='4'>DIVISION 3. ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-50.13</section_number>
<catch_line>Responsibilities of the manager.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003413</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-50.13. Responsibilities of the manager.<section>The County Manager shall facilitate such activities, designate such staff, and assign such responsibilities as are necessary to fulfill the purposes of this chapter. The manager shall, at a minimum, do the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Designate staff to evaluate acquisition proposals in accordance with the approved criteria and prepare and implement project management plans.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Make recommendations to the LASC on acquisition proposals.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Designate an Environmentally Endangered Lands Project Review Committee to assist with the coordination of interdepartmental and interagency activities, to assist in the preparation of recommendations on acquisition proposals, and to approve interim management plans. The Project Review Committee shall be chaired by the County Manager or his designee and shall include at least one (1) representative each from the Department of Environmental Resources Management, the Park and Recreation Department, and the Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Designate a negotiation resource committee to develop negotiation strategies for approved acquisition projects, to monitor negotiations, and to assist in coordinating all activities relating to negotiations, purchase agreements and closings, as needed. The Negotiation Resource Committee shall include at least one (1) representative from the Department of Environmental Resources Management, the Department of Development/Facilities Management, the Park and Recreation Department, and the Property Appraiser's Office. The County Attorney shall also designate (a) representative(s) to serve on the Negotiation Resource Committee.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history></law>