<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='3'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00015' order_by='00015' level='4'>ARTICLE IV. NATURAL AND BIOLOGICAL ENVIRONMENTAL RESOURCES PERMITTING AND PROTECTION; REGULATION OF DRAINAGE SYSTEMS AND STORMWATER MANAGEMENT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-50.9</section_number>
<catch_line>Acquisition list.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003370</order_by>
<text><section>The EEL Acquisition List shall consist of the Priority A List and the Priority B List and shall be approved semi-annually by the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with the procedures set forth in Sections and hereinbelow.<section prefix='(1)'>Priority A List.<section prefix='(a)'>The Priority A List shall contain no more than ten (10) projects which shall be selected by the Board of County Commissioners from those acquisition proposals which receive the highest evaluations pursuant to the criteria provided for in Section 24-50.8 and for which acquisition is feasible. No rank order shall be assigned to Priority A projects. The County shall actively pursue the acquisition of Priority A projects.</section><section prefix='(b)'>A project shall be removed from the Priority A List only after purchase by the County, upon approval of the next succeeding acquisition list as provided hereinbelow or by resolution of the Board of County Commissioners. Projects removed from the Priority A List for any reason except purchase by the County shall be placed on the Priority B List.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Priority B. List. The Priority B list shall contain all acquisition proposals which are deemed worthy of acquisition based upon the evaluation criteria provided in Section 24-50.8, and which may feasibly be acquired, but which have not been assigned to the Priority A List. The County may not actively pursue acquisition of a property on the Priority B List unless the share of the purchase price paid from the EEL Acquisition Trust Fund is no more than fifty (50) percent of the total purchase price of the property or unless the seller donates fifty (50) percent or more of the value of the property as estimated in an appraisal report prepared by an independent fee appraiser and accepted by the County.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04)</history></law>