<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00045' order_by='00045' level='2'>Chapter 24 ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION, BISCAYNE BAY AND ENVIRONS DESIGNATED AQUATIC PARK AND CONSERVATION AREA, THE BISCAYNE BAY ENVIRONMENTAL ENHANCEMENT TRUST FUND, AND THE ENVIRONMENTALLY ENDANGERED LANDS PROGRAM</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00021' order_by='00021' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>24-6</section_number>
<catch_line>Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management—Office created; appointment; term; exempt from classified service and merit system; compensation; assistants; operating procedures.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003290</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 24-6. Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management—Office created; appointment; term; exempt from classified service and merit system; compensation; assistants; operating procedures.<section>The office and position of Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, is hereby created and established. The Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the County Manager. Such Director shall be chosen by the Manager on the basis of his qualifications and experience in the field of air and water pollution controls, and the Director shall be a professional engineer registered to practice in the State of Florida under the provisions of Chapter 471, Florida Statutes, or he shall become registered within eighteen (18) months after the date of appointment, or he shall have at least a bachelor's degree from an accredited university in a field which will, in the Manager's judgment, technically qualify him to discharge the duties imposed by this chapter. The Office of Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management, shall constitute a position exempted from the classified service of Miami-Dade County and the State merit system. The salary for such position shall be fixed by the Board of County Commissioners. The Director shall serve under the administrative jurisdiction of the County Manager and subject to the direct supervision of the County Manager. The County Manager shall appoint such assistants to the Director as may be necessary in order that the duties of the Director may be performed properly. The organization and administrative operating procedures of such County office and its relationship and coordination with other County departments shall be established and placed in effect, from time to time, by administrative order of the County Manager, but the Manager shall not have any power to modify the duties imposed upon the Director by this chapter or the procedures prescribed herein for the performance of such duties.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 04-214, §§ 1, 5, 12-2-04; Ord. No. 08-55, § 2, 5-6-08)</history></law>