<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00060' order_by='00060' level='2'>Chapter 30 TRAFFIC AND MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00001' order_by='00001' level='3'>ARTICLE I. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30-388.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Free public parking for the physically disabled.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000003811</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(1)'>Except as provided in subsections (2) and (3) below, any motor vehicle which is qualified to park in a specially marked parking space designated for the physically disabled pursuant to Article II of this chapter shall be permitted to park in any public parking space in Miami-Dade County without incurring a fee for parking. For purposes of this section, the term "public parking space" shall mean a parking space provided by Miami-Dade County and each municipality within Miami-Dade County, and each agency, instrumentality and authority thereof.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notwithstanding subsection (1) above, the Public Health Trust shall be entitled to charge and collect parking fees for the use of any timed parking space, in a parking facility or lot made available for parking by the Public Health Trust, by vehicles that display a disabled parking permit or license plate issued under state law, except that any such vehicle exiting a Public Health Trust parking facility or lot less than two (2) hours from entering the facility or lot shall not be charged parking fees. Any such vehicle exiting the facility or lot more than two (2) hours from entering the facility or lot shall be charged for the time the vehicle uses the facility or lot, except that any such vehicle shall not be charged a parking fee for the first two (2) hours that the vehicle uses the facility or lot.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notwithstanding subsection (1) above, the Aviation and Seaport Departments shall be entitled to charge and collect parking fees for the use of any County airport or seaport parking facility, including facilities providing temporary, short-term, or up-close parking sites, by vehicles that display a disabled parking permit or license tag issued under Sections 316.1958, 320.084, 320.0842, 320.0843, 320.0845, or 320.0848, Florida Statutes, as such sections may be amended from time to time, except that any such vehicle exiting an airport or seaport parking facility less than two (2) hours from entering the facility shall not be charged parking fees. Any such vehicle exiting the facility more than two (2) hours from entering the facility shall be charged for the entire time the vehicle uses the facility.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Notwithstanding subsections (2) and (3) above, no parking charges shall be imposed by the Public Health Trust or the Airport or Seaport Departments upon any vehicle with specialized equipment, such as ramps, lifts, or foot or hand controls, or for utilization by a person who has a disability or whose vehicle is displaying the Florida Toll Exemption permit.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 87-42, ยง 1, 6-16-87; Ord. No. 13-104, ยง 1, 11-5-13; Ord. No. 14-25, ยง 1, 3-4-14)</history></law>