<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00061' order_by='00061' level='2'>Chapter 30A URBAN RENEWAL</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. REDEVELOPMENT OF MIAMI BEACH CITY CENTER/HISTORIC CONVENTION VILLAGE REDEVELOPMENT AND REVITALIZATION AREA</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>30A-52</section_number>
<catch_line>Obligation to appropriate; duration of obligation; limitations on obligation, bond sales and refundings; accounting requirements of County increment.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004005</order_by>
<text><section>Each taxing authority, including The Children's Trust, shall by January first of each year appropriate to the fund for so long as any indebtedness pledging the tax increment due the fund is outstanding (but not later than March 31, 2044, a sum not less than the increment as defined and determined by; provided however, that The Children's Trust shall become exempt commencing on the earlier of (1) the date the Miami Beach Redevelopment Agency's bonds outstanding as of November 1, 2014 are no longer outstanding, or (ii) March 31, 2023. In no year shall the County's obligation to the fund exceed the amount of that year's tax increment as determined in. Beginning with the twentieth year after the date of sale of the initial bonding or indebtedness pledging tax increment funds, no new sale of bonds or indebtedness supported by the County's tax increment may occur nor may existing indebtedness so supported be refunded without Board approval. The County's obligation to fund the fund annually shall continue until all loans, advances, and indebtedness, if any, and interest thereon, of the community redevelopment agency incurred as a result of redevelopment in the redevelopment area have been paid provided however, the County's obligation to fund the fund shall not extend beyond March 31, 2044, unless the County's obligation to fund the fund has not been satisfied. The County's increment contribution is to be accounted for as a separate revenue within the fund but may be combined with other revenues for the purpose of paying debt service. The County must approve the amount, duration of the obligation and the purpose of any bond, note or other form of indebtedness, including advances, pledging or otherwise obligating tax increment funds.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 93-28, ยง 3, 4-27-93; Ord. No. 14-133, ยง 1, 12-16-14)</history></law>