<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='3'>ARTICLE V. GENERAL REQUIREMENTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-304</section_number>
<catch_line>Chauffeur's registration—Additional taxicab requirements.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004167</order_by>
<text><section>Each chauffeur shall:<section prefix='(1)'>Only transport passengers or goods with a properly sealed and operating taximeter with the flag down if so equipped and meter running.</section><section prefix='(2)'>When parked in a designated taxi stand remain adjacent and in attendance to his or her vehicle at all times. All doors on the vehicle are to be closed except when loading or unloading passengers.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Only transport passengers or goods with a lit tell-tale light.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Inquire of a disabled passenger whether he or she requires assistance from the chauffeur to or from the nearest accessible door both at the origin and destination of a trip.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Not accept any other fare while en route to a dispatched call for an accessible vehicle.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, twelve (12) months after the effective date of this ordinance, any chauffeur who seeks authorization to pick-up passengers at Miami International Airport and the Port of Miami shall be required to register with the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources and meet with and abide by the following standards:<section prefix='(a)'>Chauffeurs of Ambassador Cabs shall at all times during the performance of their duties be in compliance with Chapter 31 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Miami-Dade Aviation Operational Directive number 42, Port of Miami Tariff number 10 and the requirements of this section;</section><section prefix='(b)'>A chauffeur seeking authorization to operate an Ambassador Cab shall not be eligible to operate an Ambassador Cab if he or she has during the preceding one (1) year period: (i) been found guilty of more than two violations of Chapter 31 of the Code by an administrative hearing officer; or (ii) failed to pay or appeal more than two citations for violations of Chapter 31 of the Code within the established time; or (iii) paid more than two (2) fines for violating Chapter 31 of the Code;</section><section prefix='(c)'>Any chauffeur of an Ambassador Cab shall be removed from the Ambassador Cab program and not permitted to pick-up passengers at Miami International Airport and the Port of Miami if he or she has during any one (1) year period as an Ambassador Cab chauffeur: (i) been found guilty of more than two violations of Chapter 31 of the Code by an administrative hearing officer; or (ii) failed to pay or appeal more than two (2) citations for violations of Chapter 31 of the Code within the established time; or (iii) paid more than two (2) fines for violating Chapter 31 of the Code;</section><section prefix='(d)'>Any chauffeur of an Ambassador Cab shall be removed from the Ambassador Cab program and not permitted to pick-up passengers at Miami International Airport and the Port of Miami if he or she has during any one (1) year period as an Ambassador Cab chauffeur: (i) been found guilty of one of the following violations of Chapter 31 of the Code by an administrative hearing officer; or (ii) failed to pay or appeal one of the following citations for violating Chapter 31 of the Code within the established time; or (iii) paid a fine for violating one of the following provisions of Chapter 31 of the Code:<section prefix='i.'>Failure to use established rates; or</section><section prefix='ii.'>Refusal to transport a passenger.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding, any provision to the contrary, any chauffeur of an Ambassador Cab shall be permanently removed from and permanently ineligible to apply for the Ambassador Cabs Program and not permitted to pick-up passengers at Miami International Airport and the Port of Miami if he or she has: (i) been found guilty of a second offense of one of the following violations of Chapter 31 of the Code by an administrative hearing officer; or (ii) for a second time, failed to pay or appeal one of the following citations for violating Chapter 31 of the Code within the established time; or (iii) for a second time, paid a fine for violating one of the following provisions of Chapter 31 of the Code:<section prefix='i.'>Failure to use established rates; or</section><section prefix='ii.'>Refusal to transport a passenger.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Chauffeurs removed from operation as an Ambassador Cab chauffeur may not re-apply to pick up passengers at Miami International Airport or the Port of Miami until one (1) year from the date of removal from the program has passed provided that during that period the chauffeur has not: (i) been found guilty of more than two violations of Chapter 31 of the Code by an administrative hearing officer; or (ii) failed to pay or appeal more than two (2) citations for violations of Chapter 31 of the Code within the established time; or (iii) paid more than two (2) fines for violating Chapter 31 of the Code;</section><section prefix='(g)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, beginning six (6) months after the effective date of this ordinance, chauffeurs of Ambassador Cabs shall have and utilize a SunPass device where the toll is fixed. Where the "SunPass Only" or "SunPass Express" toll is not fixed, the chauffeur shall determine whether the passenger desires to use the "SunPass Only" or "SunPass Express" lane and comply with the wishes of the passenger;</section><section prefix='(h)'>Chauffeurs of Ambassador Cabs shall, without exception, wear a collared shirt, dark trousers or skirt and closed shoes;</section><section prefix='(i)'>Chauffeurs of Ambassador Cabs shall open doors for passengers;</section><section prefix='(j)'>Chauffeurs of Ambassador Cabs shall load and unload luggage, unless otherwise instructed by the passenger;</section><section prefix='(k)'>Chauffeurs of Ambassador Cabs shall be prohibited from refusing to accept payment by a credit card.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>Open doors for passengers;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Load and unload luggage, unless otherwise instructed by the passenger;</section><section prefix='(9)'>Be prohibited from refusing to accept payment by a credit card if a credit card processing system is required; and</section><section prefix='(10)'>Not discharge a passenger prior to reaching the passenger's requested destination.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-15, § 5, 1-20-94; Ord. No. 03-45, § 1, 3-11-03; Ord. No. 12-51, § 1, 7-3-12; Ord. No. 14-08, § 1, 1-29-14; Ord. No. 14-09, § 1, 1-29-14)</history></law>