<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-89</section_number>
<catch_line>Vehicle standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004012</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>In addition to the applicable Federal Motor Vehicle Safety requirements in 49 Code of Federal Regulations, part 571 and Florida Statutes, the following vehicle standards apply to all for-hire motor vehicles operated under the provisions of this article. It is the operator's responsibility to insure that each vehicle meets the following standards and minimum inspection requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Brakes within allowable parameters as provided by test equipment readings for stopping effectiveness. There shall be no leaks in lines, hoses, fittings, or parts; hoses shall not be cracked or frayed; there shall be no audible air leaks in air brake system.</section><section prefix='(2)'>License, permit or inspection decals, as applicable, shall be correctly displayed and be clearly visible from the outside of the vehicle;<section prefix='(a)'>Chauffeur registration, operating permit number, rate card, passenger advisory and any additional information as may be required shall be displayed within the vehicle in accordance with the instructions of the CSD.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Vehicle signage and markings shall be as required by this article.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Inside rear-view mirror and a mirror on each side of vehicle.</section><section prefix='(4)'>A functioning speedometer and odometer indicating speed in miles per hour and a functioning odometer indicating distance in miles.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Functioning windows, door handles and latches. The primary and secondary hood/trunk/rear access door latches shall be fully operable.</section><section prefix='(6)'>A functioning interior light within the passenger compartment. If the light becomes defective, the operator must correct the defect on the very next day or remove the vehicle from service at that time.</section><section prefix='(7)'>An operating air-conditioning system that provides cooled and heated air. If the air-conditioning system becomes inoperable, the vehicle must be removed from service until such system is repaired. Maximum output temperature will be based on a sliding scale chart which takes outside air temperature and relative humidity into account. Output temperature will be taken at center duct with controls set for maximum cooling.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The vehicle exterior must be free of grime, oil or other substances and free from cracks, breaks, dents and damaged paint that detracts from the overall appearance of the vehicle and that could harm, injure, soil or impair the passenger or his personal belongings.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Equipped with hubcaps or wheelcovers, on all four (4) wheels. If not on vehicle, the operator must put them on vehicle the next day.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Bumpers/moldings/guards shall be installed/ replaced as originally manufactured except for moldings on side panel doors.</section><section prefix='(11)'>The interior of the trunk, or rear portion of for-hire vehicles, shall be free from dirt, grime, oil, trash, or other material which could soil items placed therein and free of protruding metal or other objects that could damage items placed therein.</section><section prefix='(12)'>The passenger compartment must be clean, free from torn upholstery or floor coverings, damaged or broken seats, and protruding sharp edges. All equipment in the interior of the vehicle shall be safely and adequately secured. There shall be no holes opening to the passenger compartment from the underbody.</section><section prefix='(13)'>A horn which shall be audible.</section><section prefix='(14)'>The driver's vision must be unobstructed on all four (4) sides.</section><section prefix='(15)'>Safe tires no recaps shall be used. Maximum allowable treadwear shall be where tread is level with wear bar, or " when measured at three random places in tire tread. The tires shall be inflated to manufacturer's specifications and free of cuts, cracks, bulges or exposed belts.</section><section prefix='(16)'>Front-end and rear-end alignment shall be within allowable parameters as provided by test equipment readings for alignment.</section><section prefix='(17)'>Wiper blades must be able to clean glass when wet and the rubber element shall not be torn, ripped, or loose.</section><section prefix='(18)'>All lights shall be operable including 4-way flasher, turn and signal, clearance, warning, marker, brakes, taillight, license plate, backup and parking light. All lights must be of correct color and properly positioned as required by Florida Statutes and regulations. All dome lights must be operable with lens in place.</section><section prefix='(19)'>Reflectors and lenses shall not be cracked or missing and must be of correct color and properly positioned.</section><section prefix='(20)'>Headlights, low and high beam, shall be operable, and within test equipment allowable readings.</section><section prefix='(21)'>Glass shall not be broken or cracked and chips must be capable of being ground out, leaving a smooth, clear finish.</section><section prefix='(22)'>Doors shall be operable with all weather stripping and rubber seals.</section><section prefix='(23)'>Vehicle steering and suspension shall be functional.</section><section prefix='(24)'>Seatbelts for all persons transported shall be in place and functional, unless otherwise exempted by regulation.</section><section prefix='(25)'>Accessible vehicles shall have posted the international symbol of accessibility for disabled persons in the manner prescribed by CSD and shall be equipped with the following:<section>Ramp or lift facility which is operated electrically, hydraulically or manually with sufficient capacity to safely and smoothly lift passengers into and out of the vehicle and is in compliance with the lift and ramp requirements of the Americans with Disabilities Act.</section><section>For each wheelchair passenger transported, four (4) points of securement of latching or locking to the vehicle and the wheelchair in which the passenger will ride. The latching or locking devices shall be designed to minimize any lateral, longitudinal, or vertical motion of the passenger conveyance within the vehicle.</section><section>For each wheelchair passenger being transported, there shall be sufficient restraining belts or straps designed to securely confine the passenger to the wheelchair in which he or she is transported. The restraining belts or straps shall be utilized.</section></section><section prefix='(26)'>Vehicles, other than taxicabs, used to transport passengers shall not display the word(s) "taxicab," "taxi" or "cab" on the vehicle exterior or interior and shall not be equipped with a taximeter.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Taxicabs shall meet the following additional standards:<section prefix='(1)'>The taxicab number, fares or rates, trade name or business name and passenger service company's telephone number shall be permanently affixed to the exterior of the vehicle in accordance with instruction issued by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Vehicle exterior color scheme must be approved by the CSD.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The top and tell-tale lights must be operable. Only taxis shall be equipped with a taximeter or top tell-tale light.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Advertisement on behalf of third parties may be displayed on the outside or inside of a for-hire vehicle provided approval is given by the CSD and any display is installed pursuant to instructions of the CSD. In no event shall the top and tell-tale lights of a taxicab be obscured.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Taxicabs operated under for-hire licenses issued through the lottery process provided in Section 31-82 shall have a mobile two-way radio, excluding CB radios, or a cellular telephone, installed and operating properly in compliance with applicable standards and requirements of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC).</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Required Technology. Beginning twenty-four (24) months after the effective date of this ordinance, any taxicab that picks up passengers in Miami Dade County shall be required to have the following required technology:<section prefix='(1)'>Credit Card Processing System. Each taxicab shall be equipped with an operable back of seat credit card processing system.<section prefix='(i)'>The credit card processing system shall allow the passenger to utilize his or her credit card in the rear compartment of the taxicab without handing the card to the chauffeur. Said equipment shall list tips, fares, tolls and fees separately. The credit card payment display terminal shall be interfaced with the vehicle's taxi meter and shall be programmed to display all authorized meter and flat fare rates. The meter shall be used for all fares, including flat fare trips. In the event the credit card processing system is not operational, the chauffeur shall: (1) immediately notify the RER department of the situation; (2) repair the system and have it re-inspected within forty eight (48) hours at the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources Vehicle Inspection Facility; and (3) notify any passenger that the system is not working, and make available to the passenger a mobile credit card processing system. If available, the chauffeur shall (a) utilize a mobile credit card processing system which has the capability to provide a receipt to the passenger and (b) provide each passenger with a receipt. If the credit card processing system is not repaired within forty-eight (48) hours after malfunctioning, the chauffeur shall remove the vehicle from service and not pick up passengers until the system is re-inspected and found to be functional.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>No credit card processing fee, convenience fee, equipment rental fee or any other additional fees or charges are to be paid by the passenger when using a credit card to pay the fare. A receipt shall be provided for all trips. All customer receipts shall be generated by a taximeter or other electronic device and shall contain the date and time that the trip starts, the time the trip ends, and total distance traveled. The receipt shall also include the fare charged, the name and telephone number of the passenger service company, the operating permit number, the chauffeur registration number, and the telephone number and e-mail address for filing complaints with the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. Chauffeurs shall be prohibited from refusing to accept payment by a credit card;</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Any and all credit card service providers shall utilize a paycard or direct deposit system and establish an account directly with each chauffeur that provides for electronic payments. Payments for taxicab fares shall be credited to a chauffeur's paycard or bank account within two (2) business days. Only credit card processing systems approved by the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources may be utilized in taxicabs. The processing of credit card payments shall comply with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>The County Commission shall adopt a resolution within one hundred and fifty (150) days after the effective date of this ordinance which offers a discount in taxicab fares or rates where payment is made by cash, check or other means not involving the use of a credit card as permitted by section 501.0117, Florida Statutes. Within ninety (90) days from the effective date of this ordinance, the Mayor shall prepare a fare resolution pursuant to the provisions of Section 31-87 which shall offer a discount in taxicab fares or rates where payment is made by cash, check or other means not involving the use of a credit card. The discount shall be offered to all prospective passengers. The Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources shall consult with the industry and any existing taxicab advisory group prior to completing the fare resolution required by this subsection.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Global Positioning Dispatch System. Taxicabs must be integrated with a global positioning dispatch system capable of determining the location of each taxicab utilizing the system twenty-four (24) hours a day, three hundred and sixty-five (365) days a year. All taxicabs shall have a mobile two-way radio or electronic dispatch system, installed and operating properly that is connected to and subscribed to by a passenger service company that has a fixed-base call center operated twenty-four (24) hours a day, three hundred and sixty-five (365) days a year. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, the requirements of this subsection shall not take effect until thirty (30) months after the effective date of this ordinance;</section><section prefix='(3)'>SunPass Device. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, beginning six (6) months after the effective date of this ordinance, any taxicab that picks up passengers in Miami Dade County shall have and utilize a SunPass device where the toll is fixed. Where the "SunPass Only" or "SunPass Express" toll is not fixed, the chauffeur shall determine whether the passenger desires to use the "SunPass Only" or "SunPass Express" lane and comply with the wishes of the passenger;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Digital Security Camera System. Taxicabs shall have an operable digital security camera system in accordance with the requirements stated in Chapter 31, Section 31-82(o)(7)(iii) of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, the requirements of this subsection shall not take effect until thirty (30) months after the effective date of this ordinance;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Warning Lights. Taxicabs shall be equipped with operable warning lights, in accordance with the requirements stated in Chapter 31-82(o)(7)(v) of the Code of Miami-Dade County for the purpose of advising others and law enforcement agents that an emergency situation exists within the vehicle. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, the requirements of this subsection shall not take effect until thirty (30) months after the effective date of this ordinance;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Top Lights. Taxicabs shall be equipped with a "vacant" light attached to the top of the roof or to the top of the dome light. Such light unit shall be connected to a contact switch attached to the taximeter, and such contact switch shall operate automatically to illuminate the "vacant" light when the taximeter is not in operation, indicating the cab is vacant and for hire, and to extinguish such light when the taximeter is in operation. No person shall drive or operate any taxicab with such a light illuminated when such taxicab is transporting a passenger. Such top light must utilize equipment with the requisite wattage to ensure that the top light is visible to passengers and the public from a reasonable distance.</section></section><section>All taxicabs shall be inspected by the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources and shall receive and be required to display a decal issued by Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources demonstrating compliance with technology requirements.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The CSD shall conduct an annual taximeter inspection for each taxicab and shall inspect each vehicle for compliance with the foregoing standards, and any other requirement or prohibition contained in this article other than standards, requirements or prohibitions relating to taximeters, as provided below. The CSD shall charge a fee for such inspections. In addition to regular inspections, the CSD, any police officer or any other authorized personnel may inspect any for-hire motor vehicle at any time, and may require the driver of said vehicle to stop the vehicle at any time, and to permit the inspection of the interior or exterior of the vehicle, and to produce any license, permit, or document required by this article. The results of each inspection and the date for the next inspection shall be recorded and a copy provided the operator. Any vehicle failing to meet required safety standards shall not be operated as a for-hire vehicle until such time as the vehicle satisfactorily passes a reinspection. The CSD shall charge a fee for such reinspection. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the quarterly inspection of each vehicle between and including five (5) and fifteen (15) model years old to determine compliance with the vehicle condition standards required by Section 31-89(a)(3), (5), (6), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), (12), (13) and (14), Section 31-89(b)(1), (2), (3), (4) and (5) and Section 31-89(c)(1), (2) and (3) shall commence on May 1, 1995 and the quarterly inspection of each such vehicle to determine compliance with the vehicle safety and mechanical standards required by Section 31-89(a)(1), (2) and (4) shall be reduced to semi-annual inspection until July 1, 1998.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, from and after ninety (90) days after the conduct of the lottery process, all taxicabs operated under for-hire licenses issued through the lottery process provided in Section 31-82 shall comply with the requirements of subsection (5) of subsection (b) of this section.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Taxicab vehicle age limits and inspection schedules. Twenty-four (24) months after the effective date of this ordinance, taxicab vehicle age limits and frequency of for-hire inspections are as follows provided, however, that the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources may inspect a for-hire vehicle at any time. Any vehicle initially placed into service, shall not have been previously used as a taxicab, or have a "rebuilt" or "salvage" title and shall be no greater than three (3) model years of age. Any vehicle over six (6) model years of age shall not be operated as a taxicab. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any taxicab:<section prefix='(1)'>That operates as a Wheelchair Accessible Cab initially placed into service shall not have been previously used as a taxicab or have a "rebuilt" or "salvage" title and shall be no greater than three (3) model years of age. Any vehicle over eight (8) model years of age shall not operate as a Wheelchair Accessible Cab;</section><section prefix='(2)'>That is initially placed in service within twenty-four (24) months of the effective date of this ordinance, may continue to operate until the taxicab has reached eight (8) model years of age. At the expiration of eight (8) model years, each taxicab shall be required to adhere to the vehicle age requirements mandated by this subsection.</section></section><section>Taxicabs shall minimally meet the following inspection schedule:<section prefix='(1)'>Taxicabs 1 through 2 model years of age shall be inspected annually;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Taxicabs 3 through 4 model years of age shall be inspected semi-annually;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Taxicabs 5 model years of age or more shall be inspected quarterly.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Telecommunication devices for taxis. Beginning January 1, 1999, all taxicabs shall have a mobile two-way radio, excluding CB radios, or a cellular telephone, installed and operating properly in compliance with applicable standards and requirements of the Federal Communications Commission and this chapter.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The County Commission shall, as deemed appropriate, adopt within twelve (12) months of the effective date of this ordinance a fare increase pursuant to the provisions of section 31-87 in light of the additional technology requirements mandated by subsection 31-89(c).</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, § 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 87-12, § 2, 3-17-87; Ord. No. 89-44, § 1, 5-23-89; Ord. No. 90-74, § 1, 7-24-90; Ord. No. 94-15, § 3, 1-20-94; Ord. No. 98-105, § 1, 7-9-98; Ord. No. 00-139, § 1, 11-14-00; Ord. No. 03-45, § 1, 3-11-03; Ord. No. 14-08, § 1, 1-29-14)</history></law>