<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='2'>Chapter 31 VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. LICENSING AND REGULATION OF FOR-HIRE MOTOR VEHICLES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>31-93</section_number>
<catch_line>Special provisions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004073</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>The provisions of this article shall be the exclusive regulations applicable to the provision of and operation of for-hire motor vehicle transportation services in Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding the provisions of any municipal ordinance, resolution or agreement to the contrary, from and after the effective date of this article no municipality shall authorize, establish, change, alter, amend, or otherwise regulate for-hire transportation in Miami-Dade County. Regulations established by this article shall be uniform throughout Miami-Dade County both in the incorporated and unincorporated areas without regard to municipal boundaries. All municipal ordinances or resolutions to the contrary are hereby superseded and rescinded.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Ambassador Cabs. Any taxicab licensed pursuant to Section 31-82 of this article and meeting all standards set forth in Section 31-89 of this article shall seek and receive authorization to provide transportation of persons and their baggage from Miami International Airport and from the Port of Miami. The transportation of persons and baggage from Miami International Airport or from the Port of Miami shall constitute an agreement by the operator that he/she/it will conform and cause the chauffeur driving such taxicab to conform to such terms, conditions, and fees. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, any taxicab for-hire license holder who seeks authorization to pick-up passengers at Miami International Airport and the Port of Miami utilizing his/her/its taxicab shall be required to register with the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources and comply with and abide by the standards set forth below. Taxicabs authorized to provide taxicab service at Miami International Airport and the Port of Miami shall be designated as Ambassador Cabs. For purposes of this Article, the Miami Intermodal Center (MIC) shall be considered part of Miami International Airport, and all taxicabs which provide taxicab service from the MIC shall be subject to all provisions governing taxicab service at Miami International Airport. Twelve (12) months after the effective date of this ordinance, all taxicabs transporting persons and their baggage from Miami International Airport or from the Port of Miami shall be registered as Ambassador Cabs. Ambassador Cabs shall comply with the following requirements:<section prefix='(1)'>Credit Card Processing System. Each Ambassador Cab shall be equipped with an operable back of seat credit card processing system.<section prefix='(i)'>The credit card processing system shall allow the passenger to utilize his or her credit card in the rear compartment of the taxicab without handing the card to the chauffeur. Said equipment shall list tips, fares, tolls and fees separately. The credit card payment display terminal shall be interfaced with the vehicle's taximeter and shall be programmed to display all authorized meter and flat fare rates. The meter shall be used for all fares, including flat fare trips. In the event the credit card processing system is not operational, the chauffeur shall: (1) immediately notify the RER department of the situation; (2) repair the system and have it re-inspected within forty-eight (48) hours at the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources Vehicle Inspection Facility; and (3) notify any passenger that the system is not working, and make available to the passenger a mobile credit card processing system. If available, the chauffeur shall (a) utilize a mobile credit card processing system which has the capability to provide a receipt to the passenger and (b) provide each passenger with a receipt. If the credit card processing system is not repaired within forty-eight (48) hours after malfunctioning, the chauffeur shall remove the vehicle from service and not pick up passengers at Miami International Airport or the Port of Miami until the system is re-inspected and found to be functional.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>No credit card processing fee, convenience fee, equipment rental fee or any other additional fees or charges are to be paid by the passenger when using a credit card to pay the fare. A receipt shall be provided for all trips. All customer receipts shall be generated by a taximeter or other electronic device and shall contain the date and time that the trip starts, the time the trip ends, and total distance traveled. The receipt shall also include the fare charged, the name and telephone number of the passenger service company, the operating permit number, the chauffeur registration number, and the telephone number and e-mail address for filing complaints with the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources. Chauffeurs shall be prohibited from refusing to accept payment by a credit card.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Any and all credit card service providers shall utilize a paycard or direct deposit system and establish an account directly with each chauffeur that provides for electronic payments. Payments for taxicab fares shall be credited to a chauffeur's paycard or bank account within two (2) business days. Only credit card processing systems approved by the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources may be utilized in taxicabs. The processing of credit card payments shall comply with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard;</section><section prefix='(iv)'>The County Commission shall adopt a resolution within one hundred and fifty (150) days after the effective date of this ordinance which offers a discount in taxicab fares or rates where payment is made by cash, check or other means not involving the use of a credit card as permitted by section 501.0117, Florida Statutes. Within ninety (90) days from the effective date of this ordinance, the Mayor shall prepare a fare resolution pursuant to the provisions of Section 31-87 which shall offer a discount in taxicab fares or rates where payment is made by cash, check or other means not involving the use of a credit card. The discount shall be offered to all prospective passengers. The Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources shall consult with the industry and any existing taxicab advisory group prior to completing the fare resolution required by this subsection.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Global Positioning Dispatch System. Ambassador Cabs must be integrated with a global positioning dispatch system capable of determining the location of each taxicab utilizing the system twenty-four (24) hours a day, three hundred and sixty-five (365) days a year. All Ambassador Cabs shall have a mobile two-way radio or electronic dispatch system, installed and operating properly that is connected to and subscribed to by a passenger service company that has a fixed-base call center operated twenty-four (24) hours a day, three hundred and sixty-five (365) days a year. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, the requirements of this subsection shall not take effect until twenty-four (24) months after the effective date of this ordinance;</section><section prefix='(3)'>SunPass Device. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, beginning six (6) months after the effective date of this ordinance, any Ambassador Cab that picks up passengers in Miami Dade County shall have and utilize a SunPass device where the toll is fixed. Where the "SunPass Only" or "SunPass Express" toll is not fixed, the chauffeur shall determine whether the passenger desires to use the "SunPass Only" or "SunPass Express" lane and comply with the wishes of the passenger;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Digital Security Camera System. Ambassador Cabs shall have an operable digital security camera system in accordance with the requirements stated in Chapter 31, Section 31-82(o)(7)(iii) of the Code of Miami-Dade County. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, the requirements of this subsection shall not take effect until twenty-four (24) months after the effective date of this ordinance;</section><section prefix='(5)'>Warning Lights. Ambassador Cabs shall be equipped with operable warning lights, in accordance with the requirements stated in Chapter 31-82(o)(7)(v) of the Code of Miami-Dade County for the purpose of advising others and law enforcement agents that an emergency situation exists within the vehicle. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, the requirements of this subsection shall not take effect until twenty-four (24) months after the effective date of this ordinance;</section><section prefix='(6)'>Top Lights. Ambassador Cabs shall be equipped with a "vacant" light attached to the top of the roof or to the top of the dome light. Such light unit shall be connected to a contact switch attached to the taximeter, and such contact switch shall operate automatically to illuminate the "vacant" light when the taximeter is not in operation, indicating the cab is vacant and for hire, and to extinguish such light when the taximeter is in operation. No person shall drive or operate any taxicab with such a light illuminated when such taxicab is transporting a passenger. Such top tail light must utilize equipment with the requisite wattage to ensure that the top tail light is visible to passengers and the public from a reasonable distance;</section><section prefix='(7)'>Vehicle Decal. Ambassador Cab shall have a special "Ambassador Cab" decal designated by the Department displayed on the vehicle. Such decal shall be placed in the manner and place as directed by the Department. Ambassador Cabs shall not be permitted to pick up passengers at either Miami International Airport or the Port of Miami without the required decal;</section><section prefix='(8)'>Vehicle Age Requirements and Standards. Any Ambassador Cab initially placed into service shall not have been previously used as a taxicab, or have a "rebuilt" or "salvage" title, and shall be no greater than three (3) model years of age. Any vehicle over six (6) model years of age shall not operate as a taxicab at either Miami International Airport or the Port of Miami.<section>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, any taxicab that is initially placed in service within twelve (12) months of the effective date of this ordinance, may continue to operate until the taxicab has reached eight (8) model years of age. At the expiration of eight (8) model years, each taxicab shall be required to adhere to the vehicle age requirements mandated by this subsection;</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>Vehicle Age Requirements and Standards for Wheelchair Accessible Cabs. Any Wheelchair Accessible Ambassador Cab initially placed into service shall not have been previously used as a Wheelchair Accessible Cab, or have a "rebuilt" or "salvage" title and shall be no greater than three (3) model years of age. Any vehicle over eight (8) model years of age shall not operate as a Wheelchair Accessible Cab at either Miami International Airport or the Port of Miami;</section><section prefix='(10)'>Compliance with Other Provisions. Ambassador Cabs shall at all times be in compliance with Chapter 31 of the Code of Miami Dade County.</section></section><section>Any Ambassador Cab that is also an alternative fuel vehicle, as defined in section 403.42(2)(b), Florida Statutes, shall have priority access to the Miami International Airport terminal and the Port of Miami terminal to pick up passengers.</section><section>Any Ambassador Cab that has met all the requirements of the Ambassador Cab program and is designated as an Ambassador Cab within 180 days after the effective date of this ordinance shall have priority access to the Miami International Airport terminal and the Port of Miami terminal to pick up passengers until all provisions of this ordinance are mandated.</section><section>The County Commission shall, as deemed appropriate, adopt within twelve (12) months of the effective date of this ordinance a fare increase pursuant to the provisions of in light of the additional technology requirements mandated by subsection(b).</section><section prefix='(c)'>Underserved taxicab service area.<section prefix='(1)'>An underserved taxicab service area is hereby established. For purposes of this subsection, an "underserved taxicab service area" means the economically disadvantaged area in Miami-Dade County that is bounded as follows:<section prefix='1.'>on the north by a line commencing at N.W. 47th Avenue and N.W. 215th Street running east to N.E. 2nd Avenue;</section><section prefix='2.'>on the east by a line commencing at N.W. 215th Street and running north to south along N.E. 2nd Avenue to N.W. 7th Street;</section><section prefix='3.'>on the south by a line commencing at N.E. 2nd Avenue and running west along 7th Street to N.W. 42nd Avenue; and</section><section prefix='4.'>on the west by a line commencing at N.W. 7th Street and N.W. 42nd Avenue north to N.W. 119th Street, west along N.W. 119th Street to N.W. 47th Avenue, north along 47th Avenue to N.W. 135th Street, west along 135th Street to N.W. 57th Avenue, north along 57th Avenue to N.W. 167th Street, east along N.W. 167th Street to N.W. 47th Avenue, north along 47th Avenue to N.W. 215th Street.</section><section>For purposes of this subsection, an "underserved area taxicab" means a taxicab where: (a) the for-hire license holder has entered into a passenger service company agreement with a passenger service company that has its principal place of business within the underserved taxicab service area; (b) an average minimum of seventy-five (75) percent of all pickups by the taxicab during each twenty-four hour period originate in the underserved taxicab service area; and (c) the for-hire license holder has applied for and been designated by the Director of CSD as an underserved area taxicab. Any for-hire license holder who seeks to be designated as an underserved area taxicab shall complete and submit a form provided by CSD documenting compliance with the provisions of this subsection for the three-month period preceding submission of the application. Each for-hire license holder authorized to operate as an underserved area taxicab shall on a semiannual basis submit on a form provided by CSD documentation demonstrating continuing compliance with the requirements of this subsection. Failure of the underserved area taxicab for-hire license holder to comply with any of the provisions of this subsection shall result in the suspension or revocation of authorization to operate as an underserved area taxicab. All taxicabs operated pursuant to this subsection that were, as of March 14, 2007, equipped with a properly installed and operating two-way dispatch system shall continue to utilize and maintain the two-way dispatch system which shall be operated twenty-four hours a day.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Underserved area for-hire taxicab licenses shall be issued through a separate lottery pursuant to Section 31-82(o)(3) to qualified chauffeurs who satisfy the criteria of Section 31-82(q) and enter into a binding agreement with the County that contains, among others, the following provisions: (i) the chauffeur is restricted to picking up passengers in an underserved taxicab service area only; and (ii) the chauffeur shall enter into a passenger service company agreement with a passenger service company which has its principal place of business in an underserved taxicab service area. Any chauffeur issued a for-hire taxicab license pursuant to this subsection shall not transfer the taxicab license during the time periods specified in Section 31-82(q) of the Code. Any transfer of an underserved taxicab license shall only be made to a qualified chauffeur who meets the requirements of this subsection. The price for an underserved taxicab area for-hire license issued pursuant to a lottery shall be fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000.00).</section><section prefix='(3)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, a taxicab that satisfies the requirements of either subsection (c)(1) or (c)(2) shall meet the following vehicle age requirements: any vehicle initially placed into service shall not have been previously used as a taxicab and shall be no greater than eight (8) model years of age. Any vehicle over ten (10) years of age shall not be operated as a taxicab.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, a taxicab that satisfies the requirements of either subsection (c)(1) or (c)(2) may utilize a color scheme approved by the Director of CSD which does not satisfy the requirements of Section 31-85(a) pertaining to uniform color scheme.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>South Miami-Dade taxicab service area. A South Miami-Dade taxicab service area is hereby established. For purposes of this subsection, the South Miami-Dade taxicab service area means the area located south of S.W. 88 Street. South Miami-Dade taxicab service area for-hire taxicab licenses shall be issued through a separate lottery, pursuant to Section 31-82(o)(2), to qualified chauffeurs who satisfy the criteria of Section 31-82(q) and enter into a binding agreement with the County that the chauffeur is restricted to picking up passengers in the South Miami-Dade taxicab service area only. Any chauffeur issued a for-hire taxicab license pursuant to this subsection shall not transfer the taxicab license during the time periods specified in section 31-82(q) of this Code. Any transfer of a South Miami-Dade taxicab service area license shall only be made to a qualified chauffeur who meets the requirements of this subsection. The price for a South Miami-Dade taxicab service area for-hire license issued pursuant to a lottery shall be fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000.00). All taxicabs operated pursuant to this subsection that were, as of March 14, 2007, equipped with a properly installed and operating two-way dispatch system shall continue to utilize and maintain the two-way dispatch system which shall be operated twenty-four (24) hours a day.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Notwithstanding the vehicle age limits required by Sections 31-82(l)(4), 31-89(f) and 31-93(c)(3) of the Code, any properly permitted and inspected taxicab scheduled for retirement on December 31, 2012 shall be allowed to be operated for an additional one-year period. Notwithstanding the vehicle age limits required by Sections 31-82(l)(4), 31-89(f) and 31-93(c)(3) of the Code, any properly permitted and inspected model year 2005 taxicab scheduled for retirement on December 31, 2013 shall be allowed to be operated until June 30, 2014. No further extensions shall be granted.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, each for-hire license holder who has been issued a for-hire taxicab license prior to September 3, 2012, which is required to be operated using a taxicab in the underserved taxicab service area pursuant to Section 31-93(c) or the South Miami taxicab service area pursuant to Section 31-93(d) may convert that for-hire license into a license which may be operated in both the designated underserved area and countywide (hereinafter "hybrid underserved taxicab license" or "hybrid underserved taxicab") as provided herein. An underserved taxicab license may be converted into a hybrid underserved taxicab license upon payment of five thousand dollars ($5,000.00). A hybrid underserved taxicab license may be operated countywide on alternating days as follows. All hybrid underserved taxicabs whose license number ends in an odd number (i.e., 1, 3, 5, 7, 9) are required to pick up passengers exclusively in the designated underserved taxicab service area or South Miami taxicab service area, whichever is applicable, on odd-numbered days of the month. All hybrid underserved taxicabs whose license number ends in an even number (i.e., 0, 2, 4, 6, 8) are required to pick up passengers exclusively in the designated underserved taxicab service area or South Miami taxicab service area, whichever is applicable, on even-numbered days of the month. To "pick up passengers exclusively in the designated underserved taxicab service area or South Miami taxicab service area" means that such taxicabs may discharge passengers at any location, but may only accept passengers in the designated underserved taxicab service area. No hybrid underserved taxicab operating pursuant to this section may provide transportation of persons and their baggage from Miami International Airport.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-85, § 3, 7-21-81; Ord. No. 81-116, § 1, 10-26-81; Ord. No. 83-2, § 1, 1-18-83; Ord. No. 84-17, § 1, 2-2-84; Ord. No. 85-40, § 2, 6-6-85; Ord. No. 88-70, § 1, 7-19-88; Ord. No. 88-118, § 2, 12-6-88; Ord. No. 90-7, § 1, 2-6-90; Ord. No. 98-105, § 1, 7-9-98; Ord. No. 99-71, § 1, 6-22-99; Ord. No. 01-177, § 1, 10-23-01; Ord. No. 04-103, § 1, 5-11-04; Ord. No. 07-60, § 1, 4-24-07; Ord. No. 11-11, § 1, 3-1-11; Ord. No. 11-102, § 1, 12-19-11; Ord. No. 12-65, § 1, 9-6-12; Ord. No. 12-68, § 1, 9-6-12; Ord. No. 14-09, § 1, 1-29-14; Ord. No. 14-11, § 1, 1-29-14)</history></law>