<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. DUTIES OF PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='4'>DIVISION 1. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-54</section_number>
<catch_line>Annual service fee payable to Board.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004162</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-54. Annual service fee payable to Board.<section>Each public utility operating under a certificate issued by the Board shall pay to the County each year, as a part of the cost of providing public utility regulation in the public interest, a sum equal to one dollar and fifty cents ($1.50) per each one hundred dollars ($100.00) of the annual gross operating revenues of said public utility derived from its operations conducted within the County pursuant to the authorization contained in said certificate. However, the annual service fee due from each municipality owned or operated public utility shall be applicable only to gross revenues derived from sales made to consumers not within the boundaries of said municipality. Each annual service fee shall be based on such gross revenues for the twelve-month period ending on the anniversary date of said certificate and shall be payable on the first day of the first month following said anniversary date, except that the annual service fee due from each municipality shall be due and payable on November first each year and shall be based upon the revenues for the twelve (12) months ending September thirtieth of that year. Each municipal utility may increase its rates so as to pass through, to its customers, the service fee imposed upon said utility by this section. On a one-time basis only, said rates may be increased after filing and review by the Board without the necessity of notice and public hearing as provided by. Payment of each fee shall be accompanied by a statement, verified by the public utility involved, showing its gross operating revenues upon which such service fee is computed. This statement shall be in such form and detail as the Board shall prescribe and shall be subject to audit by the County. The Board may refund any overpayment of any such fee and may require the utility to pay such additional amount as may be due in case of an underpayment. The service fee payable hereunder shall be used exclusively by the Water and Sewer Board to administer and regulate public utilities in Miami-Dade County, Florida. No part of said fee shall be used for purposes other than public utility regulation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-20, ยง 26, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 75-28, ยง 17, 5-7-75; Ord. No. 79-41, ยง 1, 6-19-79; Ord. No. 80-98, ยง 2, 9-16-80)</history></law>