<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. DUTIES OF PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='4'>DIVISION 1. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-55</section_number>
<catch_line>Contracts with subdivision developers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004124</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-55. Contracts with subdivision developers.<section prefix='(a)'>All public utilities under this chapter are authorized to enter into reasonable contracts with the owner or owners of all or substantially all of the lots in a subdivision or parcels of land in an area not within a service area of another public utility for the purpose of furnishing water or sewer service, or both, to such subdivision or area; provided that any such proposed contract shall either conform to the terms and conditions prescribed by rules approved by the Board of County Commissioners or first be submitted to and approved by the Board. No such contract shall be approved by the Board that is contrary to the public interest or would adversely affect the utility's ability to render adequate and efficient service to its existing customers.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The provisions of this section shall not apply to nor affect any bona fide contract or agreement entered into and delivered prior to the effective date of this chapter, and in respect to such contracts the provisions of this chapter governing the regulation of rates and charges shall apply only to rates and charges for service after the installation and connection of the facilities of the public utilities made under such prior contracts.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-20, ยง 19, 7-5-60; Ord. No. 62-28, ยง 6, 7-3-62)</history></law>