<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. DUTIES OF PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00032' order_by='00032' level='4'>DIVISION 1. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-53</section_number>
<catch_line>Registration of all public utilities.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004161</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-53. Registration of all public utilities.<section>Every public utility, including public utilities owned and operated by municipalities, that on the effective date of this chapter is engaged in operating, constructing, or extending any water system or sewer system in Miami-Dade County, or a part thereof, shall register with the Metropolitan Water and Sewer Board by filing with the Board a written statement under oath setting forth the full legal name of the public utility, its principal place of business and its mailing address, together with a complete description of the service area which such public utility purports or claims to provide water or sewer services, or both, and such service area shall be accurately designated or depicted upon a map or sketch in such form, type or character as shall be prescribed, approved by or acceptable to the Board. Such public utilities shall register with the Board within ninety (90) days after the entire membership of the Board shall have been appointed and duly qualified to serve in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. The Board may extend the time for such registration for good cause shown. The Board shall give to every public utility so registered at least ten (10) days' written notice by mail of any public hearing required by this chapter. No public utility shall be entitled to receive notice of any public hearings under the provisions of this chapter until it has registered as required under this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-20, ยง 6, 7-5-60)</history></law>