<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. DUTIES OF PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00033' order_by='00033' level='4'>DIVISION 2. RATES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-66</section_number>
<catch_line>Jurisdiction over publicly owned and operated systems.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004226</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-66. Jurisdiction over publicly owned and operated systems.<section prefix='(1)'>Anything herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding, the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board shall have full power and jurisdiction to regulate the rates charged by all municipally owned or operated systems to any consumers not within the boundaries of said municipality and to other municipally or privately owned water or sewer utilities; provided, however, that the Board shall not have jurisdiction in respect to rates charged by municipally owned or operated utilities:<section prefix='(a)'>To consumers within the boundaries of that municipality, or</section><section prefix='(b)'>To customers being served by a municipally owned or operated system pursuant to an agreement with Miami-Dade County which by its terms either prescribes the rates to be charged or prescribes a method by which rates shall be established, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>To consumers not within the boundaries of said municipality so long as ninety (90) percent of the gross revenues generated by water and sewer rates are derived from consumers within the boundaries of said municipality and the rates are uniformly applied to consumers inside and outside the municipal boundaries.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Anything herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding, the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Water and Sewer Board shall have no jurisdiction whatever over the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority or Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Neither Miami-Dade County nor the Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority shall be required to pay any fees or charges imposed by the provisions of this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 60-30, § 1, 10-11-60; Ord. No. 62-28, § 7, 7-3-62; Ord. No. 64-23, § 8, 7-7-64; Ord. No. 70-60, § 2, 7-21-70; Ord. No. 72-94, § 3, 12-6-72; Ord. No. 75-28, § 16, 5-7-75; Ord. No. 75-68, § 1, 9-3-75; Ord. No. 76-62, § 2, 7-6-76; Ord. No. 79-41, § 2, 6-19-79; Ord. No. 83-101, § 1, 11-1-83; Ord. No. 85-17, § 1, 4-2-85)</history></law>