<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. DUTIES OF PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00033' order_by='00033' level='4'>DIVISION 2. RATES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-69</section_number>
<catch_line>Base facility charge criteria.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004229</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-69. Base facility charge criteria.<section prefix='(a)'>The monthly billing unit for the base facility charge (BFC) shall be the equivalent residential connection (ERC). An ERC shall be ten thousand (10,000) gallons or the utility may elect to use the actual average monthly consumption of all single-family customers as an ERC. If a utility elects to use a volume other than ten thousand (10,000) gallons as an ERC, that elected volume shall be used by that utility instead of the ten thousand-gallon monthly ERC in complying with this section.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Subsequent to the initial change to the ERC method of billing the base facility charge, the number of ERC billing units assigned to a customer shall be adjusted when the utility proposes a change in rates. The twelve-month period (test year) used in support of the rate change shall be used to determine an average single-family monthly usage ERC and a customer's maximum usage.</section><section prefix='(c)'>A different evaluation and adjustment period may be used to establish customers' billing units provided the revised customers' billing units do not result in an increase in total revenues.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The number of billing units assigned to each customer shall be obtained by dividing the maximum month's use of each customer billed monthly or the estimated maximum month's usage for customers billed quarterly (customer's maximum quarterly usage divided by the number of days usage in that billing period times thirty and four-tenths (30.4) days) by the volume of consumption considered an ERC for that utility.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The minimum monthly BFC to any customer shall not be for less than one-half of a billing unit. Monthly billing units for customers exceeding the one-half billing unit minimum shall be computed to the nearest one-tenth of a billing unit (ERC).</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-9, ยง 2, 2-7-84)</history></law>