<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00064' order_by='00064' level='2'>Chapter 32 WATER AND SEWER REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE IV. DUTIES OF PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00033' order_by='00033' level='4'>DIVISION 2. RATES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>32-71</section_number>
<catch_line>Fire hydrant service.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004231</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 32-71. Fire hydrant service.<section prefix='(a)'>The Board hereby approves the rates for fire hydrant service as follows:<section prefix='(1)'>For all Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department water customers located within the City of Miami and for all Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Authority Department water customers provided fire protection by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County whenever said customer is located within six hundred sixty (660) feet of a fire hydrant; forty cents ($0.40) per month.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For all Metro-Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Utility water customers provided fire protection by Metropolitan Miami-Dade County whenever said customer is located within six hundred sixty (660) feet of a fire hydrant: thirty-eight cents ($0.38) per month.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The rates for fire hydrant service set forth in subsection (a) shall cover the costs of fire hydrant water service, repairs, maintenance and installation. Said rates shall become effective for all billings based upon fire hydrant service provided on and after January 1, 1984; where fire hydrant service being billed encompasses periods both prior to January 1, 1984, and after, fire hydrant service prior to January 1, 1984, shall be determined by proration according to the number of days for which the old and new rates were in effect.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The fire hydrant service charges authorized herein shall be held and restricted in a separate group of accounts by the Department and by the Metro-Miami-Dade Water and Sewer Utility and funds collected as a result of said charges are to be used solely to reimburse Department costs for fire hydrant water service, repairs, maintenance and installation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 84-1, §§ 1—3, 1-17-84)</history></law>