<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00038' order_by='00038' level='4'>DIVISION 5. COMMERCIAL SIGNS ON EXPRESSWAY RIGHT-OF-WAY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-121.10</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004391</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-121.10. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>"Expressway" shall mean limited access rights-of-way and facilities and related approaches, viaducts, bridges and interchange facilities and service roads and any portion of the interstate highway system, now existing or as may be later constructed or designated.</section><section prefix='(b)'>"Applicable regulations" shall mean any pertinent zoning, building or other regulations in effect in the incorporated or unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County or the State of Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>"Protected areas" shall mean all property in Miami-Dade County within six hundred (600) feet of the right-of-way of any expressway right-of-way provided that directional signs and semaphore signs may be located on any portion of a shopping center which is approved as a development of regional impact pursuant to section 380.06, Florida Statutes, or which has received a binding letter of vested rights from the State of Florida issued prior to January 1, 1980, exempting it from development of regional impact review. Any such signs shall be subject to the requirements of Article VI of this Chapter, but the provisions of section 33-121.15 shall not apply.</section><section prefix='(d)'>"Sign" shall mean any display of characters, letters, illustrations or any ornamentation designed or used as an advertisement, announcement or to indicate direction.</section><section prefix='(e)'>"Erect" shall mean to construct, build, rebuild (if more than fifty (50) percent of the structural members involved), relocate raise, assemble, place, affix, attach, paint, draw, or in any other manner bring into being or establish.</section><section prefix='(f)'>"Temporary sign" shall mean signs to be erected on a temporary basis, such as signs advertising the sale or rental of the premises on which located; signs advertising a subdivision of property; signs advertising construction actually being done on premises on which the sign is located; signs advertising future construction to be done on the premises on which located and special events, such as public meetings, sporting events, political campaigns or events of a similar nature.</section><section prefix='(g)'>"Point of sale sign" shall mean any sign advertising or designating the use, occupant of the premises, or merchandise or products sold on the premises.</section><section prefix='(h)'>"Outdoor advertising sign" shall mean any sign which is used for any purpose other than that of advertising to the public the legal or exact firm name or type of business conducted on the premises, or of products or merchandise sold on the premises; or which is designed and displayed to offer for sale or rent the premises on which displayed, or the subdivision of such premises, or present or future construction or development of such premises, or advertising special events, shall constitute an outdoor advertising sign.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-26, ยง 1, 7-2-63; Ord. No. 83-53, ยง 1, 7-5-83; Ord. No. 85-36, ยง 1, 6-6-85; Ord. No. 00-32, ยง 1, 5-9-00)</history></law>