<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='3'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='4'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-121.14</section_number>
<catch_line>Nonconforming signs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004356</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>Signs which have been erected prior to the effective date of this division may continue to be maintained until March 1, 1968. Thereafter, unless such signs conform to the provisions of this division, they shall be removed: If a nonconforming spacing situation can be eliminated by the removal of one (1) sign, the sign which has been erected for the longest period of time shall have priority.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Any sign legally erected, permitted, or maintained subsequent to July 11, 1963, which is not in violation of this division but upon the opening for public use of an expressway or applicable portion thereof becomes nonconforming, the same may continue to be maintained for a period of five (5) years from the day of such opening provided on or before the expiration of the five (5) year period, the nonconforming sign must be removed; provided, any sign which is exempt from the provisions of this division pursuant to Subsection (d) of Section 33-121.13 hereof, but subsequently becomes nonconforming due to the elimination of the obstruction preventing its visibility from an expressway, must be removed within five (5) years from the time of the elimination of such obstruction; further provided, after the effective date of this amendment any sign erected, permitted or maintained after a future expressway right-of-way has been designated by the recording of an expressway right-of-way map in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, which becomes nonconforming due to the completion of such expressway shall be removed within thirty (30) days after such expressway or applicable portion thereof is opened for public use.</section><section prefix='(c)'>If approved as a result of a public hearing by the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board, a nonconforming sign may be replaced or modernized provided the board size and height is not increased.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 63-26, ยง 5, 7-2-63; Ord. No. 70-94, ยง 1, 12-15-70; Ord. No. 98-59, ยง 1, 5-5-98)</history></law>