<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00040' order_by='00040' level='4'>DIVISION 7. BUSWAY RIGHT-OF-WAY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-121.28</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004408</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-121.28. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Busway right of way map shall mean an official map designating outside boundaries for the Miami-Dade Transit Busway for Miami-Dade County, Florida, which shall be certified by the Clerk of the Board as the official busway zoning right-of-way map, and which shall be maintained on file in the records of the Department of Planning and Zoning. The busway zoning map may from time to time be altered, enlarged, amended or deleted by ordinance.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Applicable regulations shall mean any pertinent zoning or building ordinance or other legislation regulating the use of signs in the incorporated or unincorporated areas of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Busway protected areas shall mean all property in Miami-Dade County within three hundred (300) feet of the busway right-of-way.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Sign shall mean any display of characters, letters, illustrations or any ornamentation designed or used as an advertisement, announcement or to indicate direction.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Erect shall mean to construct, build, rebuild (if more than 50% of the support structure is involved), relocate, raise, assemble, place, affix, attach, paint, draw, or in any other manner bring into being or establish a sign.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 05-202, ยง 1, 11-3-05)</history></law>