<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00039' order_by='00039' level='4'>DIVISION 6. COMMERCIAL SIGNS ON RAPID TRANSIT SYSTEM RIGHT-OF-WAY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-121.24</section_number>
<catch_line>Nonconforming signs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004461</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-121.24. Nonconforming signs.<section prefix='(a)'>Signs which have been erected prior to the effective date of this division may continue to be maintained until January 1, 1984. Thereafter, unless such signs conform to the provisions of this division, they shall be removed. If a nonconforming spacing situation can be eliminated by the removal of one (1) sign, the sign which has been erected for the longest period of time shall have priority.</section><section prefix='(b)'>[If] any sign [be] legally erected, permitted or maintained subsequent to the effective date of this division, which is not in violation of this division but upon the opening for public use of a Rapid Transit System or applicable portion thereof becomes nonconforming, the same may continue to be maintained for a period of three (3) years from the day of such opening, provided on or before the expiration of the three-year period, the nonconforming sign must be removed; provided any sign which is exempt from the provisions of this division pursuant to (d) of Section 33-121.23 hereof, but subsequently becomes nonconforming due to the elimination of the obstruction preventing its visibility from a Rapid Transit System, must be removed within three (3) years from the time of the elimination of such obstruction; further provided, after the effective date of this amendment any sign erected, permitted or maintained after a future Rapid Transit System right-of-way has been designated by the recording of a Rapid Transit System right-of-way map in the public records of Miami-Dade County, Florida, which becomes nonconforming due to the completion of such Rapid Transit System shall be removed within thirty (30) days after such Rapid Transit System or applicable portion thereof is opened for public use.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-74, ยง 3, 10-17-78)</history></law>