<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00058' order_by='00058' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(J). NARANJA COMMUNITY URBAN CENTER DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.70</section_number>
<catch_line>Building Placement and Street Type Development Parameters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004871</order_by>
<text><section prefix='A.'>All new development and redevelopment within the NCUC shall comply with the Building Placement Standards as provided in Section 33-284.85 of this code. Outdoor produce markets in the Market District shall comply with the Building Placement Standards for Civic Uses in Section 33-284.85 of this code; all other development in the Market District shall comply with the Building Placement Standards for Mixed-Use, Multi-Family as provided in Section 33-284.85.</section><section prefix='B.'>All new development and redevelopment within the NCUC shall comply with the Streets, Service Roads and Utilities standards as provided in Section 33-284.86(C), except as provided herein:</section><section prefix='C.'>The following setbacks shall be required where a Building Placement Standard in Section 33-284.85 of this code refers to a Frontage Table:</section><section prefix='D.'>Street Types Development Parameters. U.S. 1</section><section></section><section>Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements.</section><section>Main Street</section><section></section><section>Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements.</section><section>Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated.</section><section>Busway Frontage</section><section></section><section>Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements.</section><section>Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated.</section><section>Footnotes:<section prefix='a.'>Landscape area is exclusive of the minimum sidewalk width.</section><section prefix='b.'>Street trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches at time of planting.</section><section prefix='c.'>Permanent irrigation is required.</section><section prefix='d.'>Tree grates shall have a minimum area of twenty-four (24) square feet; tree planters shall have a minimum area of thirty-two (32) square feet; continuous landscape strips shall have a minimum width of six (6) feet in the Center Sub-district, eight (8) feet in the Edge Sub-district.</section><section prefix='e.'>In all Sub-districts, curbs and gutters shall be provided at all intersections and roadway edges of arterials, boulevards and Main Street; in Core and Center Sub-districts, curbs and gutters shall be provided at all intersections and roadway edges of minor streets.</section><section prefix='g.'>Bike lanes shall be four (4) feet in width when adjacent to curb or swale; five (5) feet in width when adjacent to a parking lane.</section><section prefix='h.'>The minimum required width of one-lane/one-way travel lanes shall be determined by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management or its successor and Fire Rescue Department or its successor on a case-by-case basis during the Administrative Site Plan Review process (ASPR).</section><section prefix='i.'>The use of permeable materials to pave private street sidewalks, on-street parking, and vehicular drives is permitted. Use of permeable materials to pave public street sidewalks, on-street parking and vehicular drives shall require approval from the Director of the Department of Public Works and Waste Management.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-11, ยง 1, 1-24-06; Ord. No. 07-96, ยง 2, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 15-65, ยง 4, 7-14-15)</history></law>