<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00063' order_by='00063' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(O). OJUS URBAN AREA DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.19</section_number>
<catch_line>Building Placement and Street Type Development Parameters</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004861</order_by>
<text><section prefix='A.'>All new development and redevelopment within the OUAD shall comply with the Building Placement Standards as provided in Article XXXIII(K) of this code.</section><section prefix='B.'>All new development and redevelopment within the OUAD shall comply with the Streets, Service Roads and Utilities standards in Article XXXIII(K) of this code or as provided herein:</section><section prefix='C.'>The following setbacks shall be required where a Building Placement Standard in Article XXXIII(K) of this code refers to a Frontage Table:</section><section prefix='D.'>Street Types Development Parameters.</section><section></section><section></section><section>*  Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements.</section><section>**  Curb and gutter between the sidewalk and parking/travel lanes may be utilized in place of the valley gutter illustrated.</section><section></section><section></section><section>*  Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements.</section><section></section><section></section><section>* Refer to column B in Street Types Table for required landscape elements.<section>Footnotes:</section><section prefix='a.'>Landscape area is exclusive of the minimum sidewalk width.</section><section prefix='b.'>Street trees shall have a minimum caliper of six (6) inches at time of planting.</section><section prefix='c.'>Permanent irrigation is required.</section><section prefix='d.'>Tree grates shall have a minimum area of twenty-four (24) square feet; tree planters shall have a minimum area of thirty-two (32) square feet; continuous landscape strips shall have a minimum width of six (6) feet in the Core and Center Sub-districts, eight (8) feet in the Edge Sub-district.</section><section prefix='e.'>In all Sub-districts, curbs and gutters shall be provided at all intersections and roadway edges of arterials, boulevards and Main Street; in Core and Center Sub-districts, curbs and gutters shall be provided at all intersections and roadway edges of minor streets.</section><section prefix='g.'>Bike lanes shall be four (4) feet in width when adjacent to curb or swale; five (5) feet in width when adjacent to a parking lane.</section><section prefix='h.'>The minimum required width of one-lane/one-way travel lanes shall be determined by the Department of Public Works and Waste Management and Fire Rescue Department on a case-by-case basis during the Administrative Site Plan Review process (ASPR).</section></section><section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 06-86, § 6, 6-6-06; Ord. No. 07-94, § 4, 7-10-07; Ord. No. 14-14, § 3, 2-4-14)</history></law>