<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00048' order_by='00048' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII. AU, AGRICULTURAL DISTRICT</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-279.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Agricultural Uses Permitted in Areas Located Outside the Urban Development Boundary, Designated Agriculture on the Comprehensive Development Master Plan and Zoned EU, RU, BU or IU.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004677</order_by>
<text><section>Notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary in of this Code, the agricultural uses provided in this Section are permissible in areas zoned EU, RU, BU and IU that are designated Agriculture on the Comprehensive Development Master Plan Land Use Plan Map and that are located outside of the Urban Development Boundary.<section prefix='(a)'>For areas zoned EU and RU:<section prefix='(1)'>Agricultural uses provided in Section 33-279.1(b) of the Code are permitted, provided that:<section prefix='(a)'>The on-site sale of agricultural products is prohibited in properties zoned RU.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The on-site sale of agricultural products is permitted in properties zoned EU only when located on section-line roads.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>For areas zoned BU and IU:<section prefix='(1)'>Agricultural uses provided in Section 33-279 of the Code are permitted.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>For all properties subject to this Section:<section prefix='(1)'>The property shall conform to the minimum lot size and setback requirements of the underlying zoning district.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Agricultural uses on the property shall not be subject to the underlying zoning district's landscaping and lot coverage requirements.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A Zoning Improvement Permit shall be obtained prior to establishing any agricultural use.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-121, ยง 1, 12-3-13)</history></law>