<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(U). BIRD ROAD CORRIDOR URBAN AREA DISTRICT (BRCUAD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.71</section_number>
<catch_line>Development Parameters.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004915</order_by>
<text><section prefix='A.'>Except as otherwise provided in this section, all new development and redevelopment within the BRCUAD shall comply with the development parameters as set forth in Article XXXIII(K) of this chapter.</section><section prefix='B.'>All new development and redevelopment in areas designated MCS shall comply with the development parameters for the MC area as set forth in Article XXXIII(K) of this chapter.</section><section prefix='C.'>Except for State roads, streets within the BRCUAD shall comply at a minimum with the Street Type Parameters for Type 5, Minor Street, as provided in section 33-284.85.</section><section prefix='D.'>The front setback along Bird Road shall be hard surfaced and finished to match the adjoining sidewalk. A minimum of five (5) feet clear width within the setback shall be kept unobstructed for pedestrians. Trees shall be planted within the setback inside grates or planters along the front property line at a maximum of twenty-five (25) feet average on center, with a minimum six (6) inch diameter at breast height.</section><section prefix='E.'>Buffering between dissimilar land uses shall be in accordance with Section 18A-6(H) of this code.</section><section prefix='F.'>Where a proposed development abuts an area designated for single-family residential on the Future Land Use Map of the CDMP, the height of the proposed development along the abutting property line, for a minimum depth of 50 feet, shall be no greater than three stories. Examples of the required height transition are shown below.</section><section></section><section>Example of building heights transition from mixed-use to single-family</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-58, ยง 5, 6-4-13)</history></law>