<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00059' order_by='00059' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(K). STANDARD URBAN CENTER DISTRICT REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.89.3</section_number>
<catch_line>Amendments to Urban Center District Land Use Plan Category or Other Regulating Plan.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004777</order_by>
<text><section>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Code, for properties that have a zoning classification of urban center district, the following procedures shall govern (i) any amendment to an urban center district land use plan to change the land use category to which a specific property is designated; or (ii) any amendment to other urban center regulating plan as applicable to the particular property:<section prefix='(A)'>Application. The amendment process shall be initiated by filing with the Department an application, on forms prescribed by the Director.<section prefix='(i)'>The application form shall be executed and sworn to by the owner or owners of at least seventy-five (75) percent of the property described in the application, or by tenant or tenants, with owner's written sworn-to consent, or by duly authorized agents, evidenced by a written power of attorney, if not a member of the Florida Bar, or by the Director.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>All properties described in one application must be contiguous and immediately adjacent to one another, and the Director may require more than one application if the property concerned contains more than forty (40) acres, or the fee paid for one application would not equal the cost of processing the same.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>The amendment shall be presented as an ordinance amending the applicable urban center district regulations.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Notice.<section prefix='(i)'>Notice of the amendment ordinance shall be provided in accordance with the standard procedures for consideration of legislative ordinances.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>In addition, notice of the public hearing date on the amendment ordinance shall be provided in accordance with the requirements of Section 33-310 of this Code applicable to an application for district boundary change to an urban center district. The first reading of the ordinance shall not be subject to this additional notice requirement.</section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Hearings. The amendment ordinance shall be introduced on first reading at a regular meeting of the Board of County Commissioners. The ordinance shall thereafter be set for public hearing and second reading at a regular meeting of the Board of County Commissioners. The ordinance shall be considered as a quasi-judicial item and shall be accompanied by the written recommendation of the Director, prepared in accordance with Section 33-310 of this chapter. The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the procedures for direct zoning applications to the Board of County Commissioners, as set forth in Sections 33-314 and 33-311 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(D)'>Exhaustion of remedies; judicial review.<section prefix='(i)'>No person aggrieved by any zoning ordinance, resolution, order, requirement, decision, or determination of an administrative official or by any decision of the Board of County Commissioners may apply to the Court for relief unless such person has first exhausted the remedies provided for herein and taken all available steps provided in this section and complied with all other requirements concerning exhaustion of remedies and court review set forth in Section 33-316 of this chapter. Judicial review of any decision pursuant to this section shall be governed by the procedures set forth in Section 33-316 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Any person or entity claiming a particular action under this section constitutes or would constitute a temporary or permanent taking of private property or an abrogation of vested rights must affirmatively demonstrate the legal requisites of the claim by exhausting the administrative remedy provided in Section 2-114.1 of this code.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-119, ยง 1, 12-3-13)</history></law>