<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='3'>ARTICLE XXXIII(U). BIRD ROAD CORRIDOR URBAN AREA DISTRICT (BRCUAD)</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-284.99.67</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose, intent and applicability.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004966</order_by>
<text><section prefix='A.'>The BRCUAD is guided by the goals, objectives, policies and interpretative text of the Land Use Element of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='B.'>The regulations contained in this chapter and Chapter 18A, Landscape Code, Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall apply to this article, except as otherwise added to or modified herein.</section><section prefix='C.'>This Article applies primarily to the area fronting Bird Road (SW 40th Street) between the Palmetto Expressway and the Homestead Extension of the Florida Turnpike. Figure 1 shows the boundaries of the Bird Road Corridor Urban Area District (BRCUAD).</section><section prefix='D.'>The BRCUAD's Designated Urban Center shall consist of the areas designated as the Core and Center Sub-districts on the Sub-districts Plan in Sec. 33-284.99.69 of this article. As provided in the Standard Urban Center District Regulations, the Workforce Housing requirement shall apply to the area included in the Designated Urban Center boundaries. The legal description of the boundaries of the BRCUAD is on file with the Development Services Division of the Miami-Dade County Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources.</section><section prefix='E.'>Full scale maps of the boundaries presented in Figure 1, as well as all the Regulating Plans and Street Development Parameters figures in this article, are on file with the Development Services Division of the Miami-Dade County Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources.</section><section prefix='F.'>No provision in this article shall be applicable to any property lying outside the boundaries of the BRCUAD as described herein. No property lying within the boundaries of the BRCUAD shall be entitled to the uses or subject to the regulations provided in this article until an application for a district boundary change to BRCUAD has been heard and approved in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</section><section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 13-58, ยง 1, 6-4-13)</history></law>