<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00034' order_by='00034' level='4'>DIVISION 1. TITLE, APPLICABILITY, PURPOSE AND DEFINITIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-83</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004302</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-83. Purpose.<section prefix='(a)'>The purpose of this chapter [article] is to permit signs that will not, because of size, location, method of construction and installation, or manner of display:<section prefix='(1)'>Endanger the public safety; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>Create distractions that may jeopardize pedestrian or vehicular traffic safety; or</section><section prefix='(3)'>Mislead, confuse, or obstruct the vision of people seeking to locate or identify uses or premises; or</section><section prefix='(4)'>Destroy or impair aesthetic or visual qualities of Miami-Dade County which is so essential to tourism and the general welfare; and</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The purpose of this article is also to permit, regulate and encourage the use of signs with a scale, graphic character, and type of lighting compatible with buildings and uses in the area, so as to support and complement land use objectives as set forth in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The purpose of this article is also to protect noncommercial speech such that any sign authorized herein may contain, in lieu of any other message or copy, any lawful noncommercial message, so long as such sign complies with the size, height, area and other requirements of this article.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-59, ยง 2, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 07-61, ยง 1, 4-26-07)</history></law>