<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='4'>DIVISION 2. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-86</section_number>
<catch_line>Permits required.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004417</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-86. Permits required.<section prefix='(a)'>Applications and permits. No sign, unless excepted by this article, shall be erected, constructed, posted, painted, altered, maintained, or relocated, except as provided in this article and until a permit has been issued by the Department. Before any permit is issued, an application for such permit shall be filed together with three (3) sets of drawings and/or specifications (one (1) to be returned to the applicant) as may be necessary to fully advise and acquaint the issuing department with the location, method of construction, type of materials, manner of illumination, method of erection, securing or fastening, number and type of signs applied for, and advertisement to be carried. All signs which are electrically illuminated by neon or any other means shall require a separate electric permit and inspection.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Consent of property owner. No sign shall be placed on any property unless the applicant has the written consent of the owner and lessee, if any, of the property.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Calculating number of signs. A single sign containing advertisement on each side shall be counted as one (1) sign. Every other sign shall be counted as a separate sign for each face thereof. Excepting class C signs, "V" type signs will be considered as one (1) sign if the spread of the "V" at the open end is not greater than the length of its narrowest side.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Calculating sign size. The area of a sign shall include borders and framing. Heights shall be measured to the top extremity of the sign and distances to the farthest point. The square footage in a circular rotating or revolving sign shall be determined by multiplying one-half (½) of the circumference by the height of the rotating sign, except in the case of the flat rotating sign, the area will be determined by the square footage of one (1) side of such sign. The Director shall have the discretion of determining the area of any sign which is irregular in shape, and in such cases will be guided by calculations as made by a licensed, registered engineer when same are shown on the drawing.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Review of the application. The Department shall complete its review of a sign permit application for the unincorporated area within 30 calendar days after filing, and shall render a decision either for approval or denial within that time. Failure by the Department to render a decision within 30 calendar days shall be deemed a denial, appealable as provided herein. If the permit is denied based upon grounds set forth in this article, the applicant may file an appeal to the appropriate Community Zoning Appeals Board. Such appeal shall be heard at the next regular meeting of such board after notice pursuant to the requirements of Section 33-310(c) of this code. Further appeal shall be as authorized pursuant to the Florida rules of court. It is provided that the procedures for the review of a sign permit application pursuant to this section shall be limited to the Department of Planning and Zoning and shall not apply to other county departments' review of a sign permit application pursuant to the Florida Building Code.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Restrictions on Certain Class C Sign Permits.<section prefix='(1)'>No permit shall be issued for a mural on property where a civil violation notice pursuant to Chapter 8CC of this code has been issued for an unauthorized mural until such civil violation notice has been resolved.</section><section prefix='(2)'>No permit shall be issued for a mural to an erector or affiliate of such erector who has been issued a civil violation notice pursuant to Chapter 8CC of this code for erecting an unauthorized mural until such civil violation notice has been resolved.</section><section prefix='(3)'>No permit shall be issued to a property owner or owner of a mural or affiliate thereof who has been issued a civil violation notice pursuant to Chapter 8CC of this code for erecting an unauthorized mural, until such civil violation notice has been resolved.</section><section prefix='(4)'>No permit shall be issued for an existing mural in violation of this article if authorization for such mural was obtained from a municipality.</section><section prefix='(5)'>No permit for a mural shall be issued to an owner, erector or affiliate thereof, if such owner, erector or affiliate has an existing agreement with a municipality purporting to allow the establishment or continuation of a mural upon payment of fines, penalties or other payments to the municipality, if such mural is not in compliance with the requirements of this article.</section><section prefix='(6)'>For purposes of this subsection, the term "affiliate" shall mean (i) a person, corporation, partnership or other business organization ("entity"), directly controlling, controlled by, or under common control with, another entity, or (ii) any entity owning or controlling ten percent or more of the ownership interest of another entity.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-59, § 2, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 07-61, § 4, 4-26-07)</history></law>