<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='4'>DIVISION 2. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-95</section_number>
<catch_line>Prohibited signs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004314</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-95. Prohibited signs.<section prefix='(a)'>No sign shall be so located as to constitute a danger to public safety.</section><section prefix='(b)'>No sign shall exhibit thereon any lewd or lascivious matter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No sign shall be attached to trees, utility poles or any other unapproved supporting structure.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Roof signs are prohibited in all the districts.</section><section prefix='(e)'>No signs shall be erected or painted on fence and wall enclosures in residential districts. Fence and wall signs shall be prohibited in the residential districts. These restrictions do not apply to Class B signs in the AU district.</section><section prefix='(f)'>In both the incorporated and unincorporated areas of the County even if not classified as a sign, blinking or flashing lights, streamer lights, pennants, banners, streamers, and all fluttering, spinning or other type of attention attractors or advertising devices are prohibited except for national flags, flags of bona fide civic, charitable, fraternal and welfare organizations and further except during recognized holiday periods such attention-attractors that pertain to such holiday periods may be displayed on a temporary basis during such periods. The flags permitted by this subsection shall not be used in mass in order to circumvent this subsection by using said flags primarily as an advertising device.</section><section prefix='(g)'>No revolving or rotating sign shall be permitted or erected except as a class B (point of sale) sign in the BU and IU Districts. Such signs shall be illuminated by internal lighting only.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Any signs which are not traffic signs as defined in Section 33-94(b) which use the word "stop" or "danger" or present or imply the need or requirement of stopping, or which are copies or imitations of official signs. Red, green or amber (or any color combination thereof) revolving or flashing light giving the impression of a police or caution light is a prohibited sign, whether on a sign or on an independent structure.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Unless specifically permitted by this chapter or other law, portable signs shall be prohibited, including those that are tied down with metal straps, chaining, or otherwise temporarily anchored to an existing structure or other similar method of anchoring.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Signs painted or affixed in any manner to any vehicle, trailer or pickup truck, van or similar transportable device and which is used to advertise a place of business or activity as viewed from a public road shall be prohibited. This shall not be interpreted to prohibit identification of commercial vehicles provided such vehicles are operational and moved and used daily for delivery or service purposes and are not used, or intended for use, as portable signs. This sign shall also not be interpreted to apply to buses, taxicabs, and similar common carrier vehicles which are licensed or certified by Miami-Dade County or other governmental agency.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-59, ยง 2, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 10-90, ยง 1, 12-7-10)</history></law>