<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='3'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00008' order_by='00008' level='4'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-96.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Automatic electric changing signs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004332</order_by>
<text><section>Subject to the following mandatory conditions, Automatic Electric Changing Signs ("ACS"), shall be permitted in BU and IU districts, seaports, airports, sports stadiums, racetracks, and other similar uses as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>This provision shall apply to Class B (Point of Sale) signs only.</section><section prefix='(b)'>An ACS shall conform to all sign size, placement, setback, and quantity limitations as provided elsewhere in this chapter and shall comply with all building code requirements.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Incandescent lamps/bulbs in excess of 9 watts are prohibited in an ACS. Incandescent lamps/bulbs in an ACS shall not be exposed but shall be covered by a translucent lenses or filters.</section><section prefix='(d)'>An ACS shall be equipped with an automatic operational night dimming device.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The following operating modes are prohibited:<section prefix='(1)'>Flash — the condition created by displaying the same message intermittently by turning it on and off, on and off, with rapidity, or any other delivery mode that creates a flashing effect.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Zoom — the look or condition created by expanding a message from a central point to its full size.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Any signs which use the word "stop" or "danger" or imply the need or requirement of stopping, or which are copies or imitations of official signs.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Red, green or amber (or any color combination thereof) revolving or flashing light giving the impression of a police or caution light shall be prohibited.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>A minimum of ten (10) acres gross improved land area shall be required for the placement of an ACS.</section><section prefix='(g)'>With the exception of airports or seaports, the subject ACS shall be located only on a major or minor roadway as depicted on the adopted Comprehensive Development Master Plan Land Use Plan map.</section><section prefix='(h)'>A detached ACS shall be surrounded by a minimum of twenty-five (25) square feet of landscaped area. A plan indicating such landscape area shall be submitted to the Director at the time of building permit application.</section><section prefix='(i)'>The content of the ACS shall be limited solely to the promotion of products or services offered on the premises. The only fixed message shall be the name of the company possessing a valid Certificate of Use and Occupancy for the subject premises.</section><section prefix='(j)'>The applicant for an ACS shall file of record a declaration of use, on a form prescribed and approved by the Director, which will govern the operation of the ACS and contain penalties for abatement and removal of the ACS for violations of the declaration of use and the provisions herein.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 94-99, § 2, 5-17-94; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95)</history></law>