<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='4'>DIVISION 2. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-97</section_number>
<catch_line>Maintenance of signs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004317</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-97. Maintenance of signs.<section prefix='(a)'>[Required.] All signs shall be properly maintained in a safe and legible condition at all times. In the event that a use having a sign is discontinued for a period of forty-five (45) days, all signs identifying the use are to be removed from the site or in the case of a painted sign, painted out. Sign removal shall be the responsibility of the owner of the property.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Latticework, painting, etc. Where the rear of any sign is visible from a street, waterway, park or residence, or from a EU, RU, or BU District, the exposed structural members of such sign shall be either concealed by painted latticework, slats or be suitably painted or decorated, and such back screening shall be designed, painted and maintained to the satisfaction of the Director.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Cutting weeds. The owner of each sign not attached to a building shall be responsible for keeping the weeds cut on his property within a radius of fifty (50) feet or to the nearest highway or waterway.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Removal of dilapidated signs. The Director may cause to be removed any sign which shows neglect or becomes dilapidated or where the area around such sign is not maintained as provided herein after due notice has been given. The owner of the sign and/or the property shall be financially responsible for the removal of the sign.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-59, ยง 2, 7-18-85)</history></law>