<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00067' order_by='00067' level='2'>Chapter 33 ZONING</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='3'>ARTICLE VI. SIGNS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00035' order_by='00035' level='4'>DIVISION 2. GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33-94</section_number>
<catch_line>Signs permitted without a sign permit.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000004368</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33-94. Signs permitted without a sign permit.<section prefix='(a)'>Class A temporary signs not exceeding six (6) square feet in area, not electrically illuminated will not require a sign permit, but must otherwise comply with this article and applicable technical codes.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Traffic signs, provisional warnings and signs indicating danger, are exempt from this chapter. Such exempted signs shall not contain any commercial advertisement.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Awning, canopy, roller curtain, or umbrella sign or signs shall be limited to eight-inch letters in height, and shall not exceed a total coverage of twenty-four (24) square feet. Any such sign shall be limited to the identification of the occupant and/or use of the property. No sign permit shall be required for the awning, canopy, roller curtain or umbrella sign, but the same shall comply with applicable technical codes.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Disabled or handicapped parking signs. Signs required by State law or County ordinance for parking spaces reserved for disabled or handicapped persons shall not require a sign permit.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Signs not exceeding one and one-half (1½) square feet in area and bearing only property street numbers, post box numbers, or name of occupant of premises.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Flags and insignia of any government, except when displayed in connection with commercial promotion.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Legal notices, identification, information, or directional signs erected by or on behalf of governmental bodies.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Integral decorative and architectural features of buildings except letters, logos, trademarks, moving parts or moving lights.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Signs within enclosed buildings or structures which are so located that they are not visible from public or private streets or adjacent properties such as signs in interior areas of malls, commercial buildings, ball parks, stadiums and similar structures or uses, providing said signs are erected in such a manner as not to be hazardous. If illuminated, the necessary electrical permits shall be obtained.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Temporary holiday decorations provided said decorations carry no advertising matter and further provided that such decoration is not up more than sixty (60) days for a single holiday and is removed within seven (7) days after the holiday ends.</section><section prefix='(k)'>"Danger," "No Parking," "Post No Bills," "Bad Dog," and similar warning signs, provided such signs do not exceed an area of one (1) and one-half (1.5) square feet.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Banners and other decorative materials in conjunction with an event conducted pursuant to a dedication or a grand opening, are permitted without a sign permit. Such banners and decorative materials are not to be posted more than thirty (30) days preceding the event, and are to be removed within seven (7) days following the grand opening day of the event.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Signs required by law.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Signs which are incorporated within bus passenger benches and shelters in compliance with Sections 33-121.14 and 33-121.17(b).</section><section prefix='(o)'>Baby stroller parking signs. Signs required for parking spaces reserved for persons transporting young children and strollers shall not require a sign permit.</section><section prefix='(p)'>"No Trespassing" signs, provided such signs do not exceed an area of three (3) square feet.</section><section prefix='(q)'>The Director of the Miami-Dade County Park and Recreation Department, or designee, shall be permitted to post banners promoting park activities, special events and sponsorships relating to same, provided (i) such banners are posted on the Miami-Dade County park property where the activity or special event will occur; (ii) that each banner shall be limited in size to no more than thirty (30) square feet; (iii) that the banner shall not be posted more than sixty (60) days preceding the activity or event and shall be removed within seven (7) days following the activity or event. Banners complying with the conditions specified in this subsection shall be permitted without a sign permit.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 85-59, § 2, 7-18-85; Ord. No. 90-24, § 1, 3-20-90; Ord. No. 96-161, § 1, 11-12-96; Ord. No. 96-162, § 1, 11-12-96; Ord. No. 06-35, § 1, 3-7-06)</history></law>