<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='4'>DIVISION 2. OVERLAY ZONING REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-26</section_number>
<catch_line>Environmental performance standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005027</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-26. Environmental performance standards.<section>All development in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall comply with the standards listed below. The cumulative and/or secondary/induced impacts of the proposed development shall be considered in determining whether the development meets the environmental performance standards of this section.</section><section prefix='(a)'>Fill:<section prefix='(1)'>The placement of fill including the construction of roadways shall not impede the rate or volume of surface water flow or create significant backwater conditions.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The area of fill shall not exceed the following limitations:<section prefix='a.'>In Management Areas 1 and 3B—One-half acre; and</section><section prefix='b.'>In Management Areas 2A, 2B, 3A and 3C—The minimum area necessary to install an on-site waste water treatment system, not to exceed one-half acre.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Excavation: No excavation shall be carried out in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern, except:<section prefix='(1)'>Discontinuous shallow ditching for agricultural purposes shall be permitted; however, it shall not serve as a continuous conduit for transporting water to the extent that it has a significant adverse effect on the natural hydrologic regimen of the immediate vicinity of the parcel proposed for development.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Excavation of shallow lakes for recreation and/or fill for uses permitted under this division shall be evaluated on a case-by-case basis, and all such lakes shall meet all applicable Miami-Dade County criteria for lakes.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Roads:<section prefix='(1)'>No roads shall be permitted in Management Areas 2A and 2B.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Where permitted, roads in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern must be designed so that they will not interrupt or divert natural sheet flow. Elevated roads must be sufficiently bridged and culverted to allow the passage of high water flows without causing significant backwater conditions. The Miami-Dade County Public Works Manual on road design, as amended from time to time, is incorporated herein by reference. No roads shall be permitted in Management Areas 2A and 2B.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Clearing of native vegetation: Tree islands characterized by native vegetation shall be preserved in all management areas, including agricultural areas. Residential and hunting camp uses on tree islands shall be permitted only if the tree island canopy is preserved intact and the proposed use will not have a significant adverse impact on the wildlife habitat value of the island.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Landscaping: Species to be used in ornamental planting shall not include noxious exotic plants. All ornamental planting shall be subject to the approval of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Solid waste disposal: No solid waste not degradable by approved on-site systems shall be disposed of or deposited in the area of critical environmental concern.</section></section><section prefix='(g)'>Agriculture:<section prefix='(1)'>Agricultural activities shall be managed so that exotic plants will not become established, maintained or propagated. All practicable methods of control, subject to County approval, which do not significantly degrade the environment shall be employed. Affirmative steps shall be taken to eliminate the noxious exotic species defined herein.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any agricultural practice which reduces infiltration rate from that of natural (or present) conditions shall be compensated for by an on-site retention technique (e.g., ditch, depression). The design of such facilities shall ensure that collected water will percolate into the groundwater system and that no net change in infiltration rate or volume occurs.</section><section prefix='(3)'>After completing rock plowing and regrading activity, elevated planting beds shall not inhibit surface water sheet flow.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Farm roads built above grade must meet Public Works Manual criteria with regard to the passage of flood flows and sheet flow.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Construction of structures ancillary to agricultural use such as equipment storage sheds should be located and designed so that they minimize the impact on surface water flow.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 6, 10-27-81)</history></law>