<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='4'>DIVISION 2. OVERLAY ZONING REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-24</section_number>
<catch_line>Applicability of division to development; disclaimer statement.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005080</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-24. Applicability of division to development; disclaimer statement.<section prefix='(a)'>All development in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall comply with each and every provision of this division.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The requirements of this division shall be in addition to each and every other requirement of the rules, regulations and ordinances of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, and in the case of conflict, the provisions of this division shall control.</section><section prefix='(c)'>No permit for use or development of any land within the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall be issued by any agent of Miami-Dade County government which permit does not contain the following statement:<section>The subject parcel is located in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern and is subject to seasonal flooding. Neither Miami-Dade County nor the South Florida Water Management District plans to construct flood protection works which would benefit the subject parcel. Moreover, neither Miami-Dade County nor the Water Management District will allow the owner (or permittee) to use public canal systems to provide drainage that is not now available to the subject parcel. In addition, it is against county policy either to provide new roads or to maintain and/or improve privately built roads in this area.</section><section>I hereby certify that I have read and understand the foregoing statement.</section></section><section>The foregoing statement is to be included in all permits as a courtesy to owners, and failure to include such statement in any permit shall not be construed as a waiver of any other provision of this division.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-121, ยง 4, 10-27-81)</history></law>