<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='4'>DIVISION 3. SEVERABLE USE RIGHTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-43</section_number>
<catch_line>Severable use rights established.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005148</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-43. Severable use rights established.<section prefix='(a)'>The owners of unimproved land located in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall have severable use rights in the amount set out in subsections (b), (c) and (d) of this section. The severable use rights allocated in this section may be used to obtain a development bonus in accordance with the provisions of this division for the development of suitable land in unincorporated Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, other than land located in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Severable use rights are hereby established in the following ratios:<section prefix='(1)'>In Management Area 1 as established in the ordinance declaring the East Everglades to be an area of critical environmental concern—One (1) severable use right per five (5) gross acres;</section><section prefix='(2)'>In Management Area 3B as established in the ordinance declaring the East Everglades to be an area of critical environmental concern—One (1) severable use right per twelve (12) gross acres;</section><section prefix='(3)'>In Management Area 3C as established in the ordinance declaring the East Everglades to be an area of critical environmental concern—One (1) severable use right per forty (40) gross acres.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding the allocation of severable use rights in subsection (b) of this section, the owners of parcels of land in Management Areas 1, 3B and 3C, that were legally entitled to a density of one (1) dwelling unit as of January 14, 1981, under the provisions of Chapter 33 of the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code, but have less than the acreage specified in subsection (b) for a whole SUR, shall be entitled to an allocation of a single severable use right provided that:<section prefix='(1)'>The subject parcel of land was not in common ownership with any adjacent parcel of land on, or after, January 14, 1981; and</section><section prefix='(2)'>The subject parcel of land is registered with the Department of Planning and Zoning of Miami-Dade County within one (1) year of the effective date of this division, provided that at the time of registration the applicant can demonstrate that he or she was entitled to develop a single dwelling unit under the rules, regulations and ordinances of Miami-Dade County that were in effect on January 14, 1981.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>In the event that the owners of parcels of land fail to register for the severable use right provided for in subsection (c) of this section, they shall only be entitled to a fractional severable use right at the ratio specified in subsection (b) of this section. For example, in Management Area 1:<section prefix='(1)'>A tract of two and five-tenths (2.5) acres shall have five-tenths (0.5) SUR,</section><section prefix='(2)'>A tract of seven (7) acres shall have one (1) SUR,</section><section prefix='(3)'>A tract of twelve (12) acres shall have two (2) SUR.</section></section><section prefix='(e)'>The Director of the Department of Planning and Zoning of Miami-Dade County shall have the authority to establish a fee schedule following a public hearing, to establish other administrative items necessary to implement the intent of this division.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-122, § 3, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 23, 9-3-98)</history></law>