<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='4'>DIVISION 2. OVERLAY ZONING REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-30</section_number>
<catch_line>Management areas.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005031</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-30. Management areas.<section prefix='(A)'>Criteria:<section prefix='(1)'>Management Area 1: Management Area 1 is defined as that land in the East Everglades area of Miami-Dade County which is adjacent to Levee L-31-N and Canal C-111 and has been directly and permanently altered by human activity as of January 14, 1981. Management Area 1 includes Sections 11, 14, 15, 21, 22, 23, 27, 28; the east one-half of Section 16; all land in Section 26 which lies northerly and westerly of Levee L-31-N; the east one-half of the northeast one-quarter (¼) and the east one-half of the southeast one-quarter of Section 29; all within Township 55 South and Range 38 East; and all land adjacent to Levee L-31-N or Canal C-111, and south of Southwest 168th Street which has been directly and permanently altered by human activity as of January 14, 1981. An official map of Management Area 1 will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Management Area 2: Management Area 2 is defined as that land within the East Everglades area of Miami-Dade County which is flooded (i.e., water level within one (1) foot of the land surface) for at least nine (9) months of the year in a year with average rainfall. (The boundary is determined by comparing the duration and elevation of water levels to the elevation of the land using the most complete water records available.) An official map of Management Area 2 will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Management Area 3: Management Area 3 is defined as that land within the East Everglades area of Miami-Dade County described below as Management Areas 3A, 3B and 3C;<section>Management Area 3A is all land in the East Everglades which meets at least one (1) of the following three (3) criteria:</section><section prefix='(a)'>Has vegetation characterized by tree island and/or wet prairie communities; that is, the community mosaics characterized by (in order of abundance) sawgrass glades, spike rush-beak rush, and maidencane flats; by spike rush-beak rush, sawgrass glades and maidencane flats; and by the post-burn recovery vegetation of former bayhead, former cypress dome or hammock communities, and prairietree island communities, including narrow beard grass, three-awn grass, love grass prairies and wax myrtle-saltbush thickets, as depicted on the vegetation maps prepared as a part of the East Everglades Resources Planning Project.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Is flooded from three (3) to nine (9) months during a year when average rainfall occurs. (This boundary is calculated by the same method as that described above for Management Area 2.)</section><section prefix='(c)'>Is flooded for less than three (3) months during a year when average rainfall occurs (calculated as described above), but is not contiguous with Management Area 1.<section>Management Area 3B is all land that is contiguous with Management Area 1 and is flooded less than three (3) months during a year in which average rainfall occurs.</section><section>Management Area 3C is all of the remaining land in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern that is not within Management Areas 1, 2, 3A or 3B.</section><section>An official map of Management Areas 3A, 3B and 3C will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.</section></section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Determination of management area boundaries: A person may file a request for a determination of management area boundaries with respect to a given parcel of land. Such request must be in writing and addressed to the Director of the Miami-Dade County Department of Environmental Resources Management (DERM). The Director of DERM shall respond in a timely manner and shall specify why the parcel is in the assigned management area.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Revision of management area boundaries:<section prefix='(1)'>Revisions to the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" may be made by the Department of Environmental Resources Management from time to time as more scientific information becomes available. Any revisions to the boundaries of the Management Areas should be based entirely on the criteria listed in part (A) of this section.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Any individual may submit an application to revise the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" to the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management. Such application shall be in such form and contain sufficient information and documentation to allow an evaluation by the Department of Environmental Resources Management with respect to the criteria described in part (A) of this section.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Revision of the Management Area map boundary shall be by public hearing by the Board of County Commissioners in the manner specified below in subsection (D).</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Review of application:<section prefix='(1)'>Within fifteen (15) days after an application to revise the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" is submitted, the Director of Environmental Resources Management shall determine whether the application is complete. If the application is determined to be incomplete, a written statement specifying the deficiencies shall be sent to the applicant and no further action shall be taken on the application until the deficiencies are remedied.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Within forty-five (45) days after receipt of a complete application, the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management shall review the application to revise the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" and shall decide whether the proposed revision should be issued or denied and the grounds for such decision. Such review and decision shall be based on the comments and recommendations of all other relevant County departments and a determination of whether the applicant has demonstrated compliance with the criteria set forth in part (A) of this section.</section><section prefix='(3)'>An applicant for revision to the map of "Management Areas of the East Everglades" under the provisions of this section may appeal the decision of the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management to the Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Notice of appeal shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission within fifteen (15) days.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Upon receipt of a notice of appeal, the Clerk of the Commission shall place the application on the agenda of the next regular meeting of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(6)'>The Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County shall review the application, the decision of the Director of the Department of Environmental Resources Management and any additional information which may be submitted. The Commissioners may affirm, reverse or modify the decision of the Department of Environmental Resources Management. Such affirmance, reversal or modification shall be based on the extent to which the applicant has demonstrated compliance with the criteria set forth in part (A) of this section.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 10, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 23, 9-3-98)</history></law>