<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='3'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='4'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-14</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005018</order_by>
<text><section>For the purpose of this article, the following terms shall have the following meanings. When not inconsistent with the context, words used in the present tense include the future, words in the plural number include the singular, and words in the singular include the plural. The word "shall" is always mandatory and not merely directory.<section prefix='(a)'>Area (or critical area) means the area of critical environmental concern as described in Section 33B-13</section><section prefix='(b)'>Area of critical environmental concern means an area where the environment and natural resources are highly susceptible to degradation to the detriment of the public health, safety and welfare unless its alteration or development is in accordance with the purposes of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Development means the carrying out of any use permitted on land by applicable zoning regulations (i.e., Chapter 33 of the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code) or making any material change in the use or character of land, including, but not limited to, the placement of structures on land; the clearing of land or a change in the intensity of use of land. Development shall include the ancillary activities such as road building and sewer construction that occur along with or as a result of any proposed land use. When appropriate to the context, development refers to the act of developing or the result of development.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Ecosystems means the complex of a community of organisms and its physical environment.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Flooding denotes a condition in which water is at or above a point which is one (1) foot below the average elevation of a specific land area.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Groundwater means water beneath the surface of the earth, but above the base of the Biscayne Aquifer, whether or not flowing through known or definite channels.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Hydroperiod means that portion of the annual hydrological cycle during which water is at or on the soil surface. In estuaries, the hydroperiod is the annual period during which surface runoff from the land measurably dilutes seawater.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Impound means to create or cause to be created any lake, reservoir, pond or other containment of surface waters occupying a bed or depression in the earth's surface and having a discernible shoreline.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Land means earth, water and air above, below or on the surface.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Natural flow regime means the velocity, volume and direction of the surface or ground water flow occurring at any given point in the current hydroperiod for any given portion of the area.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Natural vegetation means vegetation indigenous to a site.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Impermeable or impervious surface means site area covered by nonporous structural materials such as pavement, roofing, decking or structure foundations or supports.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Periodicity means the characteristic frequency and duration of overland flow of surface water resulting from a given meteorologic or hydrologic event.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Person means any and all persons, including, but not limited to, an individual, firm, association, organization, partnership, business trust, trust, corporation or company.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Surface runoff means overland flow of waters.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Surface waters means any water upon the surface of the earth, whether contained in bounds created naturally or artificially, or diffused. Water from natural springs shall be classified as surface water when it exists from the spring onto the earth's surface. Natural flow of surface water shall mean the unaltered movement or drainage of water upon the surface of the earth, whether standing or flowing. It is not essential that the flowing be uniform or uninterrupted, and the flowing, or existence of water on the surface of the land, may be seasonable or periodic.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Water quality means the physical, chemical and biological characteristics of water together with the physical, chemical and biological characteristics of water that affect the propagation of fish, wildlife and aquatic plants and animals.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Water quantity means the amount of water present at any location as indicated by its surface elevation, depth, velocity and direction of flow.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Works means any artificial or natural barrier raised to obstruct, divert, impound or interfere or which does obstruct, divert, interfere or impound either continuously, periodically or seasonally, any of the surface waters in Metropolitan Miami-Dade County which shall include but not be limited to ditches, canals, conduits, channels, culverts, pipes, and other construction that connects to, draws water from, drains water into, or is placed in or across the surface waters of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, but shall not include walls.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Wetlands means any swamp, marsh, bog, or other land area that is partially or periodically inundated with water and characterized by indigenous biota adapted to and dependent upon partial or periodic inundation.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-1, ยง 4, 1-15-81)</history></law>