<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00043' order_by='00043' level='4'>DIVISION 3. SEVERABLE USE RIGHTS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-41</section_number>
<catch_line>Purpose.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005091</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-41. Purpose.<section>In order to protect, enhance and preserve the public and private resources of the East Everglades and to achieve the goals of East Everglades Resources Planning Project, it is necessary and appropriate to create a system of land management and development regulations that will provide the owners of land located within the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern a development alternative to on-site development whereby they can secure a beneficial use of their property through off-site development without the expense and cumulative environmental degradation of on-site development. If the environmental integrity of the East Everglades and the surface and ground water resources it represents can be protected, then the capacity of Miami-Dade County as a whole to sustain and support new growth and development is maintained. This division is intended to facilitate the protection of the East Everglades resources and thereby permit growth and development in the County through a management program that ensures an equitable distribution, throughout the County, of the economic impacts and burdens of protecting the public and private resources of the East Everglades. The board hereby incorporates by reference Miami-Dade County Ordinance 81-1 [Division 1 of Article II of this chapter].</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-122, ยง 1, 10-27-81)</history></law>