<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='4'>DIVISION 2. OVERLAY ZONING REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-25</section_number>
<catch_line>Authorized uses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005081</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-25. Authorized uses.<section prefix='(A)'>Management Area 1:<section prefix='(1)'>Permitted uses:<section prefix='(a)'>Agricultural use, and</section><section prefix='(b)'>Agricultural support housing at a density of no greater than one (1) unit per forty (4) acres, or</section><section prefix='(c)'>Single-family detached dwelling units at a density of no greater than one (1) unit per forty (40) acres.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Conditional uses:<section prefix='(a)'>Single-family detached dwelling units at a density of no greater than one (1) unit per five (5) acres in that portion of Management Area 1 which had an established residential character as of January 14, 1981, provided that positive drainage flood control facilities are available to protect the area from a one-in-ten-year flood event. This area is defined as all of Sections 14, 21, 22, 23, 27, 28; the south one-half of Section 11 and the south one-half of the north one-half of Section 11; the east one-half of Section 15; the east one-half of Section 16; all land in Section 26 which lies northerly and westerly of Levee L-31-N; the east one-half of the east one-half of Section 29; all within Township 55 South and Range 38 East.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Residential dwelling units at a density of no greater than one (1) dwelling unit per twenty (20) acres, provided that:<section prefix='1.'>The dwelling unit is ancillary to an established agricultural operation involving less than forty (40) acres, and</section><section prefix='2.'>Occupancy of the dwelling is limited to the owner, operator or employees of the established agricultural operation, and</section><section prefix='3.'>The parcel was not in common ownership with any adjacent parcel of land on or after January 14, 1981.</section></section></section></section><section prefix='(B)'>Management Area 2:<section prefix='(1)'>Permitted uses:<section prefix='(a)'>Residential dwellings at a density of no greater than one (1) unit per forty (40) acres.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Passive recreation and conservation and traditional ORV and airboat use.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Conditional uses:<section prefix='(a)'>One (1) residential dwelling unit on parcels of less than forty (40) acres provided that:<section prefix='1.'>The parcel proposed for development was entitled to a density of at least one (1) dwelling unit as of January 14, 1981, under the provisions of Chapter 33 of the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code; and</section><section prefix='2.'>The parcel proposed for development has at least two hundred (200) feet of frontage on U.S. Highway 41 (Tamiami Trail) or on U.S. Highway 1; and</section><section prefix='3.'>The parcel proposed for development is at least five (5) acres in size and was not in common ownership with any adjacent parcel of land on or after January 14, 1981; and</section><section prefix='4.'>The only filling allowed on the parcel proposed for development is that amount necessary for an individual on-site waste water disposal system and the fill pad for such a system is placed adjacent to the highway; and</section><section prefix='5.'>When not located on the waste water disposal fill pad, the residential unit and driveway access shall be elevated to the appropriate flood criteria by the use of pilings.</section></section></section></section><section prefix='(C)'>Management Area 3:<section prefix='(1)'>Permitted uses:<section prefix='(a)'>Residential dwellings at a density no greater than one (1) unit per forty (40) acres.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Passive recreation and conservation and traditional ORV and airboat use.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Conditional uses:<section prefix='(a)'>Agricultural use, provided that:<section prefix='1.'>The parcel of land proposed for development is located in Management Area 3B or 3C,</section><section prefix='2.'>The parcel proposed for agricultural use in Management Area 3C is adjacent to an established agricultural use or separated from an adjacent agricultural use by a parcel of land that cannot be farmed due to natural conditions such as a slough or tree island or by the refusal of the adjacent property owner to allow his/her land to be farmed,</section><section prefix='3.'>When the parcel proposed for development is within Management Area 3C, there are no alternative locations for the establishment of an agricultural use in Management Areas 1 and 3B,</section><section prefix='4.'>The applicant can demonstrate that the parcel is hydrologically capable of supporting farming, and all required federal permits are obtained.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-121, ยง 5, 10-27-81)</history></law>