<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='3'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='4'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-42</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005035</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>Developer means any person undertaking development.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Development means the carrying out of any use permitted on land by applicable zoning and environmental regulations (e.g., Chapters 9, 24 and 33 of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code) or making any material change in the use or character of land, including but not limited to excavation, rock plowing or other alteration of the topographic, geographic or hydrologic character of land in preparation or as a part of the commencement of new agricultural activities, the placement of structures on land; the clearing of land or a change in the intensity of use of land. Development shall include the ancillary activities such as road building and sewer construction that occur along with or as a result of any proposed land use. When appropriate to the context, development refers to the act of developing or the result of development.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Development bonus means an increase in the intensity and/or density of development that can be carried out per unit of land.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Density means the number of minimum size lots, units, or other measure of development intensity that can be located or developed on a specified unit of land.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Land means the earth, water and air above, below or on the surface.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Owner means the person with legal and/or equitable title to real property.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Parcel of land means any quantity of land capable of being described with such definiteness that its location and boundaries may be established which is designated by its owner or developer as land to be used as a unit.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Person means any and all persons, including but not limited to an individual, firm, association, organization, partnership, business trust, trust, corporation or company.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Severable use right means a specially allocated, lawful permitted right of use of real property which inures to the benefit of the owner of a parcel of land, as created under this division.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Transferor parcel means a parcel of land from which a severable use right has been severed.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Unimproved land means land which is not developed for or used for residential purposes. In the event that a residential dwelling unit is located on a parcel of land which exceeds the minimum lot area required under the provisions of Chapter 33 of the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code on January 14, 1981, the area in excess of the minimum lot area shall be considered unimproved. (Ord. No. 81-122, ยง 2, 10-27-81)</section></text></law>