<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='3'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00005' order_by='00005' level='4'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-45</section_number>
<catch_line>Development of severable use rights.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005038</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>The use of severable use rights for development in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be development permitted as of right under the provisions of Chapter 33 of the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Severable use rights may only be used to secure a development bonus for the development of lands located in unincorporated portions of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County which are designated in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan metropolitan development pattern map for urban development, that is, within all of the development patterns except agriculture and open land, parks and recreation, and environmental sensitivity.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Development of severable use rights shall be in accordance with all of the requirements of the Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code, except as specifically modified by subsection (g) of this section.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The developer must demonstrate that he or she is the bona fide owner of the severable use right to be entitled to the development bonus.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The developer must demonstrate that the severable use rights proposed for development allocated to the transferor parcel of land under this division have not previously been used to secure a development bonus.</section><section prefix='(f)'>The developer must demonstrate that an instrument of conveyance or the use of the severable use right has been recorded in the chain of title of the parcel of land from which the severable use rights is transferred and that such instrument restricts the use of the transferor lands to nonresidential uses.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Residential use of severable use rights. Except as provided in paragraph (g)(15) below and notwithstanding the provisions of any other code or regulation of Miami-Dade County, the developer of a parcel of land may develop, in addition to the number of dwelling units authorized in each zoning district, one (1) dwelling unit for each severable use right, provided that the total development proposed does not exceed the following limitations:<section prefix='(1)'>In the EU-2 District:<section prefix='a.'>Minimum lot size—Four (4) acres;</section><section prefix='b.'>Minimum frontage—One hundred sixty-five (165) feet;</section><section prefix='c.'>Maximum coverage—Twenty (20) percent.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>In the EU-1C District:<section prefix='a.'>Minimum lot size—Two (2) acres;</section><section prefix='b.'>Minimum frontage—One hundred twenty-five (125) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>In the EU-1 District:<section prefix='a.'>Minimum lot size—Thirty-two thousand five hundred (32,500) square feet;</section><section prefix='b.'>Minimum frontage—One hundred ten (110) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>In the EU-S District:<section prefix='a.'>Minimum lot size—Twenty thousand (20,000) square feet;</section><section prefix='b.'>Minimum frontage—One hundred ten (110) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(5)'>In the EU-M District:<section prefix='a.'>Minimum lot size—Twelve thousand five hundred (12,500) square feet;</section><section prefix='b.'>Minimum frontage—One hundred (100) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(6)'>In the RU-1 District:<section prefix='a.'>Minimum lot size—Six thousand (6,000) square feet;</section><section prefix='b.'>Minimum frontage—Sixty (60) feet;</section><section prefix='c.'>Maximum coverage—Forty (40) percent.</section></section><section prefix='(7)'>In the RU-2 District:<section prefix='a.'>Minimum lot size—Six thousand (6,000) square feet;</section><section prefix='b.'>Minimum frontage—Sixty (60) feet;</section><section prefix='c.'>Maximum coverage—Forty (40) percent.</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>In the RU-TH District:<section prefix='a.'>Maximum density—Ten (10) du/acre;</section><section prefix='b.'>Minimum lot size—One thousand eight hundred (1,800) square feet;</section><section prefix='c.'>Minimum front setback—Ten (10) feet.</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>In the RU-3M District:<section prefix='a.'>Maximum density—Fifteen (15) du/acre;</section><section prefix='b.'>Maximum floor area ratio—0.60;</section><section prefix='c.'>Maximum height—Three (3) stories;</section><section prefix='d.'>Maximum coverage—Thirty-five (35) percent.</section></section><section prefix='(10)'>In the RU-4L District:<section prefix='a.'>Maximum density—Twenty-five (25) du/acre;</section><section prefix='b.'>Maximum floor area ratio—0.9;</section><section prefix='c.'>Maximum height—Six (6) stories;</section><section prefix='d.'>Maximum coverage—Thirty-five (35) percent.</section></section><section prefix='(11)'>In the RU-4M District:<section prefix='a.'>Maximum density—Forty (40) du/acre;</section><section prefix='b.'>Maximum floor area ratio—1.0;</section><section prefix='c.'>Maximum height—Nine (9) stories;</section><section prefix='d.'>Maximum coverage—Thirty-five (35) percent.</section></section><section prefix='(12)'>In the RU-4 District:<section prefix='a.'>Maximum density—Fifty-five (55) du/acre;</section><section prefix='b.'>Maximum height—One (1) additional story;</section><section prefix='c.'>Maximum floor area ratio—2.2 for a development over nine (9) stories.</section></section><section prefix='(13)'>In the RU-4A District:<section prefix='a.'>Maximum density:<section prefix='1.'>Apartments—Fifty-five (55) du/acre;</section><section prefix='2.'>Hotel rooms—Eighty-five (85) du/acre;</section></section><section prefix='b.'>Maximum height—One (1) additional story;</section><section prefix='c.'>Maximum floor area ratio—2.2 for a development over nine (9) stories.</section></section><section prefix='(14)'>In the PAD District: A bonus of twenty (20) percent in the number of residential dwelling units above the maximum density set forth on the Comprehensive Development Master Plan Land Use Plan Map as permitted by the Land Use Element of the Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='(15)'>In all Community Urban Center zoning districts: Developments located on parcels of land that are in the Core or Center Sub-districts of Community Urban Center zoning districts and that are designated as Mixed Use Main (MM), Mixed Use Corridor (MC), or Mixed Use U.S. 1 (M1) on the respective Land Use Regulating Plan, may develop, in addition to the number of dwelling units authorized in the Land Use Regulating Plan, up to 8 dwelling units at the rate of 2 dwelling units for each severable use right.</section></section><section prefix='(h)'>Commercial development of severable use rights. The developer of a parcel of land in the BU-1, BU-1A, BU-2 and BU-3 Districts may secure a development bonus of additional floor area ratio of .015 per acre for each severable use right. In no event shall a development in a BU-1 and BU-1A District exceed forty-five (45) percent lot coverage. In no event shall a development in a BU-2 and BU-3 District exceed fifty (50) percent of lot coverage.</section><section>The developer of a parcel of land in the OPD district may secure a development bonus of additional floor area ratio of .010 per acre for each severable use right.</section><section prefix='(i)'>In the event the use of severable use rights involves development above the underlying permitted height or lot coverage or floor area ratio restriction in the district the parcel proposed by development is located, each dwelling unit and every square foot of nonresidential building above the underlying height or lot coverage or floor area ratio restriction shall be derived from severable use rights.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-122, § 5, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 89-54, § 1, 6-6-89; Ord. No. 02-232, § 1, 11-19-02; Ord. No. 05-143, § 13, 7-7-05)</history></law>