<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='4'>DIVISION 2. OVERLAY ZONING REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-28</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—General standards.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005029</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-28. Same—General standards.<section>A conditional use permit may be granted only if the applicant demonstrates that:<section prefix='(a)'>The conditional use is consistent with the purposes, goals, objectives and standards of the East Everglades Management Plan;</section><section prefix='(b)'>The design of the proposed development minimizes adverse effects, including visual impacts of the proposed use on adjacent properties;</section><section prefix='(c)'>The proposed use will not have singular or cumulative adverse effect on the value of adjacent property;</section><section prefix='(d)'>The proposed use, singly or cumulatively, will not unduly burden essential public facilities and services including roadways, parking spaces, police and fire protection, drainage systems, refuse disposal, water and sewers, and schools;</section><section prefix='(e)'>The proposed use, singly or cumulatively, will not have any of the following irreversible effects on the ecological integrity of the East Everglades:<section prefix='(1)'>Harmful obstruction or undesirable alteration of the natural flow of water within the area of work.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Harmful or increased erosion, or adverse environmental impact resulting from changes in water quality or quantity.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Adverse impact upon wetland flora and fauna within adjacent parcels.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Adverse impact upon wetland flora and fauna within those portions of the subject property not proposed for development under the application.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Material injury to adjoining land.</section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 8, 10-27-81)</history></law>