<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00044' order_by='00044' level='4'>DIVISION 4. WETLANDS DISCLOSURE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-54</section_number>
<catch_line>Disclosure statement for land transactions in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005100</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-54. Disclosure statement for land transactions in the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern.<section prefix='(a)'>All transactions involving the sale or transfer of real property or interest in real property located within the East Everglades Area of Critical Environmental Concern shall include in the documents of conveyance the following statement:<section>THE LAND WHICH IS THE SUBJECT OF THIS TRANSACTION IS LOCATED IN THE EAST EVERGLADES AREA OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN. THE LAND IS SUBJECT TO PERIODIC, NATURAL FLOODING, WHICH POSES A SERIOUS RISK TO PERSONS AND PROPERTY IN THE AREA AND MAKES THE PROPERTY UNSUITABLE FOR RESIDENTIAL, COMMERCIAL, AND INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT.</section><section>METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY AND THE SOUTH FLORIDA WATER MANAGEMENT DISTRICT HAVE OFFICIALLY DETERMINED THAT FLOOD PROTECTION FOR THIS AREA WILL NOT BE PROVIDED WITH PUBLIC MONIES.</section><section>METROPOLITAN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY HAS ALSO DETERMINED THAT IT WILL NOT CONSTRUCT ANY NEW ROADS IN THE AREA OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN AND WILL MAINTAIN ONLY THE FOLLOWING ROADS: SW 136 STREET FROM SW 187 AVENUE TO SW 209 AVENUE; SW 168 STREET FROM LEVEE L-31N TO SW 237 AVENUE; SW 237 AVENUE FROM SW 168 STREET TO SW 160 STREET; INGRAHAM HIGHWAY (FORMERLY SR 27).</section><section>I HEREBY CERTIFY THAT I HAVE READ AND UNDERSTAND THE FOREGOING STATEMENT.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>The statement in subsection (a) of this section shall be set forth on a separate sheet of paper and shall be signed by the purchaser prior to the execution of any other instrument committing the purchaser to acquire said real property or to acquire any interest therein.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 82-113, ยง 5, 12-21-82)</history></law>