<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00042' order_by='00042' level='4'>DIVISION 2. OVERLAY ZONING REGULATIONS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-23</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005079</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-23. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Agricultural support housing means a single residential or housekeeping unit for the employees of an agricultural use.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Agricultural use means horticulture and floriculture, horticultural and floricultural uses and purposes, including row crop farms, groves, nurseries, horticultural farming, truck farming and barns, sheds, or other nonhabitable structures which are used for the storage of farm machinery, fertilizer, seed or other items or equipment which are ancillary to an on-site agricultural use. The propagation, sale, maintenance, or transport of noxious exotic species as defined hereunder is prohibited. The maintenance and raising of animals for commercial purposes is not included.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Conservation means any activity which protects or enhances the vitality of a parcel's native flora and fauna.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Critical habitat means those land areas which are described as critical habitat by the U.S. Department of Interior.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Cumulative impact means the total impact, over time, of a proposed development and a proliferation of the same or similar developments on the environment throughout the management area.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Developer means any person undertaking development.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Development means the carrying out of any use permitted on land by applicable zoning and environmental regulations (e.g., Chapters 9, 24 and 33 of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County Code) or making any material change in the use or character of land, including, but not limited to, excavation, filling, rock plowing or other alteration of the topographic, geologic or hydrologic character of land in preparation or as a part of the commencement of new agricultural activities, the placement of structures on land, the clearing of land or a change in the intensity of use of land. Development shall include ancillary activities such as road building and sewer construction that occur along with or as a result of any proposed land use. When appropriate to the context, development refers to the act of developing or the result of development.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Established agricultural operation means an agricultural use in existence on January 14, 1981.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Land means the earth, water and air above, below or on the surface.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Management Area 1 means that land that is shown as Management Area 1 on the attached map entitled "Management Areas of the East Everglades" which is filed with the Clerk of the County Commission. An official map of the East Everglades Management Area will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Management Area 2 means that land that is shown as Management Area 2 on the attached map entitled "Management Areas of the East Everglades" which is filed with the Clerk of the County Commission. An official map of the East Everglades Management Area will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section>The south half of Section 19, Township 58 South, Range 39 East lying westerly of U.S. Highway No. 1, less canal and road rights-of-way, containing three hundred twenty (320) acres, more or less, Miami-Dade County, Florida, shall be excluded from Management Area 2.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Management Area 3 means that land that is shown as Management Area 3 on the attached map entitled "Management Areas of the East Everglades" which is filed with the Clerk of the County Commission. An official map of the East Everglades Management Area will be maintained by the Miami-Dade County Department of Planning and Zoning.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Noxious exotic plants includes but is not limited to any of the following plant species: Cajeput (Melaleuca quinquenervia); Australian pine (Casuarina spp.); Brazilian pepper (Schinus terebinthifolius); castor bean (Ricinus communis); colubrina Colubrina asiatica); aerial potato (Discorea bulbifera); and day-blooming jasmine (Cestrum diurnum).</section><section prefix='(n)'>Owner means the person with legal and/or equitable title to real property.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Passive recreation means those recreational opportunities afforded by such resources as the native flora, fauna, and aesthetic appeal of a natural setting and requiring minimum development to utilize and enjoy such resources, including but not limited to nature study, primitive camping, hiking, canoeing, picnicking, hunting and fishing.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Parcel of land means any quantity of land capable of being described with such definiteness that its locations and boundaries may be established and which is designated by its owner or developer as land to be used as a unit.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Person means any and all persons, including but not limited to an individual, firm, association, organization, partnership, business trust, trust, corporation or company.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Road means any cleared, plowed, bulldozed, filled, graded, excavated or paved area capable of being used for the passage of vehicles, persons or animals. Roads shall not mean trails used or capable of being used solely by off-road vehicles such as airboats, swamp buggies and all-terrain vehicles.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Secondary/induced impact means those impacts which may result from a development that is generated as an ancillary or subsequent use to the proposed development, including but not limited to the disposal of runoff from a primary use.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-121, ยง 3, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 95-215, ยง 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, ยง 23, 9-3-98)</history></law>