<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERALLY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-11</section_number>
<catch_line>Adoption of declarations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005070</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-11. Adoption of declarations.<section>The aforesaid declarations are hereby adopted as the legislative and intent of the Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, and are made a part hereof.</section><section>The Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County, Florida, hereby declares and finds that the creation of the area of critical environmental concern is essential to assure the protection and maintenance of the public health, safety and welfare of the present and future inhabitants of, and visitors to, Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. It is the purpose of this designation to protect the public health, safety and welfare by assuring orderly development of the designated area and minimal degradation of those natural ecosystems described in; by requiring that the functional integrity of natural ecosystems as described in is protected; by assuring the maintenance of the present surface and subsurface hydrology within those lands described in; by providing for the protection of the ecological form and function of the Everglades National Park, its estuarine areas and adjacent wetlands, and to maintain the capability of the natural environment to sustain a proposed use in the long term. This approach will ensure the integrated use of the physical, natural and social sciences and arts in the planning decision process to minimize adverse impacts upon, and to maximize the benefits and resources of, the area.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-1, ยง 1, 1-15-81)</history></law>