<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='2'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00002' order_by='00002' level='3'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00041' order_by='00041' level='4'>DIVISION 1. GENERALLY</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-15</section_number>
<catch_line>Management area.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005019</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 33B-15. Management area.<section>Based on the environmental conditions and management purposes in Sections and, respectively, of this article, three (3) management areas are hereby established for the East Everglades. As illustrated on the accompanying map, these areas are as follows:<section prefix='(a)'>Management Area 1: Modified Environment. This management area includes land along the eastern boundary of the study area which has been previously altered by human activity.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Management Area 2: Permanent Wetlands. This management area is defined as all land within the East Everglades that is flooded for at least nine (9) months of a normal water year. This condition is determined by stage-duration relationships calculated using available hydrologic data. This area includes most of Northeast Shark River Slough and the Southeast Saline Everglades.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Management Area 3: Seasonal Wetlands. Management Area 3 is defined as that area lying between Management Areas 1 and 2. It is flooded for less than nine (9) months of a normal water year. Based on hydrologic conditions, the area is further divided into Subareas 3A, 3B and 3C.<section prefix='(1)'>Subarea 3A is defined as meeting at least one (1) of the following criteria:<section prefix='a.'>Has vegetation characterized by tree island and wet prairie communities;</section><section prefix='b.'>Is flooded from three (3) to nine (9) months during an average water year; and</section><section prefix='c.'>Is flooded less than three (3) months during an average water year but is not contiguous with Management Area 1.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Subarea 3B is defined as all land in the East Everglades which meets both of the following criteria:<section prefix='a.'>Is flooded less than three (3) months during an average year; and</section><section prefix='b.'>Is contiguous with Management Area 1.</section></section></section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-1, ยง 5, 1-15-81)</history></law>