<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00069' order_by='00069' level='3'>Chapter 33B AREAS OF CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL CONCERN</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='4'>ARTICLE II. EAST EVERGLADES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33B-27</section_number>
<catch_line>Conditional uses—Application process.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005028</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>Application contents. An application for a permit for development approval for a conditional use authorized by Section 33B-25 of this division shall be submitted to the Department of Environmental Resources Management in accordance with the provisions of this section and shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable fee in an amount to be established from time to time by the Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County. The application shall be in such form and contain such information and documentation as shall be prescribed from time to time by the Department of Environmental Resources Management and the Department of Planning and Zoning and shall contain at least the following information:<section prefix='(1)'>Name and address of applicant;</section><section prefix='(2)'>Legal description and lot number of the property which is the subject of the application;</section><section prefix='(3)'>Statement of ownership;</section><section prefix='(4)'>Size of the subject property;</section><section prefix='(5)'>A written statement describing in general terms the proposed development;</section><section prefix='(6)'>A written statement setting forth how the proposed development meets each standard specified in Section 33B-28 for the conditional use;</section><section prefix='(7)'>A site plan at a scale of not more than fifty (50) feet to the inch, on one (1) or more sheets, illustrating the proposed development and use, and including the following:<section prefix='a.'>Location of the property by lot number, block number, and street address, if any.</section><section prefix='b.'>The boundary lines of the property, the dimensions of the property, existing subdivision, and easements, roadways and public rights-of-way on or adjacent to the property.</section><section prefix='c.'>The location and dimensions of all structures designed to maintain the natural flow of surface waters.</section><section prefix='d.'>The location, height and use of all proposed and existing buildings and structures and filled areas.</section><section prefix='e.'>The approximate location and dimensions of all proposed lots.</section><section prefix='f.'>All existing and proposed surface and subsurface drainage facilities, waste treatment facilities, septic tank and potable well location.</section><section prefix='g.'>Scale of drawing and north arrow.</section><section prefix='h.'>Such other information or documentation as may be necessary or appropriate to a full and proper consideration and disposition of the development application.</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>An aerial photograph(s) taken within one (1) year of the application at the scale of three hundred (300) feet to the inch of the subject parcel and all adjacent property within two thousand six hundred forty (2,640) feet or, if an aerial photo is not available, a vicinity sketch at the scale of three hundred (300) feet equals one (1) inch showing all existing development within two thousand six hundred forty (2,640) feet of any boundary of the subject parcel.</section><section prefix='(9)'>An environmental description of the parcel proposed for development including:<section prefix='a.'>A topographical survey signed by a registered engineer or licensed land surveyor,</section><section prefix='b.'>A general description of the existing vegetation as well as all other natural features including sloughs, tree islands, geological formation, and soil type.</section></section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Review of application.<section prefix='(1)'>Within fifteen (15) days after an application for conditional use approval is submitted, the Director of Environmental Resources Management shall determine whether the application is complete. If the application is determined to be incomplete, a written statement specifying the deficiencies shall be sent to the applicant and no further action shall be taken on the application until the deficiencies are remedied.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Within sixty (60) days after receipt of a complete application, the Directors of the Planning and Zoning and the Environmental Resources Management Departments shall review the application for conditional use approval and shall decide whether the proposed conditional use permit should be issued or denied and the grounds for such decision. Such review and decision shall be based on the comments and recommendations of all other relevant County departments and a determination of whether the applicant has demonstrated compliance with the standards for conditional use approval set forth in Section 33B-28. The Department of Environmental Resources Management shall give notice of projects accepted for conditional use approval by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County and posting a notice on property adjacent to the proposed project. If an appeal is filed with the Department of Environmental Resources Management within ten (10) days of said publication, a public hearing before the Board of County Commissioners shall be held for the project. If no appeal is requested, a conditional use permit shall be issued by the Department of Environmental Resources Management subject to the provisions herein.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>Appeal to the Board of County Commissioners.<section prefix='(1)'>An applicant for conditional use approval under the provisions of this section may appeal the decision of the Directors of the Planning and Zoning and the Environmental Resources Management Departments to the Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notice of appeal shall be filed with the Clerk of the County Commission within fifteen (15) days.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Upon receipt of a notice of appeal, the Clerk of the Commission shall place the appeal on the agenda of the next regular meeting of the Board of County Commissioners.</section></section><section prefix='(d)'>Action by the Board of County Commissioners. The Board of County Commissioners of Metropolitan Miami-Dade County shall review the application for which an appeal has been properly filed, the decision of the Directors of the Departments of Planning and Zoning and Environmental Resources Management and any additional information which may be submitted. Following a full evidentiary hearing, the Commissioners may affirm, reverse or modify the decision of the Directors of the Departments of Environmental Resources Management and Planning and Zoning. Such affirmance, reversal or modification shall be based on the extent to which the applicant has demonstrated compliance with the standards for conditional use approval set forth in Section 33B-28. An aggrieved party may appeal the decision of the Board to the Circuit Court with the applicable Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 81-121, § 7, 10-27-81; Ord. No. 95-215, § 1, 12-5-95; Ord. No. 98-125, § 23, 9-3-98)</history></law>