<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='2'>Chapter 33C FIXED-GUIDEWAY RAPID TRANSIT SYSTEM—DEVELOPMENT ZONE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33C-9</section_number>
<catch_line>Downtown Intermodal District Corridor Sub-Zone.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005169</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(A)'>Purpose and Intent. The following development review standards and criteria shall govern applications for Initial Plan Approval of the general site development plan and applications for Final Site Plan Review for all development to be located within the boundaries of the Downtown Intermodal District Corridor Subzone (DID Corridor Subzone) established in subsection 33C-9(B) herein. The DID Corridor Subzone shall function as the urban transit hub of a major international tourism and trade destination. The standards set forth herein further the unique land use characteristics of this area, which lies within the City of Miami Urban Core and within a Regional Urban Center, as designated on the Land Use Plan Map of the County's Comprehensive Development Master Plan.</section><section prefix='(B)'>Boundaries. The DID Corridor Subzone of the Rapid Transit Zone is hereby established; the boundaries of the Subzone incorporated into Exhibit 17 of subsection 33C-2(B). The legal description of the boundaries and a full scale map of the boundaries of the DID Corridor Subzone presented in Exhibit 17 are on file with the Miami-Dade Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or its successor Department.</section><section prefix='(C)'>Permitted Uses: The following uses shall be permitted in the DID Corridor Subzone, either alone or as mixed uses in horizontal or vertical integration. "Vertical integration" means any combination of primary uses (such as passenger transit systems or businesses) located on the ground floor, and residential and accommodation uses such as hotels on the upper floors. "Horizontal integration" means any combination of parcels or buildings and structures with different primary uses within the same development.<section prefix='(1)'>hotels;</section><section prefix='(2)'>commercial/retail;</section><section prefix='(3)'>offices;</section><section prefix='(4)'>residential;</section><section prefix='(5)'>bars and restaurants;</section><section prefix='(6)'>intercity passenger rail systems, which provide, but not limited to such uses, elements and activities as stations, passenger platforms and waiting areas, ticket and information booths, luggage handling areas, restrooms, utility rooms, in-station advertising displays, stairs, elevators, escalators, walkways, concessions, vending machines, restaurants, lounges and other service-related businesses offering goods and services for sale to passengers, and other similar uses as are necessary for or ancillary to the proper functioning of a passenger rail station or system;</section><section prefix='(7)'>maintenance facilities for an intercity passenger rail system, including yard and shops, and associated tracks and facilities.</section><section prefix='(8)'>rental car facilities;</section><section prefix='(9)'>parking lots and parking structures, including commercial parking lots and garages that charge fees for parking;</section><section prefix='(10)'>governmental;</section><section prefix='(11)'>convention halls and showrooms;</section><section prefix='(12)'>institutional;</section><section prefix='(13)'>health care facilities, except hospitals;</section><section prefix='(14)'>other similar uses as approved by the Director of the Department of Regulatory and Economic Resources or its successor Department.</section></section><section prefix='(D)'>Pre-application conference. The applicant shall participate in at least one pre-application conference with the Rapid Transit Development Impact Committee (RTDIC) prior to filing the application. The applicant shall provide a general outline of the proposal through schematics and sketch plans including narrative information sufficient for the understanding of the proposed development.</section><section prefix='(E)'>Initial Review.<section prefix='(1)'>Following the pre-application conference, a request for approval of a general site development plan for development within the Downtown Intermodal District Corridor Subzone of the Rapid Transit Zone as provided in subsection 33C-9 herein, shall be made by filing an application with the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee (RTDIC) in accordance with the provisions of Section 33-304. Said application shall be considered a special exception for approval of a general site development plan to be considered and acted upon directly by the Board of County Commissioners pursuant to the development regulations established in Section 33C-9. Applications shall comply with the procedural requirements of Section 33-304 of this code. Within sixty (60) days after the filing of the application, the RTDIC Staff Council shall review the application, and the RTDIC shall issue a recommendation upon such application. The recommendation shall reflect the consensus of the members present. In the event that the City representatives present do not concur with a recommendation for approval, the recommendation shall be for denial. The recommendation shall be transmitted to the Board of County Commissioners for final action. In the event of a recommendation of denial by the RTDIC, approval of the application shall require the affirmative vote of 9 members of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Phased development. The intermodal characteristics of the DID Corridor Subzone serving the MetroRail, MetroMover, and MetroBus systems may require that the construction of infrastructure to serve future development be completed in phases. Where a phased development is requested, the Board of County Commissioners, in approving a phased site plan, shall specify building footprints, heights, density, intensity, and gross square footage of buildings that are identified on the site plan as future development parameters granted by the Board of County Commissioners. Specific land uses and design details of said future development may be reviewed and approved by the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee in subsequent phases pursuant to the Final Review criteria enumerated herein, provided the development parameters approved by the Board of County Commissioners in the phased site plan are not exceeded and the development regulations set forth herein are met.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Required exhibits for Initial Development. The following exhibits shall be submitted with the application for a general site development plan:<section prefix='(a)'>A narrative describing the project's scope, including but not limited to: vision statement, size of project and location, and prominent components of the development; phasing of the development if necessary; scale; relevance to the region; its connection to the surrounding urban context; economic impact on the local economy; design concept(s); significance of the project as a gateway to the community; and any additional information necessary to explain the development.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Schematic site plan(s) at a scale of not less than one (1) inch equals one hundred (100) feet indicating: prominent structural components of the development; permitted land uses; existing and proposed streets; major points of egress/ingress of the development; public open space locations and area in square feet; floor area ratio; pedestrian circulation; residential density; and square feet of retail, office, institutional, governmental, and other proposed land uses not to exceed the development thresholds contained in the administrative site plan development parameters included herein.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Information on adjoining and adjacent uses on a plan at a scale no less than one (1) inch equals one hundred (100) feet to indicate the relationship(s) between the proposed development and adjacent areas including, but not limited to: existing land uses and their intensities; densities, vehicular and pedestrian circulation systems, blocks and lots, and unique geographical features.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Perspectives, isometrics, elevations and other drawings illustrating proposed development.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any additional information specified by the Rapid Transit Development Impact Committee at the pre-application conference to evaluate the character and impact of the proposed development.</section></section></section><section prefix='(F)'>Final Review.<section prefix='(1)'>Final Review for development of the Downtown Intermodal District Corridor Subzone. Following approval of the special exception, final review for all or a portion of the development, including phased development, shall be made and approved administratively by the RTDIC in accordance with plans and documents approved by the Board of County Commissioners. The RTDIC review shall be guided by development standards established in subparagraph 33C-9(F), herein, for an administrative site plan review (ASPR). Applications for modification of a site plan approved pursuant to this section, including applications for approval of a subsequent phase of a previously approved phased site plan, shall be considered and acted upon administratively by the RTDIC without the necessity of public hearing. In the event that the City representatives present do not concur with approval of the application, the decision of the RTDIC shall be for denial. The affirmative vote of 9 members of the Board of County Commissioners shall be required to reverse a decision of denial by the RTDIC.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Notice. Mailed notices of the RTDIC Executive Council meeting shall be accomplished by placing in the United States mail a written notice to all property owners of record, as reflected on the Miami-Dade County Property Appraiser's tax roll as updated, within five hundred (500) feet of the subject property. Such mailed notices shall contain general information, including, but not limited to, the date, time and place of the meeting, the property's location (and street address, if available), and nature of the application shall be sent no sooner than thirty (30) days and no later than twenty (20) days prior to the meeting. The property shall be posted no later than twenty (20) days prior to the meeting in a manner conspicuous to the public, by a sign or signs containing information including, but not limited to, the applied for zoning action, application number, and the time and place of the public meeting. The property owner shall be responsible for ensuring that the sign is maintained on the site until completion of the public meeting and for removal of the sign within two (2) weeks following completion of the public meeting. In addition, notice shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County, as follows: a full legal notice, to be published no later than twenty (20) days and no earlier than thirty (30) days prior to the meeting, to contain the date, time and place of the meeting, the property's location and street address, if available.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Required Exhibits. The following exhibits must be included with an application. It is provided, however, that the Director shall have the authority to waive any of the items because of the nature or timing of the development or because the information cannot be furnished at the time of this review. The application shall be deemed complete if all items in this subsection are included in the application.<section prefix='(a)'>Master plan at a scale of not less than one (1) inch equals one-hundred (100) feet, which shall include the following information:<section prefix='(i)'>Lot lines and setbacks.</section><section prefix='(ii)'>Proposed floor area of all permitted uses.</section><section prefix='(iii)'>Height, size, shape and location of existing and proposed buildings.</section><section prefix='(iv)'>Location of off-street parking and layouts showing number of parking spaces required and provided.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Proposed grades if significantly altered.</section><section prefix='(vi)'>Signage, street and lot lighting, street and lot furniture.</section><section prefix='(vii)'>Total number of dwelling units and hotel rooms, if applicable.</section><section prefix='(viii)'>Location and amount of public/private open space required and provided.</section><section prefix='(ix)'>Phase lines, if applicable.</section><section prefix='(x)'>Figures indicating gross and net acreage, and areas to be dedicated for public rights-of-way.</section><section prefix='(xi)'>Vehicular and pedestrian circulation system including blocks, streets, major points of access into and out of the development, pedestrian crosswalks, medians, and on-street parking.</section><section prefix='(xii)'>Location of pedestrian access points, including connections to existing or proposed bridges, roadways, or sidewalk areas.</section><section prefix='(xiii)'>Location of loading facilities, waste collection areas, and other service areas.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Floor plans and elevations of all structures, including gross square footage of each floor.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Sections of major structures.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Isometrics or perspectives of the proposed development.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Landscape plan(s) in accordance with Chapter 18(A), except as modified herein.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Such other design data as may be specified to satisfy a condition of approval of the Initial Review.</section></section></section><section prefix='(G)'>Administrative Site plan development parameters. The following development regulations shall apply to all development within the DID Corridor Subzone.<section prefix='(1)'>Parking: The table below indicates minimum parking for uses located in the DID Corridor Subzone.<section prefix='(a)'>To minimize adverse visual effects of the structure(s), multi-story parking garages facing public and private streets rights-of-way and/or public open space shall utilize but not be limited to: liner buildings; glazing; building wall extensions; vertical planted walls; berms; landscaping; architectural fenestration; sculpture; design features or other innovative screening methods. Surface parking lots fronting streets shall be located a minimum of ten (10) feet from the right-of-way and screened at the ten (10) foot line with a wall having a maximum height of 3'6". The setback shall incorporate a combination of hard-scape and landscape elements finished to match the existing sidewalk.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Mechanized parking shall be allowed and when provided, exempt from the provisions of Section 33-122 of this Code. For the purpose of this Subzone, mechanized parking shall be defined as a mechanism with vertical and horizontal transport capability that provides for automobile storage and retrieval. A mechanized parking space shall be counted toward the parking requirements of this Section. Mechanized parking may not be provided unless a queuing analysis is submitted and approved during the Administrative Site Plan Review process.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Required off-street parking for uses located within the DID Corridor Subzone can be located within one mile of the boundaries of the DID Corridor Subzone. An applicant for approval of development with off-site parking shall execute and record in the public records of this County a declaration of restrictions approved by the Director covenanting that such development shall cease and terminate upon the elimination of such parking area, and that no development requiring such parking shall be made of such property until the required parking area is available and provided.</section></section><section prefix='(2)'>Setbacks, cubic content, and lot size:<section prefix='(a)'>Due to the unique characteristics associated with an intermodal transit corridor subzone, development setbacks from all streets (other than NW 1st Avenue), interior/rear property lines and Metromover and Metrorail rights-of-way shall be zero (0) feet minimum.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Setback from NW 1st Avenue: The minimum setback for thirty percent (30%) of buildings fronting on NW 1st Avenue shall be zero (0) feet. Seventy percent (70%) of buildings fronting on NW 1st Avenue shall setback ten (10) feet minimum; provided, however, where a colonnade is provided the setback shall be zero (0) feet. Colonnades shall have a minimum clear unobstructed width of ten (10) feet and a minimum clear height of ten (10) feet. When the development sets back a minimum of ten (10) feet from the edge of the right-of-way, the setback area shall incorporate a combination of hard-scape and landscape elements finished to match the existing sidewalk. The percentage of frontage requirement may be calculated by street block or as a combined cumulative average of all street blocks fronting NW 1st Avenue.</section><section prefix='(c)'>There shall be no cubic content or minimum lot size requirements.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Encroachments:<section prefix='(a)'>Buildings and structures above the ground floor may be built above colonnades and/or encroach into street setbacks but shall not extend beyond the public or private right-of-way; except that a maximum of one-hundred (100%) percent of the street may be covered above the first floor with structures connecting buildings including: platforms fitted with trains and passenger waiting areas; roofs; upper story terraces, pedestrian bridges, automobile bridges between parking garages and parking garages. Adequate clearance for structures above streets shall be maintained.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Cantilevered balconies, awnings, weather protection elements and similar features with adequate vertical clearance may encroach into street rights-of-way but shall not extend closer than six (6) inches from the curb face.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Floor Area Ratio and lot coverage: The floor area ratio, lot coverage and maximum square footage of buildings to be developed within the DID Corridor Subzone shall not be limited.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Building Height: The maximum building height shall be limited by FAA criteria.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Open Space: The minimum open space requirement shall be fifteen percent (15%) of the gross development area. Open space shall include parks, plazas, balconies, terraces, courtyards, arcades/colonnades, pedestrian paths, rooftop green spaces above buildings and parking garages, and transit platform areas improved for pedestrian comfort.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Signs: Signs visible from public rights-of-way or public areas shall comply with Section 33-284.87 of this Code, except that Class C signs may be permitted in accordance with Section 33-107 of this Code. Subject to the requirements and limitations of Section 33-107 of this Code, a maximum of five (5) murals may be approved in this Subzone. The signage plan submitted with the application for final site plan review shall contain criteria, locations and sizes of signs.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Density: Residential density shall not exceed 500 units per gross acre.</section><section prefix='(9)'>Architectural Expression: Building facades facing public and private street rights-of-way or public open space or both shall be a minimum 40% glazed. Glazing is not required for building facades which face the Metrorail or MetroMover rights-of-way or for above-grade parking garage structures which face public and private street rights-of-way or public open space; however, parking garages shall conform to the parking standards included herein. Blank walls facing public and private street rights-of-way and public open space shall be prohibited unless furnished with some type of artistic expression such as sculpture, mosaic and similar features.</section><section prefix='(10)'>Landscaping: Landscaping shall conform to the standards set forth in Section 18A-6, Code of Miami-Dade County, as applicable to non-residential development, with the following exceptions:<section prefix='(a)'>Lot trees: Thirty (30) trees per net acre of open space. In addition to the placement of trees in the lot, they may be placed in greens, squares, plazas and street medians within or in close proximity to the Subzone. Lot trees shall have a minimum two (2) inch diameter at breast height.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Street trees shall be planted at a maximum of thirty (30) feet average on center, with a minimum three (3) inch diameter at breast height. Street trees shall be placed inside landscaped strips, tree planters, and in medians in the right-of-way or on private property where demonstrated to be necessary due to right-of-way obstructions as determined by the Public Works and Waste Management Department or its successor Department or the appropriate authority within the municipality.</section></section><section prefix='(11)'>Service areas and mechanical equipment: Service areas and fixtures shall be screened and so located as not to be visible from public and private rights-of-way or public open space. Mechanical equipment installed on roofs shall be screened from view by parapets or other architectural elements. Fixtures, including but not limited to backflow preventers, pumps, underground ventilation exhausts, and electrical vaults, shall be located within or to the side or rear of buildings; such fixtures shall not be located within the street setback area. Backflow preventers shall be shielded from view, as required by Sec. 32-157(d) of the Code.</section></section><section prefix='(H)'>Plan Review Standards. The purpose of the site development standards is to encourage the creation of development within the Subzone that acts as a significant gateway for and destination to downtown Miami by designing and arranging buildings, public open space, transit and street circulation in a manner that foster round the clock pedestrian-activity, serves the local and regional transit demands of the community and contributes to the urban revitalization of the City of Miami.<section prefix='(1)'>A mix of uses in the design of development projects is encouraged to the maximum extent possible. Mixed-use buildings including without limitation residential, commercial, office, hotel, and restaurants, are highly encouraged in combination with transit facilities.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Developments shall provide direct pedestrian and vehicular connections to the adjacent block and street network. Pedestrian crosswalks providing safe passage from adjoining streets and blocks into the development project of the Subzone shall be installed at street corners and, if practicable, midblock locations. Crosswalks shall be distinguished from other street elements by the use of conspicuous materials, texture and color.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Public open space in the form of plazas, squares, greens, and landscaped areas shall be incorporated in the design of all development projects at grade or on above-grade surfaces. The public open spaces should have a scale that is compatible and complementary with the intensity of proposed development, and their design should relate to the development's concept. Landscaping, furniture, art, paved pedestrian paths, and lighting, among other features, should be used to enhance the open spaces pedestrian experience.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Consideration should be given to providing landscaping in a manner that reduces the heat island effect of the development on the urban environment.</section><section prefix='(5)'>All new development shall strive to meet certification standards from Florida Green Building Coalition or a similar organization.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Developments shall be designed with a coordinated outdoor lighting and signage system that is an integral part of the project and compatible and harmonious with existing and proposed development in the Subzone and with surrounding uses. Signage should clearly indicate locations of and guide pedestrians and vehicles to proposed parking areas, transit facilities, permitted uses, and surrounding activities and uses.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Proposed building scale should be in harmony with building scales allowed by applicable City of Miami regulations for surrounding properties. Buildings and their landscapes shall be built to the sidewalk edge in a manner that frames the adjacent street to create public space in the street corridor that is comfortable and interesting, as well as safe for pedestrians. Architectural elements at street level shall have abundant fenestration, windows and doors and design elements that create interest for the pedestrian.</section><section prefix='(8)'>Proposed development in the Subzone shall provide connections via bridges, paths, sidewalks, or a combination of such features to the MetroRail and MetroMover systems that adjoin the property.</section></section><section prefix='(I)'>Platting. Separate parcels located within the DID Corridor Subzone and made subject to a unity of title or covenant in lieu of unity of title shall not be deemed a subdivision and shall be exempt from the platting requirements of Chapter 28.</section><section prefix='(J)'>Conflicts. The development review procedures, standards, and criteria set forth in this section 33C-9 shall govern in the event of conflicts with other zoning, subdivision or landscape regulations of the Miami-Dade County Code or with the Miami-Dade County Public Works and Waste Management Department Manual.</section><section prefix='(K)'>Amendments. At least six (6) weeks prior to the scheduled public hearing of any amendments to this Section 33C-9, the County shall mail or e-mail a copy of the proposed ordinance to the City Clerk and the City Attorney of the City of Miami. The communication to the City shall include the date of the scheduled public hearing.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-37, § 7, 4-8-14)</history></law>