<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='2'>Chapter 33C FIXED-GUIDEWAY RAPID TRANSIT SYSTEM—DEVELOPMENT ZONE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33C-3</section_number>
<catch_line>Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005051</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>There is hereby established a Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council composed of the County's Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council (established by Section 33-303.1, Miami-Dade County Code) and two (2) representatives from each of the following municipalities: City of South Miami, City of Coral Gables, City of Miami, and the City of Hialeah. It is provided, however, that for developments located within the Downtown Intermodal District Corridor Subzone established by subsection 33C-9, however, the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee shall be composed of the County's Developmental Impact Committee Executive Council and three (3) representatives from the City of Miami. In addition, there shall be an RTDIC Staff Council composed of members of the County Departments identified in Section 33-303.1(A) of this Code and three (3) representatives from the City of Miami. The Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee shall, subject to the procedures specified in 33-303.1, Miami-Dade County Code, perform the duties specified in Section 33C-2 and Section 33C-4 of this chapter.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Except for the Downtown Intermodal District Corridor Subzone established by subsection 33C-9 herein, mailed notice of hearings before the Rapid Transit Development Impact Committee pursuant to Section 33C-2(D)(2)(d) shall be provided in the same manner as hearings on applications filed before the Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to Section 33-310(d)(3) for the special exceptions expressly enumerated in that subsection. Mailed notice of the hearing shall also be provided simultaneously to the municipality in which the application site is located. Applications shall comply with the procedural requirements of Section 33-304.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Notwithstanding any other provision of this code to the contrary, for the Downtown Intermodal District Corridor Subzone established by subsection 33C-9 herein, notice of meetings before the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Committee shall comply with the procedures set forth in 33C-9.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-74, § 1, 10-17-78; Ord. No. 03-113, § 3, 5-6-03; Ord. No. 14-37, § 3, 4-8-14)</history></law>