<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00070' order_by='00070' level='2'>Chapter 33C FIXED-GUIDEWAY RAPID TRANSIT SYSTEM—DEVELOPMENT ZONE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33C-4</section_number>
<catch_line>Rapid Transit Development Impact Zone.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005107</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>The Rapid Transit Development Impact Zone consists of those lands in such close proximity to the Rapid Transit System as to have a significant impact thereon. The Station Area Design and Development (SADD) Program (authorized by Miami-Dade County Resolution No. R-829-77), a joint municipal-County program administered through the Rapid Transit Development Impact Committee, shall prepare proposed development standards for the Rapid Transit Development Impact Zone for those stations not subject to Section 33C-2(D)(2)(e)(1). Such proposed development standards shall be submitted to the Rapid Transit Development Impact Committee established by Section 33C-3 of this chapter for review, comment and any recommendations. The Rapid Transit Development Impact Committee report, including the proposed development standards, shall be submitted to the appropriate municipality or, in the unincorporated areas, to the County for review and adoption as the land use plan for developments within the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Zone. The foregoing notwithstanding, after completion of the initial task by the SADD Program, for those stations not subject to Section 33C-2(D)(2)(e)(1) the Rapid Transit Impact Committee shall prepare all future development standards for the Rapid Transit Development Impact Zone for review and adoption by the Board of County Commissioners if located in unincorporated Miami-Dade County or the appropriate municipality if located in incorporated Miami-Dade County. Once adopted, said land use plans shall control all public actions involving or affecting land use or development, including action on applications for zoning relief, within the Rapid Transit Developmental Impact Zone. Amendments to said land use plans shall be subject to the procedures specified in this section. The County may seek judicial review of any official municipal acts relating to lands within the Rapid Transit Development Impact Zone.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Except for the Downtown Intermodal District Corridor Subzone established by subsection 33C-9 herein, and notwithstanding anything to the contrary herein, mailed notice of hearings before the Rapid Transit Development Impact Committee pursuant to Section 33-2(D)(2)(e)(1) shall be provided in the same manner as hearings on applications filed before the Community Zoning Appeals Board pursuant to Section 33-310(d)(3) for the special exceptions expressly enumerated in that subsection. Mailed notice of hearings shall also be provided simultaneously to the municipality in which the application site is located. Applications shall comply with the procedural requirements of Section 33-304.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 78-74, § 1, 10-17-78; Ord. No. 08-28, § 2, 3-4-08; Ord. No. 14-37, § 4, 4-8-14)</history></law>