<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00072' order_by='00072' level='2'>Chapter 33E ROAD IMPACT FEES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>33E-18</section_number>
<catch_line>Road Impact Fee Deferral For Certain Land Use Types.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000005151</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(A)'>Notwithstanding anything in the code to the contrary an applicant for a building permit requiring payment of a road impact fee may request a deferral of road impact fee payment for one-half (1/2) of the assessed road impact fee for a period of up to three (3) years subject to the following terms, conditions, requirements and limitations:<section prefix='(1)'>The deferral program shall not be used to defer road impact for uses under Section 33E-8 for ITE Land Use Types that are categorized as Residential, Recreational or Institutional according to Tables 100&amp;100A.</section><section prefix='(2)'>As condition of deferral of road impact fees pursuant to this section, the owner of the property that is subject to the road impact fee shall execute a voluntary lien securing payment of the deferred portion of the road impact fee on a form provided by the Director of Public Works&amp;Waste Management Department and filed in the Public Records of Miami-Dade County.</section><section prefix='(3)'>A notice that said voluntary lien has been satisfied shall be promptly filed in the Public Records by Miami-Dade County upon final payment of all outstanding road impact fees including associated administrative fees and penalties, if any that may be owed in connection with the road impact fee.</section><section prefix='(4)'>The total amount of the road impact fee owed shall be assessed at the time the building permit is issued.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Prior to issuance of the building permit, the applicant shall pay the sum of one-half (1/2) of the total road impact fee assessed against the property ("initial payment"), plus the total administrative fee for the assessed road impact fee, plus the total administrative fee for deferral as provided under this section.</section><section prefix='(6)'>An administrative fee of ($100) or two percent (2%) of the deferred portion of the road impact fee, whichever amount is greater, shall be charged in connection with the application for deferred payment of road impact fees under this section.</section><section prefix='(7)'>No deferral amount under this section shall exceed twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) for a single application.</section><section prefix='(8)'>The schedule of payment for the deferred portion of the road impact fee shall be set as follows:<section prefix='a.'>No schedule authorized under this section may exceed three (3) years; and</section><section prefix='b.'>The payment schedule shall provide for collection of a minimum of one-third of the deferred amount for each year; and</section><section prefix='c.'>All road impact fees deferred pursuant to this section shall become immediately due upon a sale, conveyance or other transfer of title of the property that is the subject of the road impact fee.</section></section><section prefix='(9)'>No interest shall be charged against road impact fees deferred under this section provided that they are paid on time in accordance with the payment schedule. It is provided, however, that payments made later than thirty (30) calendar days from the date that payment of the impact fee installment is due shall be charged interest at the rate of twelve percent (12%) per annum simple interest accruing from the date of the initial payment up to the date of the late payment plus cost of collection established by implementing order of the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(10)'>The Director of Public Works and Waste Management Department is authorized to foreclose on the lien for any deferred impact fees including and accrued interest that remain unpaid for more than one hundred and eighty (180) calendar days beyond the date when deferred impact fees are due and may assess reasonable fees associated with the foreclosure of the lien and collection of the road impact fee payment including reasonable attorney's fees and court costs.</section></section><section prefix='(B)'>The Impact Fee Section of the Regulatory and Economic Resources Department shall provide an annual report on the status of this program to the Board of County Commissioners.</section><section prefix='(C)'>The maximum total amount of road impact funds that may be deferred pursuant to this program is one million dollars ($1,000,000), whereupon this program shall not be available to defer impact fees until such time as the total deferred amount has been reduced by payment of impact fees below the maximum set forth herein. It is provided, however, the amount of deferred road impact fees shall not include deferred impact fees that are secured by a bond or letter of credit pursuant to Section 33E-6.1(g).</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 14-53, ยง 1, 6-3-14)</history></law>