<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. DADE COUNTY VESSEL MOORING CODE</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='4'>DIVISION 1. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-32</section_number>
<catch_line>Declaration of legislative intent.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001479</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-32. Declaration of legislative intent.<section>The Board finds and determines that the insecure and improper mooring of vessels in Biscayne Bay, the Miami River and their tributaries increases the danger of grounding and breaking loose of the said vessels and thereby endangers navigation, life and property; that insecurely and improperly moored vessels have broken loose in the past and damaged bridges, structures, and other valuable property; that scrap and derelict vessels occupy areas which could be developed as berths for economically active and attractive vessels; that scrap and derelict vessels moored or sunk in the Biscayne Bay, Miami River and their tributaries are unsightly, a danger to navigation, and a detriment to tourism and to property values; that the infestation of rats and the breeding of mosquitoes on derelict vessels moored upon Biscayne Bay, the Miami River and their tributaries constitute dangers to public health, and that derelict or sunken vessels often constitute attractive nuisances that endanger the lives and safety of children. The Board hereby declares its intention that the provisions of this article are not intended and should not be construed as in any way superseding or attempting to conflict with applicable statutes, ordinances, rules or regulations of the federal government or of the State of Florida but are intended to supplement any such enactments or provisions. However, this Code shall serve as a minimum standard for all municipalities within Dade County regarding the subject matter herein.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 65-52, ยง 2, 7-27-65; Ord. No. 70-38, ยง 1, 5-6-70; Ord. No. 79-28, ยง 2, 4-17-79)</history></law>