<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00007' order_by='00007' level='2'>Chapter 7 BOATS, DOCKS AND WATERWAYS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00003' order_by='00003' level='3'>ARTICLE III. DADE COUNTY VESSEL MOORING CODE</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00010' order_by='00010' level='4'>DIVISION 2. VESSELS CONSTITUTING NUISANCES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>7-46</section_number>
<catch_line>Notice.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001490</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 7-46. Notice.<section>If the County Manager finds and determines that a vessel constituting a public nuisance is moored to or located upon land abutting Biscayne Bay, the Miami River or their tributaries, he shall so notify the record owner of the offending vessel or his lawful agent and the record owner of the said abutting land, or only the latter if the record owner of the offending vessel or his lawful agent cannot be ascertained, in writing and demand that such owners cause the condition to be remedied. The notices shall be given by registered mail, addressed to the owner or owners of the property described, as their names and addresses are known to the Manager or are shown upon the records of the County Property Appraiser or the public records of Dade County, Florida, and shall be deemed complete and sufficient when so addressed and deposited in the United States mail with proper postage prepaid. In the event that such notices are returned by postal authorities the Manager shall cause a copy of the notices to be served by a law enforcement officer upon the owner of the offending vessel or his lawful agent and upon the occupant of the land, the owner, or upon any agent of the owner thereof. In the event that personal service upon the owner of the offending vessel or his lawful agent or upon the occupant of the land, the owner, or upon any agent of the owner thereof cannot be performed after reasonable search by a law enforcement officer the notices shall be accomplished by physical posting on the said property.</section><section>The notices shall be in substantially the following form:</section><section>NOTICE OF PUBLIC NUISANCE     (VESSEL)     <section>Name of Owner of Vessel or his Lawful Agent</section></section><section><section>Address of Owner of Vessel or his Lawful Agent</section></section><section><section>Our records indicate that you are the owner(s) or lawful agent of the owner of the following vessel in Dade County, Florida:</section></section><section>  (describe vessel)<section>An inspection of this vessel and its surrounds discloses, and I have found and determined, that a public nuisance exists thereon so as to constitute a violation of the Dade County Vessel Mooring Code in that:</section></section><section>  (describe here the condition which places the vessel in violation)<section>You are hereby notified that unless the condition above described is remedied so as to make it nonviolative of the Dade County Vessel Mooring Code within twenty (20) days from the date hereof, Dade County will proceed to remedy this condition and the cost of the work, including advertising costs and other expenses, will be imposed as a lien on the vessel if not otherwise paid within thirty (30) days after receipt of billing.</section></section><section>NOTICE OF PUBLIC NUISANCE     (VESSEL )     <section>Name of Owner of Land or his Lawful Agent</section></section><section><section>Address of Owner of Land or his Lawful Agent</section></section><section><section>Our records indicate that you are the owner(s) or lawful agent of the owner of the following land in Dade County, Florida:</section></section><section>  (describe property)<section>An inspection of this land discloses, and I have found and determined, that a public nuisance exists thereon so as to constitute a violation of the Dade County Vessel Mooring Code in that:</section></section><section>  (describe here the condition which places the property in violation)<section>You are hereby notified that unless the condition above described is remedied so as to make it nonviolative of the Dade County Vessel Mooring Code within twenty (20) days from the date hereof, Dade County will proceed to remedy this condition and the cost of the work, including advertising costs and other expenses, will be imposed as a lien on the land if not otherwise paid within thirty (30) days after receipt of billing.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 65-52, § 9, 7-27-65; Ord. No. 76-61, § 1, 7-6-76; Ord. No. 79-28, § 3, 4-17-79)</history></law>