<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='4'>DIVISION 7. MOTOR VEHICLE TITLE LOANS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-124.18</section_number>
<catch_line>Record keeping.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001660</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-124.18. Record keeping.<section prefix='(a)'>Every title loan lender licensed by the Department shall maintain, at the principal place of business designated on the license, all books, accounts, records, and documents necessary to determine the title loan lender's compliance with this division.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Department may authorize maintenance of records at a location other than a principal place of business. The Department may require books and records to be produced and available at a reasonable and convenient location within Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(c)'>All books, accounts, records, documents and receipts for expenses paid by the title loan lender on behalf of the borrower, including each contract signed by the borrower and expenses incurred by the title loan lender in event of foreclosure and property recovery, shall be preserved by the title loan lender and shall be made available to the Department for examination for five (5) years after the date of original entry.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Department may prescribe the minimum information to be shown in the books, accounts, records and documents of licensees.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Title loan lenders shall keep all certificates of title in fireproof or fire-resistant storage while the certificates are in the lender's possession.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-62, ยง 1, 6-8-99)</history></law>