<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00016' order_by='00016' level='4'>DIVISION 6. Miami-Dade COUNTY DRYCLEANING AND LAUNDERING ORDINANCE</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-124.5</section_number>
<catch_line>Definitions.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001646</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-124.5. Definitions.<section prefix='(a)'>Article shall mean Division 6 of Article III of Chapter 8A of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, and any rules, regulations and standards promulgated pursuant to this article.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Customer shall be a person who inquires about, makes a request for, or purchases cleaning.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Miami-Dade County means Miami-Dade County, Florida.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Cleaner shall mean any person that is in the business of performing cleaning or presents itself to the public as being in the business of performing cleaning.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Cleaning shall mean the cleansing of clothing and other fabrics either with substantially nonaqueous organic solvents, including but not limited to petroleum naptha, or in any other manner.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Director shall mean the County Manager or the County Manager's designee. This definition shall apply to Section 8A-82.1 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, when utilizing the provisions of this article.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Person shall mean an individual, partnership, joint venture, association, corporation, trust or any other legal entity.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Warranty shall mean an express or implied guarantee provided by a cleaner to a customer with respect to the cleaner's repair, replacement or compensation for defective cleaning.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-14, ยง 1, 2-25-97)</history></law>