<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='4'>DIVISION 3. SALE OF COMMODITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-109</section_number>
<catch_line>Advertising meats for sale.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001623</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-109. Advertising meats for sale.<section>Any advertising of the edible part of the muscle of U.S.D.A.-graded beef, veal, calf, lamb, yearling mutton or mutton for sale, whether by means of signs, posters, placards, handbills, newspaper displays, or by any other advertising media, where the price is advertised, shall show the grade marked in accordance with the United States Department of Agriculture official grading standards and any subsequent revisions thereof. When any of the aforesaid portions of meat are advertised with the price thereof and the meat is not U.S.D.A.-graded ("unrolled," "no-rolled") then the advertisement shall clearly disclose the fact that the meat is non-U.S.D.A.-graded by stating: "Not U.S.D.A.-graded." If the aforesaid non-U.S.D.A.-graded meat is imported from outside of the United States of America, then the advertisement shall clearly disclose the fact that the meat is non-U.S.D.A.-graded and imported by stating: "Not U.S.D.A.-graded—Imported." The following are United States Department of Agriculture official grades and marks of said grades:<section prefix='(1)'>For beef, veal or calf: (1) U.S. Prime, (2) U.S. Choice, (3) U.S. Good, (4) U.S. Standard, (5) U.S. Commercial, and (6) U.S. Utility.</section><section prefix='(2)'>For lamb, yearling mutton and mutton: (1) U.S. Prime, (2) U.S. Choice, (3) U.S. Good, (4) U. S. Utility, and (5) U.S. Cull.</section></section><section>Grade marks shall be displayed in a plain and conspicuous manner and be no less in size or prominence than any trade or brand names denoting quality. Similarly, meats required hereby to be displayed with the statements "Not U.S.D.A.-graded" or "Not U.S.D.A.-graded—Imported," shall display such statements in a plain and conspicuous manner and be no less in size or prominence than any trade or brand names denoting quality.</section><section>All prepackaged individual packages of the aforesaid portions of meat sold or offered for sale shall display by label the prescribed grades and grade marks or, alternatively, either of the following statements: "Not U.S.D.A.-graded" or "Not U.S.D.A.-graded—Imported."</section><section>The absence of grade marks on cuts of meat stamped by the U.S. Department of Agriculture in its prescribed manner shall be prima facie evidence of violation of this section.</section><section>All grading shall be done by the U.S. Department of Agriculture.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-52, § 27, 9-19-68; Ord. No. 83-36, § 1, 6-7-83)</history></law>