<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='4'>DIVISION 3. SALE OF COMMODITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-113.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Negative option marketing programs.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001575</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-113.1. Negative option marketing programs.<section prefix='(1)'>Negative option marketing programs restricted. It shall be unlawful for a person to engage in a negative option marketing program without a written contract with the consumer in which the consumer expressly agrees to participate in the negative option marketing program. No contract provisions binding a consumer to participate in a negative option marketing program shall be valid for a period longer than twenty-four (24) months from the date they were signed by the consumer.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Definition. "Negative option marketing program" as used in this section means a contract under which a seller either:<section prefix='(a)'>Sends to a consumer an announcement, advertising or notice that:<section prefix='(i)'>The supplier proposes to send goods or provide services to the consumer (other than periodic supplements to previously acquired merchandise), and</section><section prefix='(ii)'>The consumer is required to pay for those goods or services unless the consumer affirmatively communicates that the consumer refuses to accept the goods or services; or</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Sends to a consumer a notice accompanying goods or services unless the customer affirmatively communicates that the consumer refuses to accept the goods or services.</section></section><section prefix='(3)'>Contract provisions. Any negative option contract without the following provisions shall be unlawful.<section prefix='(a)'>All negative option contracts. All negative option contracts must advise the consumer that the consumer's future silence in the face of an offer will constitute an acceptance of the offered goods or service. The contract must specify the terms of the negative option including the type of goods or service to be offered; the time period (of not less than ten (10) days) in which the goods or service can be declined; the methods by which the consumer can decline the goods or service; the right of a consumer to withdraw from the negative option at any time; and the method by which the consumer can withdraw from the negative option program.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Avoiding adhesion contracts. If the contract contains any provision concerning matters other than the negative option, the negative option provisions of the contract will be invalid unless; (1) they contain all of the terms required in subsection (3)(a); (2) they are printed in type as large as the second largest type used on the contract and under no circumstances less than ten (10) point type; (3) they contain the following language in a separate, blocked section in immediate proximity to the signature line in the largest type used on the contract: "WARNING: IF YOU SIGN THIS CONTRACT, THE COMPANY WILL HAVE THE RIGHT, FOR THE NEXT 24 MONTHS, TO BILL YOU FOR GOODS OR SERVICES THAT YOU DO NOT SPECIFICALLY ORDER, IF YOU FAIL TO RESPOND TO THEIR NOTICES AND DECLINE THE GOODS OR SERVICES WITHIN THE PERIOD PRESCRIBED BY THIS CONTRACT."; (4) they are located together near the warning required in subsection (3)(b)(3); (5) they provide a place next to the negative option provisions on which the consumer can check and initial whether she accepts or rejects the negative option provisions; (6) they provide and state that there is no penalty for declining to participate in the negative option.</section></section><section prefix='(4)'>Unordered goods or services. Any goods or services delivered pursuant to a negative option marketing program that is not in compliance with this section shall be deemed unordered goods or services which the consumer may use or dispose of without any cost or obligation.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Scope of regulation. This section will not apply to any type of negative option marketing program which is subject to federal or State regulations or laws when such regulations or laws have the effect of preempting local ordinances. This section shall apply to consumer goods and services that are purchased for personal, home, or residential use.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Legal effect. This section shall not be construed to authorize contracts otherwise illegal or to create any contractual obligation or duty on the part of a consumer that does not exist under the common law of contracts of the State of Florida.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 91-68, ยง 2, 7-9-91)</history></law>