<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='4'>DIVISION 7. MOTOR VEHICLE TITLE LOANS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-124.20</section_number>
<catch_line>Enforcement and penalties.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001717</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-124.20. Enforcement and penalties.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be the duty and responsibility of all law enforcement officials to assist in the enforcement of this division and the code to the extent that it is within their jurisdiction to do so.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The Department shall maintain a system by which licensees are given written notices of all violations. Department personnel shall be permitted to enter the business premises of a person who provides services pursuant to this division to ascertain whether the license is current, and to examine books and records as required by this division.</section><section prefix='(c)'>In addition to all other penalties, remedies or other enforcement measures established within this division, or otherwise provided by law, violations of this division shall be subject to civil penalties as provided in Chapter 8CC of the Code, and penalties shall be imposed as set forth in the schedule of penalties therein. The Department is authorized to enforce the provisions of this division by, among other means, administrative fines as provided herein. Each day of a continuing violation shall be deemed a separate violation.</section><section prefix='(d)'>The Department may enter into written assurances of compliance pursuant to Sections 8A-82.1 and 8A-124.21 of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, with respect to the matters regulated under this division.</section><section prefix='(e)'>The Department is also authorized to enforce the provisions of this division by suspension or revocation of a license upon notice and hearing as provided in this section unless the licensee waives such notice and hearing. Licenses are subject to suspension or revocation when it shall appear that:<section prefix='(1)'>The licensee has failed to comply with or has violated any provision of this division; or</section><section prefix='(2)'>The license was obtained by an application in which any material fact was omitted or falsely stated.</section></section><section prefix='(f)'>Appeals from actions, decisions or determinations of the Director of the Department shall be governed by Section 8A-161.23 of the Code.</section><section prefix='(g)'>In addition to any other judicial or administrative remedies provided by law, rule, regulation, ordinance or this division, the Director of the Department shall have the judicial remedies available to enforce the provisions of this division as provided in Section 8A-161.22 of the Code.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-62, ยง 1, 6-8-99)</history></law>