<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='4'>DIVISION 7. MOTOR VEHICLE TITLE LOANS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-124.15</section_number>
<catch_line>Transaction satisfaction and default.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001657</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-124.15. Transaction satisfaction and default.<section prefix='(a)'>When the title loan has been paid in full, the title loan lender must deliver to the borrower a certificate of title clear of all encumbrances placed upon the title by the title loan lender within thirty (30) days of such payment in full.</section><section prefix='(b)'>If a borrower fails to repay all amounts legally due under the title loan agreement on or before the end of the title loan's maturity date or any extension thereof and fails to make a payment on the loan within thirty (30) days after the end of the loan's maturity date or any extension thereof, whichever is later, the title loan lender may take possession of the titled personal property. A lender may take possession of the titled personal property only through an agent who is licensed by the state to repossess motor vehicles.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Prior to engaging a repossession agent, the lender shall afford the debtor an opportunity to make the titled personal property available to the lender at a place, date, and time reasonably convenient to the lender and the borrower. Prior to taking possession of titled personal property, the lender shall afford the borrower a reasonable opportunity to remove from the titled personal property any personal belongings without charge or additional cost to the borrower. Once the lender takes possession of the titled personal property, the lender, at the lender's sole expense and risk, may authorize a third party to retain physical possession of the titled personal property.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Upon taking possession of titled personal property, the lender may dispose of the titled personal property by sale but may do so only through a motor vehicle dealer licensed under Section 320.27, Florida Statutes. At least 10 days prior to sale, the lender shall notify the borrower of the date, time, and place of the sale and provide the borrower with a written accounting of the principal amount due on the title loan, interest accrued through the date of the lender taking possession of the titled personal property, and any reasonable expenses incurred to date by the lender in taking possession of, preparing for sale, and selling the titled personal property. At any time prior to sale, the lender shall permit the borrower to redeem the titled personal property by tendering a money order or certified check for the principal amount of the title loan, interest accrued through the date of the lender taking possession, and any reasonable expenses incurred to date by the lender in taking possession of, preparing for sale, and selling the titled personal property. Nothing in this act nor in any title loan agreement shall preclude a borrower from purchasing the titled personal property at any sale.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Any such sale or disposal shall vest in the purchaser the right, title, and interest of the owner and the title loan lender.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Within thirty (30) days after the sale of the titled personal property, the borrower is entitled to receive all proceeds from the sale of the motor vehicle in excess of the principal amount due on the loan, interest on the loan up to the date of the lender taking possession, and the reasonable expenses incurred by the lender in taking possession of, preparing for sale, and selling the titled personal property. The borrower is entitled to reasonable attorneys' fees and costs incurred in any action brought to recover such proceeds that results in the title loan lender being ordered to return all or part of such amount.</section><section prefix='(g)'>The borrower shall not be personally liable to the lender for any balance due on the title loan remaining after applying the proceeds of the sale of the titled personal property to the principal amount due on the title loan, interest accrued through the date of the lender taking possession, and any reasonable expenses incurred by the lender in taking possession of, preparing for sale, and selling the titled personal property unless such balance exceeds two thousand dollars ($2,000.00). If such balance exceeds two thousand dollars ($2,000), the lender shall be entitled to reasonable attorneys' fees and costs incurred in any action brought to recover such balance that results in a judgment in favor of the lender.</section><section prefix='(h)'>The rights and remedies referred to in this section are cumulative. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the disposal of titled personal property is subject to the provisions of ch. 679, Florida Statutes.</section><section prefix='(i)'>In taking possession and disposing of titled personal property by sale or otherwise, the title loan lender shall at all times proceed in a commercially reasonable manner.</section><section prefix='(j)'>For purposes of this division, nonpublic sales or disposal of a motor vehicle between licensees and business affiliates or family members are sales and disposal that are presumed not to be commercially reasonable.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-62, ยง 1, 6-8-99)</history></law>