<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='4'>DIVISION 3. SALE OF COMMODITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-101</section_number>
<catch_line>Bread.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001670</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-101. Bread.<section>Each loaf of bread and each unit of a twin or multiple load of bread, made or procured for sale, kept, offered, exposed for sale, or sold, whether or not the bread is wrapped or sliced, shall weigh one-half (½) pound, three-quarter (¾) pound, one (1) pound, one and one-quarter (1¼) pounds, one and one-half (1½) pounds, or a multiple of one (1) pound, avoirdupois weight, within reasonable variation of tolerance that shall be promulgated by regulation by the Director; provided that the provisions of this section shall not apply to biscuits, buns, or rolls, weighing four (4) ounces or less, or to "stale bread" sold and expressly represented at the time of sale as such, or to specialty breads offered for retail sale under refrigeration, or to "fancy breads", such as fruit breads and such other breads as shall be defined as "fancy breads" in rules and regulations promulgated by the Director of the Consumer Protection Division in the manner provided by subsections(c), (d) and (e). The marking provisions of shall apply to wrapped and unwrapped, loaves of bread. If the bread is unwrapped, the information required by shall be stated on a label or by pan impression or other mechanical means. Each unwrapped loaf of bread, if labeled, shall have affixed thereon in a conspicuous place, a label of white paper at least one (1) inch square, or if round, at least one (1) inch in diameter, upon which shall be printed the required information in black or blue ink in type. If this information is given by pan impression or other mechanical means, the letters and figures showing the required information shall be plain and legible.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-52, § 29, 9-18-68; Ord. No. 69-24, § 1, 4-1-69; Ord. No. 75-8, § 1, 2-4-75; Ord. No. 91-143, § 1, 12-17-91)</history></law>