<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='4'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-124.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Acts prohibited.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001613</order_by>
<text><section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for a seller or distributor of mini bikes, being motor-driven cycles as defined in Section 30-1(22) [now 30-202(23)], Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, or go-carts, being motor vehicles as defined in Section 30-1(23) [now 30-202(21)], Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida, to display or advertise such products misleadingly as to create the impression that such vehicle may be operated at any place within Miami-Dade County, whether or not on private property, by a person who does not have a valid operator's license, or that the vehicle may be operated at any place within Miami-Dade County if the vehicle does not possess the required motor vehicle inspection certificate. All such advertisements or displays shall contain the following words: "It is unlawful to operate this vehicle at any place within Miami-Dade County, whether or not on private property, if the operator does not have a valid operator's license to operate a motor vehicle, as required by Section 30-13 [now 30-213(2)], Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida; if the vehicle does not possess the State inspection certificate, as required by Section 30-119 [now 30-390] of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida; and it is unlawful to operate this vehicle on any street in the County, if the vehicle is not licensed in accordance with State law; or if the operator is not wearing a safety helmet or shield as required by law."</section><section prefix='(b)'>It shall also be unlawful for any seller of a mini bike or go-cart as defined, or like vehicle, to sell such vehicle without having first obtained a signed statement from the purchaser which includes therein the words: "I have been informed that it is unlawful to operate this vehicle at any place within Miami-Dade County, whether or not on private property, if the operator does not have a valid operator's license to operate a motor vehicle, as required by Section 30-13 [now 30-213(2)], Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida; if the vehicle does not possess the State inspection certificate, as required by Section 30-119 [now 30-390] of the Code of Miami-Dade County, Florida; and it is unlawful to operate this vehicle on any street in the County, if the vehicle is not licensed in accordance with State law; or if the operator is not wearing a safety helmet or shield as required by law." This signed statement shall be obtained in duplicate, the seller giving one (1) copy to the purchaser, and retaining the signed original for a period of one (1) year from the date of sale, during which period it shall be made available for inspection on demand to any law enforcement officer of this State.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-39, ยง 1, 5-4-71)</history></law>