<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='4'>DIVISION 7. MOTOR VEHICLE TITLE LOANS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-124.17</section_number>
<catch_line>Licenses.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001604</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-124.17. Licenses.<section prefix='(a)'>No person may engage in business as a title loan lender or advertise to engage in business as a title loan lender unless the title loan lender has a valid license issued by the Department. A separate license shall be required for each physical location of title loan business. The Department shall issue more than one (1) license to an applicant if that applicant complies with the requirements of this section for each license.</section><section prefix='(b)'>An application for a license pursuant to this section must be submitted to the Department on such form as the Department may prescribe. If the Department determines that a license should be granted, it shall issue the license for a period not to exceed two (2) years. A non-refundable application and license fee shall accompany an initial application for each title loan application.</section><section prefix='(c)'>An application for license renewal pursuant to this section must be submitted to the Department on such form as the Department may prescribe. A title loan lender shall pay an annual license renewal fee. Renewal of registrations may be staggered over the annual period by the Director of the Department. A license that is not renewed at the end of each annual period shall automatically become inactive. An inactive license may be reactivated within ninety (90) days after the date it became inactive upon the submission of a completed reactivation form and payment of a reactivation fee. No inactive license may be reactivated after ninety (90) days.</section><section prefix='(d)'>All fees required pursuant to this section, including the initial application and license fee, license renewal fee, replacement fee and reactivation fee shall be established by administrative order approved by the Commission.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Each license must specify the location for which it is issued and shall be conspicuously displayed at that location. If the address of the principal place of business of the title loan lender is different from the location for which the license is issued, the license must state the address of the principal place of business of the title loan lender. When a title loan lender wishes to move a title loan office to another location the title loan lender shall give thirty (30) days prior written notice to the Department by certified or registered mail return receipt requested, and the Department shall then amend the license accordingly after payment of a replacement fee. A license issued pursuant to this section is not transferable or assignable.</section><section prefix='(f)'>A title loan lender licensed pursuant to this section shall designate and maintain an agent in this state for service of process.</section><section prefix='(g)'>A title loan lender licensed pursuant to this section shall apply to the Department for a new license upon a change in ownership of twenty-five (25) percent or more of the licensed title loan lender at any title loan location or office.</section><section prefix='(h)'>No license shall be issued or renewed unless the applicant has complied with the following:<section prefix='(1)'>Filed with the Department a bond in the amount of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000.00) for each license with a surety company qualified to do business in this state. The bond shall be to the Department and in favor of any consumer who is injured in the context of a title loan transaction by the fraud, misrepresentation, breach of contract, financial failure or other failure of the business, unfair or deceptive trade practice, disclosure violation, or violation of any provision of this division by the title loan lender. The performance bond shall be maintained in the full amount specified herein throughout the term of the license and for one (1) year after the license expires or is terminated, without reduction or allowances for any amounts which are withdrawn or paid pursuant to this division. An injured consumer may bring an action in a court of competent jurisdiction against the surety bond. The court shall award to a prevailing consumer reasonable attorneys' fees and costs, including appellate attorneys' fees and costs. The surety bond shall require that any surety company canceling a bond provided to a title loan lender pursuant to this section shall notify the Department of such cancellation in writing at least forty-five (45) days before cancellation.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Not have pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a felony within the last ten (10) years regardless of whether adjudication was withheld, or not be acting as an ultimate equitable owner for someone who has pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a felony within the preceding ten (10) years, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Not have pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a crime involving fraud, dishonest dealing, or any act of moral turpitude regardless of whether adjudication was withheld, or not be acting as an ultimate equitable owner for someone who has pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a crime involving fraud, dishonest dealing, or any act of moral turpitude, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld.</section><section prefix='(4)'>Not have pled nolo contendere to, or been convicted or found guilty of a crime directly related to the duties and responsibilities of a title loan lender within the preceding ten (10) years regardless of whether adjudication was withheld, or not be acting as an ultimate equitable owner for someone who has been convicted of a crime directly related to the duties and responsibilities of a title loan lender within the preceding ten (10) years, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld.</section><section prefix='(5)'>Filed with the Director a true, correct and complete application on the form prescribed by the Department.</section><section prefix='(6)'>Paid the initial, renewal or reactivation fee, as applicable.</section><section prefix='(7)'>Submitted to a background investigation resulting in a determination by the Director of the Department that:<section prefix='a.'>Each corporate or partnership applicant is qualified under the laws of Florida to do business under the trade name or names under which it has applied for a license.</section><section prefix='b.'>No fraud or willful or knowing misrepresentation or false statement was made in the application.</section><section prefix='c.'>No judgment against the applicant arising out of the activity of title loan lending practices, unless a stay or reversal of the judgment is procured through the courts.</section></section><section prefix='(8)'>Complied with the provisions of this division.</section></section><section prefix='(i)'>If an applicant for a title loan lending license is other than a corporation, the eligibility requirements of Subsections (h)(2), (3) and (4) apply to each direct or ultimate equitable owner.</section><section prefix='(j)'>If an applicant for a title loan lending license is a corporation, the eligibility requirements of Subsections (h)(2), (3) and (4) apply to each direct or ultimate equitable owner of at least twenty-five (25) percent of the outstanding equity interest of such corporation and to each director and executive officer.</section><section prefix='(k)'>The Department shall determine the form of the license and may perform criminal background checks as appropriate.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Licensees shall report changes in address, location of records, and any change of an executive officer within thirty (30) days of the change.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-62, ยง 1, 6-8-99)</history></law>