<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00017' order_by='00017' level='4'>DIVISION 7. MOTOR VEHICLE TITLE LOANS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-124.19</section_number>
<catch_line>Violations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001631</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-124.19. Violations.<section>The following acts shall constitute violations of this division and unfair and deceptive trade acts or practices:<section prefix='(a)'>Failing to comply with any provision of this division, any provision of resolutions adopted by the Commission pursuant to this division, or any written agreement entered into with the County.</section><section prefix='(b)'>Committing any act of fraud, misrepresentation, deceit, or gross negligence, regardless of reliance by or damage to a borrower, or any illegal activity in connection with a title loan transaction under this division.</section><section prefix='(c)'>Fraudulently misrepresenting, circumventing or concealing any matter required to be stated or furnished to a borrower pursuant to this division.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Imposition of illegal charges in any title loan transaction.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Engaging in false, deceptive, or misleading advertising.</section><section prefix='(f)'>Failing to maintain, preserve and keep available for examination, all books, accounts, or other documents required by this division, resolution of the Commission, state or federal law, or any agreement entered into with the Department.</section><section prefix='(g)'>Aiding, abetting, or conspiring with another person to circumvent or violate any of the requirements of this division, or the requirements of any state or federal law regulating title loan lenders.</section><section prefix='(h)'>Refusing to permit inspection of books or records in an investigation or examination by the Department or failure or refusal to comply with a subpoena or order issued by the Department.</section><section prefix='(i)'>Engaging in criminal conduct in the course of business as a title loan lender.</section><section prefix='(j)'>Knowingly entering into a title loan agreement with a person under the age of eighteen (18) years.</section><section prefix='(k)'>Making any agreement that requires or allows for the personal liability of the borrower or the waiver of any of the provisions of this division.</section><section prefix='(l)'>Knowingly entering into a title loan agreement with any person who is under the influence of drugs or alcohol when such condition is visible or apparent, or with any person using a name other than his or her own name or the registered name or his or her business.</section><section prefix='(m)'>Entering into a title loan agreement in which the amount of money advanced in consideration for the loan secured by any single certificate of title exceeds one-third () of the value of the motor vehicle. The value of the motor vehicle shall be determined by reference to the loan value in the current Southeastern Edition of the National Automobile Dealer's Association Official Used Car Guide. The value may vary based upon documented unique characteristics of the motor vehicle.</section><section prefix='(n)'>Failing to exercise reasonable care in the safekeeping of a certificate of title or motor vehicle repossessed pursuant to this division.</section><section prefix='(o)'>Failing to return a certificate of title or repossessed motor vehicle to a borrower, with any and all of the title lender's liens on the property properly released, within thirty (30) days of the payment of the full amount due, unless the property has been seized or impounded by an authorized law enforcement agency, taken into custody by a court, or otherwise disposed of by court order.</section><section prefix='(p)'>Charging or receiving any finance charge, interest, cost, or fee which is not permitted by this division.</section><section prefix='(q)'>Engaging in business as a title loan lender without a current, active license issued by the Department pursuant to this division.</section><section prefix='(r)'>Refusing to accept partial repayment of the amount financed when all accrued finance charges have been paid.</section><section prefix='(s)'>Charging a prepayment penalty.</section><section prefix='(t)'>Capitalizing any unpaid finance charge as part of the amount financed in the renewal of a title loan agreement.</section><section prefix='(u)'>Failing to account for and remit to the borrower all surplus proceeds from the disposal of the borrower's motor vehicle, within thirty (30) days of disposal.</section><section prefix='(v)'>Advertising in any publication which is primarily circulated, displayed, distributed or marketed within Miami-Dade County, Florida, which advertisement identifies a motor vehicle title loan lender offering loans regulated by this article, unless the advertisement includes the license number issued by the Department and the name under which the business is licensed. For the purposes of this subsection, any advertisement shall be defined to include any announcement, listing, display, entry or other written or oral statement of whatever nature or kind, and specifically to include a name and address or telephone number placed under a heading, where the heading describes or encompasses any kind of repair work regulated under this article without a current valid license required by the Department.</section></section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 99-62, ยง 1, 6-8-99)</history></law>