<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00011' order_by='00011' level='4'>DIVISION 1. IN GENERAL</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-76.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Shopping carts.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001590</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-76.1. Shopping carts.<section prefix='(a)'>Procedure for handling identifiable shopping carts found on public property.<section prefix='(1)'>Employees and officers of Miami-Dade County shall be deemed agents of Miami-Dade County and any identifiable shopping carts found by them on public property during the course of their official duties shall be reported to the Department of Solid Waste Management. The Department shall collect the shopping carts and place them in storage.</section><section prefix='(2)'>The Director of the Department of Solid Waste Management or his designee shall provide reasonable notice to the owner of the shopping cart as designated on the shopping cart's identification sign to retrieve the property.</section><section prefix='(3)'>The owner of the shopping cart shall have ten (10) days from receipt of the notice to retrieve the property.</section><section prefix='(4)'>If the shopping cart is not claimed by the owner within the time specified in this section or if the Department cannot contact the owner for failure to provide the identification information required under Section 8A-76 (a) of this Code, the title to such property shall vest in Miami-Dade County and shall be disposed of by the Department.</section></section><section prefix='(b)'>Procedure for handling unidentifiable shopping carts found on public property. All unidentifiable shopping carts found on public property shall be handled in accordance with F.S. ch. 705, as amended from time to time.</section><section prefix='(c)'>The Department of Solid Waste Management is delegated the authority to enforce this section.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 97-213, ยง 1, 12-2-97; Ord. No. 05-20, ยง 2, 1-27-05)</history></law>