<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00012' order_by='00012' level='4'>DIVISION 2. DIRECTOR AND INSPECTORS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-82.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Same—Acceptance of assurances of compliance.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001540</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-82.1. Same—Acceptance of assurances of compliance.<section>The Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division may terminate an investigation or an action commenced under any provision of this chapter upon acceptance by the Director of a verified, written assurance, executed by the person or persons who are the subject of the investigation or action, of voluntary compliance with the provisions of this chapter. Acceptance of an assurance by the Director may be conditioned, in the discretion of the Director, upon a verified, written commitment by said person or persons to reimburse consumers, to take other corrective action deemed appropriate by the Director, and to reimburse Miami-Dade County for the costs of investigation, enforcement and litigation. An executed assurance shall not be evidence of a prior violation of this chapter. No such assurance shall act as a limitation upon any action or investigation by the Director of the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division in the enforcement of this chapter, nor shall such assurance act as a limitation upon any action or remedy available to a person aggrieved by a violation of the provisions of this chapter. Each violation of any of the terms and conditions of a verified, written assurance by the person or persons who executed the assurance shall constitute a separate offense under this chapter.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 83-35, § 1, 6-7-83)</history></law>