<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='2'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='3'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00006' order_by='00006' level='4'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-81</section_number>
<catch_line>General powers and duties of Director.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001563</order_by>
<text><section>The Director shall have the custody of the County standards of weight and measure and of the other standards and equipment provided for by this article, and shall keep accurate records of the same. The Director shall enforce the provisions of this article. The specifications, tolerances, and other technical requirements for commercial weighing and measuring devices, together with amendments thereto, as recommended by the National Bureau of Standards and published in National Bureau of Standards Handbook 44 and supplements thereto or any publication revising or superseding Handbook 44 not in conflict with state regulations, shall be the specifications, tolerances, and other technical requirements for commercial weighing and measuring devices in this County, and are hereby adopted by reference as part of this article in the same manner and to the same effect as if said specifications, tolerances and other technical requirements were set out in full herein. For the purposes of this article, apparatus shall be deemed to be "correct" when it conforms to all applicable requirements promulgated as specified in this section; other apparatus shall be deemed to be "incorrect." He shall have and keep a general supervision over weights and measures offered for sale, sold, or in use in the County. He shall annually make to the County Manager a report of all the activities of his office.</section></text><history>(Ord. No. 68-52, ยง 6, 9-19-68)</history></law>