<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 4' order_by='00005' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='4'>DIVISION 3. SALE OF COMMODITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-98.1</section_number>
<catch_line>Perishable food packaged for sale to be labeled with terminal shelf life date; definitions; promulgation of rules and regulations.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001556</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-98.1. Perishable food packaged for sale to be labeled with terminal shelf life date; definitions; promulgation of rules and regulations.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any perishable food, as defined below, to be packaged for sale, unless the packager thereof causes to be stamped, printed or otherwise conspicuously marked on its container or any label affixed thereto a clearly specified, uncoded, calendar date which shall be the terminal shelf life date of the food.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The following definitions shall apply whenever the term is used in this section:<section prefix='(1)'>Calendar date shall mean the month and day of the month.</section><section prefix='(2)'>Marked shall mean stamped, printed or otherwise conspicuously marked on its container or any label affixed thereto.</section><section prefix='(3)'>Perishable food shall mean fresh packaged perishable meat, poultry, fish, and dairy products, excluding canned, frozen or vacuum packaged products.</section></section><section prefix='(c)'>The Director of the Consumer Protection Division, in consultation with the Miami-Dade County Health Department and the effected industry, shall have the authority to promulgate rules and regulations not inconsistent with the ordinance for the determination of the terminal shelf life date for individual food products, which rules and regulations, when approved by the County Commission is provided in subsection (e) below, shall have the force and effect of law in the County.</section><section prefix='(d)'>Notice of such rules and regulations and all proposed changes thereto shall be published once in a newspaper of general circulation in Miami-Dade County at least thirty (30) days before the County Commission meeting at which they are to be considered. Said notice shall be sufficient if made in substantially the following form:<section>"Notice is hereby given that the Director of the Consumer Protection Division proposes rules and regulations relating to the shelf life dating of perishable foods, pursuant to Ordinance No. 71-80. In general, the proposed rules and regulations provide … [the dots represent a general description of the proposed rules and regulations]. A complete copy of the proposed rules and regulations is available upon request from the Miami-Dade County Consumer Protection Division. A public hearing will be held to consider any rules and regulations."</section></section><section>In addition, the notice shall state the address and telephone number of the Consumer Protection Division.</section><section prefix='(e)'>Rules and regulations shall be considered by the County Commission at public hearing.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-80, §§ 1—3, 10-5-71; Ord. No. 72-7, § 1, 2-1-72)</history></law>