<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<law>
<structure>
<unit label='part' identifier='PART 3' order_by='00004' level='1'>PART III CODE OF ORDINANCES</unit>
<unit label='chapter' identifier='00009' order_by='00009' level='2'>Chapter 8A BUSINESS REGULATIONS</unit>
<unit label='article' identifier='00004' order_by='00004' level='3'>ARTICLE III. UNIFORM TRADE STANDARDS</unit>
<unit label='division' identifier='00013' order_by='00013' level='4'>DIVISION 3. SALE OF COMMODITIES</unit>
</structure>
<section_number>8A-98.2</section_number>
<catch_line>Sale of certain meats, poultry, fish or seafood prohibited unless packaged in transparent containers.</catch_line>
<order_by>0000001582</order_by>
<text><section>Sec. 8A-98.2. Sale of certain meats, poultry, fish or seafood prohibited unless packaged in transparent containers.<section prefix='(a)'>It shall be unlawful for any owner, manager, or supervisor of a retail store or any independently operated department thereof to sell or offer or expose for sale, at retail, any prepackaged, unprocessed and untreated fresh meat (exclusive of viscera), poultry, (except poultry or poultry products subject to and not exempted from the application of 21 U.S.C.A. § 451-70, as amended), fish or seafood, unless the package is colorless and transparent on all sides, exclusive of labeling, or unless at least seventy (70) percent of the bottom of said packaging shall be transparent, such transparency to be uniformly distributed to expose the bottom of the meat, poultry, fish or seafood while the top shall be completely visible, exclusive of labeling, which labeling shall not occupy more than ten (10) percent of one (1) side or sides or five (5) square inches, whichever is greater, of the packages whereon such labeling is affixed.</section><section prefix='(b)'>The portion or segment of a product visible in a sealed package or container shall, at the time of packaging, accurately reflect a reasonably true representation of the quality, size and freshness of the total contents.</section></section></text><history>(Ord. No. 71-95, §§ 1, 2, 12-1-71; Ord. No. 72-38, § 1, 7-5-72; Ord. No. 73-89, § 1, 10-16-73)</history></law>